<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic6108">

    <title>Known Problems and Limitations</title>
    <shortdesc>You may encounter some known limitations when working in the KVM region of this release.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
            <othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Administrator"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Architect"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Michael B"/>
            <othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <body><section>CG-1307; ;CG-1305; CG-1292</section>
        
        <section><title>StoreVirtual Cluster VIP not available on storage network. </title>
            <p>If  you cannot ping a specific virtual IP address on the network, locate the host
                with the associated IP and reboot that server.</p>
                
                <p><!--  CG-1306 -->
            </p>
            
            
        </section>
        <section><title>VXLAN not certified</title> <p>The VXLAN feature has not been certified for HP
            Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade.</p> </section>
                
            
        <section>
            <title>Cinder Block Storage snapshot feature not working </title>
            <!-- CG-1043 -->
            <p>For HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade cloud using 3PAR iSCSI configured as the Cinder
                block storage service. The Cinder volume snapshot feature might not function
                properly if following entries are enabled in the
                    <codeph>/etc/cinder/cinder.conf</codeph> file. </p>
            <codeblock>hp3par_snapshot_retention=48
hp3par_snapshot_expiration=72</codeblock>
            <p> To correct this issue, edit the <codeph>/etc/cinder/cinder.conf</codeph> file to
                disable these entries by commenting-out the entries, as follows:</p>
            <codeblock>#hp3par_snapshot_retention=48
#hp3par_snapshot_expiration=72           </codeblock>
            <p>The <codeph>hp3par_snapshot_retention</codeph> entry is the time in hours to retain a
                snapshot.</p>
            <p>The <codeph>hp3par_snapshot_expiration</codeph> entry is the time in hours when a
                snapshot expires and is deleted. </p>
        </section>
        <section> LDAP conflict causing error with templates <p>When deploying templates, such as
                    <codeph>VMAutoScaling.yaml</codeph> you might receive a n error similar to the
                following: <codeblock>Error: Can’t find role heat_stack_user </codeblock></p><p>The
                problem is due to an inconsistency in the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade LDAP
                implementation. To fix this problem, you should disable LDAP in Keystone and create
                few roles as mentioned below. </p><p>How you fix the problem depends upon whether
                your he HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade cloud is currently deployd.</p>
            <b>Cloud is not deployed</b>
            <ol>
                <li>If the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade cloud is not deployed, before deploying
                    edit the <codeph>definition.json</codeph> file to set
                        <codeph>ldap_enabled</codeph> to 0.
                        <codeblock>"ldap_enabled": 0,</codeblock><p>This setting causes the cloud to
                        deploy with SQL as Keystone backend instead of LDAP.</p></li>
                <li>After you deploy the cloud, create the following roles in the Keystone by
                    logging on to one of the controller nodes: <ol>
                        <li>Source the stackrc file: <codeblock>source stackrc</codeblock></li>
                        <li>Execute the following command to create the heat_stack_owner role:
                            <codeblock>keystone role-create --name heat_stack_owner </codeblock></li>
                        <li>Execute the following command to create the heat_stack_owner role:
                            <codeblock>keystone role-create --name heat_stack_user</codeblock></li>
                    </ol></li>
            </ol>
            <b>Cloud is currently deployed</b>
            <ol>
                <li>After the cloud is deployed, on each controller, modify the
                        <codeph>/etc/keystone/keystone.conf</codeph> to comment-out the LDAP entry
                    and uncomment SQL driver, as shown:
                    <codeblock>    [identity]
    driver = keystone.identity.backends.sql.Identity
    #driver = keystone.identity.backends.ldap.Identity</codeblock></li>
                <li>Create the following roles in the Keystone by logging on to one of the
                    controller nodes: <ol>
                        <li>Source the stackrc file: <codeblock>source stackrc</codeblock></li>
                        <li>Execute the following command to create the heat_stack_owner role:
                            <codeblock>keystone role-create --name heat_stack_owner </codeblock></li>
                        <li>Execute the following command to create the heat_stack_owner role:
                            <codeblock>keystone role-create --name heat_stack_user </codeblock></li>
                    </ol></li>
            </ol></section>
        <section><title>Floating IP not working when SNAT is enabled</title>
            <!-- CG-1012 -->
            <p>When router is configured either centralized (server default) or distributed , it is seen that Floating IP is not working.</p>
            <p>To fix this issue, log onto <codeph>controller-0</codeph> for the KVM region and execute the following
                command to disable SNAT on the router:
                <codeblock>neutron router-update &lt;router-name> --external_gateway_info type=dict network_id=&lt;network-id>,enable_snat=False</codeblock></p>        
        </section>

        <section><title>Unable to create new users through the Horizon UI</title>
            <!-- CG-1042 -->
            <p>After logging into the Horizon interface as an <codeph>admin</codeph> user, an error occurs when you
                click <b>Create User</b> under the <b>Idenity</b> section.</p> 
            
            <p>You can create users with the OpenStack Keystone CLI commands. For axample:</p>
            <codeblock>keystone user-create --name &lt;user-name> [--tenant &lt;tenant>][--pass [&lt;pass>]] [--email &lt;email>][--enabled &lt;true|false>]</codeblock>
            
            <p>For more information, see <xref
                    href="http://docs.openstack.org/cli-reference/content/keystoneclient_commands.html"
                    format="html" scope="external">OpenStack Command-Line Interface Reference</xref>.</p>
        </section>

        <section><title>Unable to create new project through the Horizon Identity UI</title>
            <!-- CG-1041 -->
            <p>After logging into the Horizon interface as an <codeph>admin</codeph> user, an error occurs when you
                click <b>Create Project</b> under the <b>Idenity</b> section.</p> 
            
            <p>You can create projects with the OpenStack Keystone CLI commands. For axample:</p>
            <codeblock>keystone tenant-create --name &lt;tenant-name>
                [--description &lt;tenant-description>]
                [--enabled &lt;true|false>]</codeblock>
            
            <p>For more information, see <xref
                href="http://docs.openstack.org/cli-reference/content/keystoneclient_commands.html"
                format="html" scope="external">OpenStack Command-Line Interface Reference</xref>.</p>
            
        </section>
        

        <section><title>Cinder Volume Backup is not working upon cloud deployment</title>
            <!-- CG-410 -->
            <p>Cinder Volume Backup is not working upon installation of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade 1.1 
                The  <codeph>cinder.backup.driver</codeph> file is not present in /etc/cinder/cinder.conf.</p>
       </section>
        
        <section><title>Bonding on the control interface is not supported</title>
            <!-- CG-1052 -->
            <p>Due to an issue in <codeph>config_region</codeph> script, bonding on the control interface (hosts PXE, CLM, BLS, CAN networks) is not supported. 
                A patch to support this feature is actively being worked upon. </p>
                <p>Because of this issue, the data interface on the compute node does support balanced-xor bonding mode and Active/Standby modes. </p>     
        </section>
        <section><title>LAG for the KVM region control plane does not work</title>
    
            <p>Link aggregation groups (LAG) are not supported in the the KVM region control plane. This is a known limitation that is scheduled to 
                be corrected with the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade GA release. A LAG is a mechanism that allows multiple parallel Ethernet network connections between two hosts to be used as a
                single logical connection.</p>
    
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>SR-IOV limitations</title>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>SR-IOV is supported only for Intel 82599.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>The maximum number of VFs per NIC is 32.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>SR-IOV and PCI passthrough cannot both be used on the same provider
                        network.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Interface or interface consolidation limitations</title>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>VLAN over bonded interface without an assigned network type
                        is not supported.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Addition of an infrastructure interface after installation is not
                        functional.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Consolidation of the infrastructure network over the OAM
                        network is not supported.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Stacked VLANs are not supported. On a consolidated management
                        or infrastructure interface, a VLAN provider network can be associated
                        directly with the untagged interface; however, flat or VXLAN provider
                        networks must be associated with a consolidated VLAN data interface.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Interface profiles cannot be created for <!--AE and -->VLAN
                        interface types. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>The <cmdname>system
                            host-if-modify-ports</cmdname> command is deprecated.<!--  --></p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Mellanox limitations</title>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>For a Mellanox CX3, all ports must be used ether for data
                        interfaces, or for non-data interfaces. It is not possible to use some ports
                        for data interfaces and others for non-data interfaces on the same Mellanox
                        CX3 NIC.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Jumbo frames are not supported on Mellanox NICs.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Installation does not fully utilize disks greater than two terabytes</title>
            <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade in the KVM region can be installed on disks greater than 2 TB, but only 2 TB of the
                disk is useable.</p>
        </section>
        <!-- Remove per Hrushi email 7-2
        <section>
            <title>Cannot create Cinder LVM volumes using disks greater than two
                terabytes</title>
            <p>Using a disk greater than 2 TB for Cinder LVM results in a
                    <filepath>config_controller</filepath> failure.</p>
        </section>  -->
        <section>
            <title>Guest heartbeat and notification features are not fully
                validated.</title>
            <p>Heartbeat and notification services for VMs are not fully validated. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Cinder API version generates a log warning</title>
            <p>The V1 API for Cinder in use by this version of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is deprecated,
                resulting in log warnings.</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>
