<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic6108">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <shortdesc>Wind River HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is a high-performance, high-availability,
        cloud operating system that enables telecommunications operators to use
        Commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) hardware to manage Virtualized Network Functions (VNF)
        within a carrier grade Network Function Virtualization (NFV) architecture.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author>Jim Owens</author>
        <author>Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade brings together the flexibility and scalability of the IT
            cloud, and the high-availability and performance demanded by the Telecommunications
            industry, into a unique carrier grade, industry-leading solution to deliver a
            price-performance ratio well above alternative solutions. HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is aligned
            with the ETSI-NFV architecture</p>
        <p>For more information on using HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide</cite> and the <cite ixia_locid="9">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Administration Guide</cite>. For information on using
            the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Developer API, including API definitions and usage descriptions, see
            the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade SDK</cite> in the file <filepath>Titanium-Server-SDK.tgz</filepath>.</p>
        <section>
            <title>Supported Hardware Platforms</title>
            <p>Wind River has partnered with leading hardware vendors to certify
                HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade running on several of their products. The following is the list of
                certified platforms:</p>
            <table frame="all" id="table_kp4_l3b_ln">
                <title>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Certified Hardware Platforms</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <p>Manufacturer</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p>Platform</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="3">
                                <p>Hewlett-Packard</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p>HP360 Proliant DL360P Gen8 Server</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <p>HP360 Proliant DL360P Gen9 Server</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <p>HP380 Proliant DL380P Gen8 Server</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <p>HP380 Proliant DL380P Gen9 Server</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <p>The following NICs have been verified for PXE booting:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>Broadcom 1G</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Broadcom 10G</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Emulex 10G</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Intel 82599</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Intel i350</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Supported Hardware Configuration</title>
            <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade has been verified to work using the following
                hardware configuration:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>The required number of controller nodes is two.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>The required number of storage nodes is two. Storage nodes
                        are optional, depending on storage needs.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>The verified number of compute nodes is 20.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>For predictable performance, it is recommended to disable hyper-threading in
                        the BIOS of all nodes in the cluster.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Supported System Configuration</title>
            <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade has been verified to work using the following system
                configuration:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>two controllers</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>two storage nodes</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>20 compute nodes with dual Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-2670 v2
                        and E5-2640v3</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>200 virtual machine instances</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>up to four physical ports per compute node</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>maximum eight AVP vNICs per guest</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>maximum eight SR-IOV vNICs per guest</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>maximum 32 VFs per NIC</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Supported Guest OSs</title>
            <p>The following Guest OSs are supported by HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>Wind River Linux 6.0</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Wind River Linux 5.0</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>CentOS 6.4</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Fedora 19</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>RHEL 6.5</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>OpenSUSE 12.3</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>Requirements for specific guest OSs are included in the SDK README files.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Performance Considerations</title>
            <p>The nature of the guest applications, their processing and storage
                demands, and other configuration factors can affect the overall performance of the
                HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade cluster.</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>