<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic6108">

    <title>Usage Caveats</title>
    <shortdesc>There are some usage issues you should be aware of when working with this
  release.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author>Jim Owens</author>
        <author>Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <section>
            <title>VMs reported as ACTIVE before compute nodes are recovered</title>
            <p>During a system recovery (for example, after a site power outage),
                when the controller is available but before the compute nodes are available, the
                Nova service shows an <b>Active</b> status for VMs . Until the
                compute nodes are available, this should be an <b>Error</b>
                status.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Controller swact raises spurious ssh security warning</title>
            <p>On ssh login to the active controller after a controller swact, a
                security warning appears, saying the host identification has changed. This occurs
                because the ssh keys are not currently synchronized across controllers. It can be
                disregarded. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Mismatch of interface settings in LAG group</title>
            <p>If the interfaces in a LAG group have mismatched speed or duplex settings, they are
                marked as incompatible by the system. To prevent this, ensure both interfaces in a
                LAG group use the same speed and duplex settings.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Storage or compute node must be re-added after MAC address change
                on management interface</title>
            <p>For a compute or storage node, any change to the management interface configuration
                that results in a change of MAC address requires the node to be re-installed. The
                management interface MAC address can change if the physical Ethernet port is changed
                (for example, from eth1 to eth2), or if a LAG configuration is changed in a way that
                removes the Ethernet port associated with the LAG MAC address (for example, if the
                interface originally used for PXE boot is removed or replaced).</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Instance cannot be launched with a specified port ID</title>
            <p>Use of the --port-id parameter when launching an instance results in
                command failure.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Live migration resets uptime</title>
            <p>When a VM is live-migrated, the uptime reported for the VM is reset
                to 0.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Interface network type cannot be changed directly from SRIOV to
                data</title>
            <p>For an interface using network type "SRIOV," the network type must be
                changed to "none" before it can be changed to "data."</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Glance image deletion does not release storage space</title>
            <p>The storage space used by a glance image is not released when the
                image is deleted. To free the space for other uses, a glance-api restart is
                required.</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>