<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic6108">
    <title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Carrier Grade 2.0 Alpha: Release Notes</title>
    <shortdesc>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is a high-performance, high-availability, cloud
        operating system that enables telecommunications operators to use Commercial-off-the-shelf
        (COTS) hardware to manage Virtualized Network Functions (VNF) within a carrier grade Network
        Function Virtualization (NFV) architecture.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
            <othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Administrator"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Architect"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Michael B"/>
            <othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade brings together the flexibility and scalability of the
            IT cloud, and the high-availability and performance demanded by the Telecommunications
            industry, into a unique carrier grade, industry-leading solution to deliver a
            price-performance ratio well above alternative solutions. HP Helion OpenStack Carrier
            Grade is aligned with the ETSI-NFV architecture</p>
        <p>For more information on using HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, see the <cite>HP Helion
                OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide</cite> and the <cite>HP Helion
                OpenStack Carrier Grade Administration Guide</cite>. For information on using the HP
            Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Developer API, including API definitions and usage
            descriptions, see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade SDK</cite>.</p>
        <p>See also: <ul>
                <li><xref href="jow1404333830815.xml#topic6108"/></li>
                <li><xref href="jow1404333831397.xml#topic6108"/></li>
                <li><xref href="jow1404333831977.xml#topic6108"/></li>
                <li><xref href="jow1430312565268.xml#topic6108"/></li>
            </ul></p>
    </body>
</topic>
