<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic1564">
  <title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> 2.0: Horizon Service Overview</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
      <othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
      <othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Systems Administrator"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Cloud Architect"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Administrator"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Network Administrator"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Service Developer"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Cloud Administrator"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Network Engineer"/>
      <othermeta name="role" content="Michael B, Nancy M"/>
      <othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
      <othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p>
      <!--PUBLISHED-->
      <!--./commercial/GA1/1.1commerical.services-horizon-overview.md-->
      <!--permalink: /helion/openstack/1.1/services/horizon/overview/--></p>
    <p> </p>
    <p>Horizon is the OpenStack service that serves as the basis for the HP Helion OpenStack
      dashboards.</p>
    <p>The dashboards provide a web-based user interface to HP Helion OpenStack services including
      Compute, Volume Operations, Networking, and Identity.</p>
    <section>
      <p/>
      <p>Using Horizon you can create Project, Admin, and Settings. Tabs on the left side of the
        interface expand and contract to show available tasks grouped into <b>panels</b>.</p>
      <p>Across the top are menus to switch between projects and menus where you can access user
        settings.</p>
      <p> To access the dashboard, enter the dashboard URL in a supported browser and log in.</p>
      <p/>
    </section>
    <section conref="../postinstall_checklist.dita#postinstall_checklist/horizon"/>
    <section>
      <p>At the bottom of this page, you can see some of the services you can manage right from the
        dashboard.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="DashProject">
      <title>Project dashboard</title>
      <p>Use the <b>Project</b> dashboard to implement and build out your cloud. This dashboard
        contains tools to create virtual server instances, create and configure your network,
        configure access tools (such as key pairs and security groups) and cloud resource templates
        (stacks).</p>
    </section>
    <section id="DashAdmin">
      <title>Admin dashboard</title>
      <p>Use the <b>Admin</b> dashboard to view, allocate, and manage all resources within the
        cloud.</p>
      <p>The Admin dashboard allows you to manage instances, define flavors, create and configure
        images, manage networks, view system resources, manage projects, and manage users.</p>
    </section>

    <section id="DashSettings">
      <title>Settings dashboard</title>
      <p>Use the <b>Settings</b> dashboard to change your display language and settings, your time
        zone, and your password.</p>
      <p>Click <b>Settings</b> in the user menu to display the Settings dashboard.</p>
      <p>For a look at the dashboard options, see <xref
          href="../../commercial/GA1/1.1commerical.services-horizon-overview.dita">Horizon
          Overview</xref>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section><ol>
        <li>
          <p>Open a web browser that has both JavaScript and cookies enabled.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>In the address bar, enter the host name or IP address for the dashboard.</p>
          <note> If a certificate warning appears when you try to access the URL for the first time,
            a self-signed certificate is in use. These certificates are not considered trustworthy
            by default. Verify the certificate or add an exception in the browser to bypass the
            warning.</note>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>On the <b>Log In</b> page, enter your user name and password and then click <b>Sign
              In</b>.</p>
          <p>
            <image href="../../media/horizon/HelionLogin.png">
              <alt/>
            </image>
          </p>
        </li>
      <li><p>The UserID with the "admin" role is provided with a special tab called Admin. The menu options
            underneath this tab are similar to the non-admin user views but cover all projects as
            well as some additional panels not available to general users. </p>
        <p>The Overview page provides a summary by project of the current 
        utilization of major OpenStack resources.  The information on this 
        screen is drawn directly from the Compute or Nova service API and provides 
        the ability to filter the query by date range and an option to download results 
        into a CSV file that is compatible with Microsoft Excel or can be imported 
        into a database.</p>
      </li>
        <li>
          <p>If you are a non-admin user, you will only be able to select a project from the list at
            the top of the screen.</p></li>
      </ol></section>

    <section id="horizon-dashboard-examples"><title>Horizon Dashboard Examples</title>
      <p>The following screen shots illustrate some of the services you can manage in the Horizon
        dashboard. There is both an overcloud Horizon dashboard and an undercloud dashboard, both of
        which are accessible via your URL in a browser.
        <!--Removed anchor point images--><!-- id="images" --></p>
      <p><b>Viewing System Info</b></p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/sysinfo.png" id="image_avw_nb3_ps"/></p>
      <p>The System Info panel provides a list of all currently installed OpenStack services and
        their operation status.</p><p/><p>Additional panels on the System Info display sub service
        status for services like Compute, Block Storage, and Network services. This is a view of the
        Compute Services tab. There  is  also a Block Storages Services tab and a tab for Network
        Agents.</p><p><b>Managing Quotas </b></p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/quotas2.png" id="image_lnv_rb3_ps"/></p>
      <p><b>Managing Routers </b></p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/routers.png" id="image_kl5_5b3_ps"/></p>
      <p><b>Managing Availability Zones</b>
      </p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/AZ.png" id="image_slz_wb3_ps"/></p>
      <p><b>Getting Hypervisor Status</b></p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/hypervisors.png" id="image_jt2_zb3_ps"/></p>
      <p>The first tab option on the Hypervisors panel provides a view of the different hypervisors
        currently running, which physical server each hypervisor instance is running on, the type of
        hypervisor, and the infrastructure resources consumed by the hypervisor. </p><p>The Compute
        Host tab lists all of the currently configured physical hosts, which Availability Zone each
        host is configured for, the status, and total consumed resources.</p>
      <p>The Compute Host tab lists all of the currently configured physical hosts, which
        Availability Zone each host is configured for, the status, and total consumed resources.</p><p><b>Creating a DNS
          Record </b> </p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/create_a_record.png" id="image_zfd_cc3_ps"/></p>
      <p><b>Managing Services </b>  </p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/services.png" id="image_d5m_2c3_ps"/></p>
      <p><b>Viewing Stacks </b>
      </p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/stacks.png" id="image_lgf_gc3_ps"/></p>
      <p><b>Creating a Domain</b>    </p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/create_domain.png" id="image_pdf_3c3_ps"/></p>
      <p><b>Viewing Network Topology</b></p>
      <p><image href="../../media/horizon/HelionDashboardMenusnew1.png" id="image_xdh_gf3_ps"/></p>
      </section><section>
        <ul>
          <li>The Updates and Extensions panel provides a list of available files that can be downloaded and installed.  This view is also only available to UserIDs with the “admin” role.
          </li>
           <li> Host aggregates are a grouping of physical servers or hosts with associated
          metadata. A host can belong to multiple aggregates. </li>
        <li>Common use cases for host aggregates include supporting the scheduling of instances to a
          subset of hosts that have a specific capability or flavor such as a specific type of
          storage, lots of RAM, and/or large numbers of processors. Another use case of host
          aggregates is to support the arrangement of hosts into logical groups for load balancing
          and instance distribution. Host aggregates are configured and only viewable by system
          admins. The end user view of a host aggregate is called an Availability Zone. Availability
          zones are created via the Nova API and the host aggregates function. End users can use
          availability zones for similar use cases. For example, an application could be deployed on
          hosts in multiple availability zones. A load balancer can then be configured and the
          instances running each deployment of the application in each availability zone can be
          assigned to the load balancer thus providing a measure of failover and high availability
          support. Additional information on host aggregates and availability zones is available at
          http://blog.russellbryant.net/2013/05/21/availability-zones-and-host-aggregates-in-openstack-compute-nova/
          and http://docs.openstack.org/openstack-ops/content/scaling.html. </li>   
          
          
        </ul>
      </section>
        
     
        
      
     <!-- <xref href="#topic1564"> Return to Top </xref>-->
 
  </body>
</topic>
