<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="install_gui">
  <title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> 2.0: Installing via the GUI </title>
  <body><!--Needs Edit-->
    <section> HP Helion OpenStack 2.0 comes with a UI, the Dayzero Installer, for installing your
      cloud. Rather than searching through and editing a number of YAML files to input your specific
      configuration data, finding the correct location, and maintaing the format of the files, the
      UI presents fields in which you may enter your information. </section>
    <section>In addition, rather than having to run a series of commands to execute the cobbler and
      ansible scripts that initiate the installation of HP Helion OpenStack, the UI application runs
      them behind the scenes. </section>
    <section>While the UI app does more than simply popoulate the configuration files that the
      configuration processor uses as input to its processses, it does populate them. Therefore you
      can inspect the files whenever you like, or before reconfiguing your cloud. </section>
    <section>Note, however, that if you decide to look at or try to modify configuration files
      during the process, none of your values are actually written to the configuration files until
      you cick the Deploy button at the end of the process. That would mean too that if you were to
      try to change anything in the files themselves mid process, the values would get overwritten
      by values you have entered in the GUI before cicking the Deploy button.</section>


    <section>These YAML configuration files are now stored in a local git repository as well, as
      explained in <xref href="installation/using_git.dita">Using git for Configuration
        Manangement</xref>. </section>
    <section><title>Before you begin</title> Before you run the GUI installer to install your cloud,
      there are a number of things you need to do to prepare. <ol>
        <li>Prepare your servers</li>
        <li>Gather your information <ul>
            <li>Server names </li>
            <li>IP addresses </li>
            <li>Server Roles </li>
            <li>PXE MAC addresses </li>
            <li>PXE IP addresses </li>
            <li>PXE interfaces </li>
            <li>IPMI/iLO IP address, username, password </li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>Choose your <xref href="example_configs.dita">cloud model/example</xref> template. Note
          that the only option for the Cloud model on KVM with VSA is to have 0 or 3 VSA nodes;
          there is no option to have 0 VSA nodes. Note also that you cannot put the deployer on a
          dedicated node using the GUI installer--only in the control plane.</li>
        <li>Before you use the GUI to install your cloud, you may install the operating system, HP
          Linux for HP Helion OpenStack, on your nodes (servers) based on your hypervisor, if you
          prefer. Otherwise the installer will install it for you. Te option is available in the
          GUI. If you deci You must do so by following the appropriate installation instructions. <ul>
            <li><xref href="gui_install_on_kvm.dita">KVM</xref></li>
            <li><xref href="gui_install_on_esx.dita">ESX</xref></li>
          </ul>
          <p id="chooseHypervisor"/><note>Before starting the GUI, you will also need to change the
            file permissions of hlm-ux-implementation/server/ansible/hosts/localhost to not
            executable. Execute the following command to do so:
            <codeblock>chmod -x ~/hlm-ux-implementation/server/ansible/hosts/localhost </codeblock>This
            will set the correct permission on the localhost file so that the ready-install-os.yml
            playbook can run and install the operating system on the nodes.</note>
        </li>

      </ol>
    </section>
    <section><title>Running the GUI to install your cloud</title>
      <p>Now that the OS, HP Linux for HP Helion OpenStack, is installed on all your servers
        (nodes), you will configure and install your cloud using the GUI.</p>
      <p>The GUI is found on the deployer node at: <b>http://&lt;Deployer_IP>:79/dayzero</b></p>
      <p>To create a secure tunnel/port forwarding into Apache from the deployer to be able to use
        the GUI in a browser, SSH tunnel into the deployer with the username/password set up when
        installing the deployer. Username and password should be what was set in "Set up the
        Deployer" in the installation instructions. For example:</p>
      <codeblock>ssh -v -N -L 8080:&lt;Deployer_IP>:79 &lt;Username>@&lt;Deployer_IP></codeblock>
      <p>Then on your local machine, point your web browser to: http://localhost:8080/dayzero</p> As
      you proceed through the GUI, you need only supply your server names and IP addresses. </section>
    <section>In the Assign network groups: External VM network fields, <b>do not</b> add entries for
      CIDR, Gateway, or IP Range, only VLAN ID. Neutron will assign these.<p>When the installation
        is complete, the Ansible log will be displayed on the final page.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Using the installer securely</title>
      <p> The GUI installer is a web-based application that runs on the deployer/lifecycle manager
        node and is implemented in nodejs. Currently this application runs behind Apache 2.0 where
        requests are proxied to the nodejs Express Web Server. The nodejs Express Server runs on
        port 3000 and Apache runs on port 79. </p>
      <p>You should access the installer through Apache and not directly from the Express server. An
        Example URL looks like this: http://&lt;deployer-host-ip>:79/dayzero When you finish
        installing, the Installer will be disabled via Ansible. It is also disabled once deployment
        is completed following the CLI instructions..</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <p>The GUI is used only once: during the initial installation of your cloud.</p><p>For VSA you
        must follow the steps outlined in the <xref href="installation/configure_vsa.dita">VSA
          Configuration</xref>page.</p> After deployment, continue to <xref
        href="installation/installation_verification.dita">Verifying Your Installation</xref> and <xref
        href="installation/postinstall_checklist.dita">Post-Installation
        Checklist</xref>.<p>To understand a cloud configuration more thoroughly and to learn how to
        make any changes later, visit these documentation pages: <ul id="ul_akt_fv2_lt">
          <li><xref href="input_model.dita">HP Helion OpenStack 2.0 Input Model</xref></li>
          <li><xref href="installation/using_git.dita">Using Git for Configuration Management</xref></li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <note>Because the GUI installer is disabled after deployment finishes, either via the GUI or
        via the command line, if you want to re-enable the GUI later but are not re-installing from
        scratch, run these commands:
        <codeblock>sudo a2ensite dayzero-apache.conf
sudo systemctl start dayzero.service</codeblock>
      </note>
    </section>

  </body>
</topic>
