<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="supported_configs">
  <title>Beta 2: Supported Configuration</title>
  <body>
    <p>In Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> 2.0 Beta 2 we offer the Entry Scale Cloud model
      with two variations depending on the hypervisor you wish to use -- KVM or ESX.</p>
    <p>The following list summarizes this configuration and it's purpose.</p>
    <section><title>Entry Scale Cloud</title>
      <p>At minimum scale this model can be used to deploy a 3-4 node environment but can also scale
        up to include up to 100 compute nodes. This is illustrated by the list below:</p>
      <simpletable id="hardware">
        <strow>
          <stentry><b>Control Plane</b></stentry>
          <stentry>3 nodes, hosts all management and ancillary services in a highly available
            cluster</stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry><b>Object Store</b></stentry>
          <stentry>All Swift services are contained in the control plane</stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry><b>Compute Nodes</b></stentry>
          <stentry>Min 1; Max 100</stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry><b>Block Storage (optional)</b></stentry>
          <stentry>3 nodes (recommended to ensure high availability) for our backend
            options</stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry><b>Physical Network</b></stentry>
          <stentry>1 pair of bonded NICs</stentry>
        </strow>
        <strow>
          <stentry><b>Network Separation</b>
          </stentry>
          <stentry>EXTERNAL_API, EXTERNAL_VM, GUEST (vxlan), MGMT on separate VLANs</stentry>
        </strow>
      </simpletable>
      <p>You can learn more about the hardware requirements here: <xref href="hardware.dita">Minimum
          Hardware Requirements</xref></p>
      <p>The network configuration supports separation of networks for:</p>
      <ul id="network">
        <li>Management - This network will be used for all internal traffic between the cloud
          services. It is an untagged network.</li>
        <li>External API - This is the network that users will use to make requests to the cloud. It
          is a tagged network.</li>
        <li>External VM - This network will be used to provide access to VMs (via floating IP
          addresses). It is a tagged network.</li>
        <li>Guest - This network will carry traffic between VMs on private networks within the
          cloud. It is a tagged network.</li>
      </ul>
      <note>The requirement to have a dedicated network for OS-install and system deployment has
        been removed. To re-use the deployment network as part of the operational network the
        following conditions must be adhered to:</note>
      <ol id="single_network">
        <li>The network IP addresses used for the operating system install (i.e.
            <codeph>baremetalConfig.yml</codeph> and <codeph>servers.yml</codeph>) must belong to a
          Network that is used for your cloud infrastructure (e.g. in networks.yml).</li>
        <li>The network that re-uses those addresses must be un-tagged.</li>
      </ol> In the example <b>entry-scale model</b> the management network is: <ul id="mgmt_net">
        <li>Mgmt 10.2.1.0/24 VLAN: 100 (untagged)</li>
      </ul>
      <p>In the <codeph>baremetalConfig.yml</codeph> file, servers are listed as:
        <codeblock>
baremetal_servers:
  - node_name: controller1
    node_type: CCN-001-001
    pxe_mac_addr: b2:72:8d:ac:7c:6f
    pxe_interface: eth2
    pxe_ip_addr: 192.168.10.3
    ilo_ip: 192.168.9.3</codeblock></p>
      <p>In the <codeph>servers.yml</codeph> file, servers will show as:
        <codeblock>
  - id: controller1
    role: ROLE-CCN
    ip-addr: 192.168.10.3</codeblock></p>
      <p>The values in the <codeph>baremetalConfig.yml</codeph> and <codeph>servers.yml</codeph>
        definition files need to members of the CIDR used for the untagged network (in this case the
        MGMT network).</p>
      <p>This cloud model also supports the physical bonding of network interfaces (NIC bonding),
        see <xref href="input_model.dita#input_model/4.7_InterfaceModels" type="section">Interface
          Models</xref> for more details on that feature.</p>
    </section>
    <section id="diagrams">
      <title>Configuration Illustrations</title>
      <p>The following diagram depicts a deployment scenario using the KVM hypervisor:</p>
      <p><image href="../media/networking/hos_kvm_diag.png"/></p>
      <p>The following diagram depicts a deployment scenario using the ESX hypervisor:</p>
      <p><image href="../media/networking/hos_esx_diag.png"/></p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
