<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_xx1_4bt_ts">
  <title>HP Helion OpenStack Object Storage (Swift)</title>
    <body>
      <p> </p>
    <p> A Object Storage (Swift)  is Software Defined Storage (SDS) architecture, layered on top of
      industry standard servers, using native storage devices which are typically disk drives. Swift
      presents an object paradigm using an undelying set of disk drives. The disk drives are managed
      by a data structure called the  "ring". Also, Swift enable you to store, retrieve, and delete
      objects in a containers through RESTful HTTP API.</p>
    <p>The services in the Swift cluster are either <i>access</i> services or <i>storage</i>
      services. <ul id="ul_x1l_32z_ts">
        <li> The <i>access</i> services group is made up of the Swift Proxy Servers, which run
          Swift-Proxy, Account and Container Services, HTTP/HTTPS load balancers, and OpenStack®
          Keystone authentication service. </li>
        <li> The <i>storage</i> services group is composed of Swift Object Servers and various
          background services such as replicators. <p>Each of the service group can scaled
            independently to meet workload and redundany requirements. The storage service can
            scaled up as necessary. It can also be horizontally scalable to handle an increased
            number of simultaneous connections as well as large number of objects.</p></li>
      </ul></p>
    <p>Based on OpenStack® Object Sotrage, the HP Helion OpenStack® Object Storage service provides
      a highly available, resilient, and scalable storage pool for unstructured data. It is highly
      durable architecture with no single point of failure. </p>
    <p>HP Helion OpenStack 2.0 allows you to specify your cloud configuration, knows as  input data
      model. Here, you need to provide the detailed information about the desired cloud topology
      (structure of control plane, assignment of services to nodes) and their services'
      configuration (e.g. Neutron plugins, etc) and environment specific configuration (e.g. OS
      kernel settings).</p>
      <p>
      <b>Input Model</b></p>
      <p><b> Enter the information what input model means in terms of swift. what all configurations
        can be set as an input data???</b>. </p>
      <section id="arch-overview"><b>Architecture Overview</b></section>
      <p> The following diagram depicts the architectural overview of the Swift deployment into your
        cloud:<ul id="ul_x1l_33z_ts">
        <li>
          <p><b>insert diagram</b>?????</p>
          <p>topology</p>
        </li>
      </ul></p>
      <section id="storage-plocies"><b>Storage Policies</b><p>Storage policies allow you to
        differentiate the way objects are stored. There are a number of possible reasons as
        follows:</p><ul id="ul_b5j_2fg_5s">
        <li>You have several different types or classes of disk drive. For example, you could use
          7.5K RPM high-capacity drives for one type of data and fast SSD drives for another type of
          data.</li>
        <li>You have different redundancy or availability needs. For example, you could use a
          replica count of 3 for "normal" data and a replica count of 4 for "critical" data.</li>
        <li>As described in the discussion of partition power above you are growing your capacity
          beyond the recommended partition power.</li>
        <li>You use erasure-coded storage for some objects and replicated storage for other
          objects.</li>
      </ul><p>Your end users chose which storage policy they use on a per-container basis. In
        practice most users will not explicitly specify the storage policy. You can specify which
        storage policy is then used by using the<b>default</b> attribute. You can change which
        storage policy is the default. However, this does not affect existing containers. Once the
        storage policy of a container is set, the policy for that container cannot be
        changed.</p><p>The disk drives used by storage policies can overlap or be distinct. However,
        if you overlap (i.e., have disks in common between two storage policies) you are recommended
        to use the same set of disk drives for both policies. If there is not a complete overlap in
        disk drives, as one storage policy receives many objects, the drives that are common to both
        policies must store more objects than drives that are only allocated to one storage policy.
        This may be appropriate for a situation where the "overlapped" disk drives are larger than
        the non-overlapped drives. However, in general this situation is harder to balance then a
        simple topology.</p></section>
       <p> 
       
       </p>
  </body>
</topic>
