<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_q5q_trz_jt">
  <title>Verify Backend Configuration</title>
  <body>
    <p>This page describes the procedure to create volume type, associate volume type to backend,
      create volume, attach volume, detach volume, and delete volume. You perform this operation to
      verify the configuration of backend (VSA, Ceph, and 3PAR).</p>
    <section>
      <title>Create Volume Type to Verify the Configuration of Backend</title>
      <p>Volumes are the Block Storage devices that you attach to instances to enable persistent
        storage. You can attach a volume or detach a volume and attach it to another instance at any
        time. You can also create and delete volume type and volumes.</p>
      <p>Perform the following steps to create a volume using Horizon dashboard:</p>
      <p>
        <ol id="ol_ldf_fxc_gt">
          <li>Log into the Horizon dashboard as <b>Admin</b>. The Horizon dashboard displays with
            the options in the left panel.</li>
          <li>From the left panel, click the <b>Admin</b> tab and then click the <b>Volumes</b> tab
            to display the Volumes page.<p><image
                href="../../media/3par/create-ceph-volumetype%20-%201.png" id="image_abz_l5z_jt"
              /></p></li>
          <li>Click <b>Create Volume Type</b> to display a dialog box.<p><image
                href="../../media/3par/create-ceph-volumetype%20(2).png" id="image_z4h_n5z_jt"
            /></p></li>
          <li>Enter a unique name for the volume. </li>
          <li>Click<b> Create Volume Type</b> to complete the action. Clicking <b>Cancel</b> returns
            to the Volumes screen without completing the action.<p>The newly created volume displays
              in the Volumes page.</p></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="associate-volume-backend">
      <title>Associate the Volume Type to a Backend</title>
      <p>To map a volume type to a backend, do the following: <ol id="ol_owv_krv_3t">
          <li>Login to the Horizon dashboard. The Horizon dashboard displays with the options in the
            left panel.</li>
          <li>From the left panel, click the <b>Admin</b> tab and then click the <b>Volumes</b> tab
            to display the Volumes page.<image
              href="../../media/3par/create-ceph-volumetype%20-%20extra-specs.png"
              id="image_tr2_q5z_jt"/></li>
          <li>Click <b>View Extra Specs</b> displayed against the volume type which you want to
            associate to the backend. <p><image
                href="../../media/3par/volume-extra-specs-3par_fc.png" id="image_hvl_t5z_jt"
              /></p><p>The <b>Create Volume Type Extra Specs</b> dialog box displays. Now map the
              volume type to the associate backend.</p></li>
          <li>In the <b>Key</b> box, enter <i>volume_banked_name</i> as volume backend name. This is
            the name of the key used to specify the storage backend when provisioning volumes of
            this volume type. The volume backend name must match the backend name mentioned in the
              <codeph>cinder.conf</codeph> file. <p>For example: You can enter the following backend
              name for the respective backend used. The backend name is mentioned in the
                <codeph>cinder.conf</codeph> file.<ul id="ul_u4j_1vz_jt">
                <li>VSA: You can enter <codeph>vsa-backend-hlm003</codeph> in the key field.</li>
                <li>Ceph: You can enter <codeph>ceph</codeph> in the key field.</li>
                <li>3PAR FC: You can enter <codeph>3par_fc</codeph> in the key field.</li>
                <li>3PAR iSCSI : You can enter <codeph>3par_iscsi</codeph> in the key field.</li>
              </ul></p></li>
          <li>In the <b>Value</b> box, enter the name of the backend to which you want to associate
            the volume type. </li>
          <li>Click <b>Create</b> to create the extra volume type specs. <note> Once the volume type
              is mapped to the backend, you can create volumes with this volume type.</note></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section id="create-volume">
      <title>Create Volume from User Account</title>
      <p>Perform the following steps to create a volume using Horizon dashboard. <ol
          id="ol_syw_xw3_jt">
          <li>Log into the Horizon dashboard. The Horizon dashboard displays with the options in the
            left panel. </li>
          <li>From the left panel, click the <b>Project</b> tab and then click the <b>Volumes</b>
            tab to display the Volumes page.<p><image href="../../media/3par/user-create-vol1.png"
                id="image_vdr_4vz_jt"/></p></li>
          <li>Click <b>Create Volume</b> to display a dialog box.<p><image
                href="../../media/3par/user_create-volume.png" id="image_hrs_pvz_jt"/></p></li>
          <li>Enter the required details in the corresponding fields. </li>
          <li>Click<b> Create Volume </b> to complete the action. Clicking <b>Cancel</b> returns to
            the Volumes screen without completing the action.<p><image
                href="../../media/3par/user-create-vol-main.png" id="image_hc5_qvz_jt"/></p><p>The
              volume is successfully created and the status of the volume is available.</p></li>
        </ol></p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Delete Volume from User Account</title>
      <p>Perform the following steps to delete a volume using Horizon dashboard:</p>
      <p>
        <ol id="ol_sdl_vy3_jt">
          <li>Log into the Horizon dashboard. The Horizon dashboard displays with the options in the
            left panel. </li>
          <li>From the left panel, click the <b>Project</b> tab and then click the <b>Volumes</b>
            tab to display the Volumes page.<p><image
                href="../../media/3par/user-create-vol-main.png" id="image_pfw_tvz_jt"/></p></li>
          <li>Check the box in the row of the volume to delete.</li>
          <li>Click <b>Delete Volume</b> to display the dialog box.<p><image
                href="../../media/3par/user-delete-vol.png" id="image_jgn_xvz_jt"/></p></li>
          <li>Click <b>Delete the Volume</b> to confirm the deletion of the selected volume. To exit
            without deleting the volume and to close the screen, click <b>Cancel</b> before
            deleting.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
