<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic804">
  <title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Carrier Grade 2.0 Alpha: Managing Server Groups</title>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <body>
    <p><!--UNDER REVISION--><!--./UseCases/TasksforUsers/Instances/1.1commercial.managing.instances.users.md--><!--permalink: /helion/commercial/1.1/dashboard/managing/instances/users/--></p>
    <p>From the Titanium Server Admin Guide </p>
    <p>Server Groups is a mechanism to group virtual machines to which a common set of attributes is
      applied.</p>
    <p>
      <b>Note:</b> This feature applies only to servers in regionone.</p>
    <p><image href="../../../media/CGH-2-server-group.png" width="600" id="image_cr5_csv_ht"/></p>
    <p>To create a server group:</p>

      <ol>
        <li><xref href="../Dashboard/CGH-2-User-Dashboard-launch.dita#topic1160">Launch the HP
            Helion OpenStack Horizon Dashboard</xref>.</li>
        <li><xref href="../Dashboard/CGH-2-User-region-selector.dita#jow1432757989702">Select the
            appropriate region and project</xref>.</li>
        <li>Click the <b>Admin</b> dashboard, then the <b>System</b> panel, then the <b>Server
            Groups</b> tab. </li>
        <li>In the <b>Server Group</b> table, click <b>Create Server Group</b>.</li>
        <li>In the <b>Create Server Group</b> dialog, specify the following information:<ul
          id="ul_ewj_3sv_ht">
          <li><b>Project</b> Select a project to associate the server group.</li>
          <li><b>Server Group Name</b> Specify a name for the new server group. </li>
          <li><b>Policy</b> Select a scheduling policy: <ul>
              <li><b>affinity</b>. When this option is selected, new instances launched as part of
                this server group are scheduled to run on the same compute node. </li>
              <li><b>anti-affinity</b>. When this option is selected, new instances launched as part
                of this server group are scheduled to run on different compute nodes. For example,
                you can use the anti-affinity option when you have two virtual machines that run in
                1:1 HA protection mode, and you want them to be protected against hardware
                failures.</li>
            </ul></li>
          <li><b>Best Effort</b>. Select this option to enforce the policy in place, affinity, or
            anti-affinity, on a best-effort basis. If for any reason the policy cannot be enforced,
            then the deployment of the new instance proceeds using the regular scheduling. When
            cleared, the policy in place must be executable for the new instance to be scheduled.
            Launching of a new virtual machine fails if there are no resources to comply with the
            selected policy. </li>
          <li><b>Max Group Size (Instances)</b>. Determines the maximum number of instances that can
            co-exist as part of this server group. </li>
        </ul></li>
        <li>Click <b>Create Server Group</b>. </li>
</ol>
    
    <p>You can add instance to a server group as you <xref
        href="../Instances/CGH-2-User-Instance-create.dita#topic2817">create the
      instance</xref>.</p>
  </body>
</topic>
