---
layout: default-devplatform
title: "HP Helion 1.1 Development Platform: Installation Troubleshooting"
permalink: /helion/devplatform/1.1/install/troubleshooting/
product: devplatform
product-version1: HP Helion Development Platform
product-version2: HP Helion Development Platform 1.1
role1: Systems Administrator 
role2: System Engineer
role3: Cloud Administrator
role4: Network Administrator
role5: Application Developer
Role6: Security Engineer
role7: Application Developer 
role8: ISV Developer
role9: Service Developer
authors: Jayme P

---
<!--PUBLISHED-->


# HP Helion 1.1 Development Platform: Installation Troubleshooting

- [Installation](#installation)
- [Download](#download)
- [Horizon](#horizon)
- [DBaaS](#dbaas) (database)
- [ALS](#ALS) (Application Lifecycle Service)
- [Marketplace](#marketplace)
- [Creating Instances](#instance-create)

## Installation {#installation}

###Command line installer fails to install
 Resolution: **Set** https\_proxy and **unset** http\_proxy values.

###Command line installer fails to install with Authentication Error 
Even after fixing some errors and retrying, the command line installation fails.

Resolution: 

1. Locate and open the *dev-platform-installer* folder. This folder is created by the installation process.
	- Delete the *.env* folder.
	- Delete the *dev-platform-installer.conf* file.
3. [Run the install command](/helion/devplatform/1.1/install/#commandline) again with all command line options.

## Download {#download}

### Service is stuck in download

The *tmp* directory has run out of space. Mount the *tmp* directory to a larger partition and try again. If it fails again, reset the download.

1. Log in to Horizon as an Admin user.
2. In the **Admin** tenant, click **Project** and then **Object Store**.
3. Open the **sherpa-cache** folder and delete the **wscatalog.<id\>** folder which contains the cached download.
4. Download the service again.

### Download terminates and remains stuck in "Staging" status

Only applies to Development Platform services. After the image download terminates for some reason, the download is reattempted. The status of the service in the Configure Services view remains stuck at "Staging" and does not progress to "Available".

 Resolution: Completely delete the service before reattempting download.

1. Log in to Horizon as an Admin user.
2. Delete the images for that service.
3. In the Admin tenant, click **Project** and then **Object Store**.
4. Go to Containers and delete the heat-templates for the service.
3. Go to Containers > Sherpa-cache and delete the wscatalog folder for that service.

If the status on the Configure Services view does not change to "Available", Sherpa is looking at the file cache. To clear this, remove the cache and restart Apache.

1. Log in to the controller management node.
2. Delete the directory */var/cache/sherpa/ws.xxxx*
1. Delete the contents of the */var/lib/Sherpa/data* folder.
2. Apache must be restarted before this change will take effect. <br />Run:
		
		service apache2 restart 


## Horizon {#horizon}
###Installed Development Platform services do not appear in Horizon

Even though the service was installed successfully, the service does not appear in the appropriate tab.
 
Resolution: After installing any Helion Development Platform service, log out of Horizon and then back in to refresh the UI.

###Deleted service still appears in Horizon

Even though the Development Platform stack has been deleted, the service still shows up in Horizon.

Resolution: Delete the service manually from the Keystone endpoint list. <br /> Start the command line client and enter:

	keystone endpoint-delete $<id>

##DBaaS {#dbaas}

###DbaaS configuration fails
 
Resolution: Make sure that you can create a volume and attach it to instances. HP Helion OpenStack supports VSA and 3PAR, but not LVM. Make sure your installation is configured to use either VSA or 3PAR.

###DbaaS instance fails to start
Resolution: Check if you can create and start a Nova instance with the same flavor and verify you can attach a volume to that Nova instance. Verify that the Nova flavors have not been updated to invalid values. Verify that the flavor's ID is correct, as flavor updates cause the flavor IDs to change.

## Marketplace {#marketplace}

###Vertica installation fails after successful Marketplace installation

Resolution: Immediately after installing Marketplace, log out of Horizon and then back in before beginning the Vertica installation. 

##ALS {#ALS}

**ALS cluster creation fails after successful installation of ALS and DBaaS.**
 
Resolution: Make sure DBaaS is functional and responsive by creating a new DBaaS instance. If DBaaS is installed in the environment, ALS expects DBaaS to respond to API requests.

<a name="katopatch"></a> **Running *kato patch install* fails to install patches on non-core nodes in ALS 1.1 clusters.**

**Note**: This issue only applies to ALS clusters created using an installer image older than version 1.1.0.19. 

**Resolution**: Update the cluster with the *cf-fix-kato-patch* command line tool.
 
1. Set the standard OpenStack environment variables. <br />The OpenStack *ca-certificate* is found in the Helion OpenStack Seed VM at:  */usr/local/share/ca-certificates/ephemeralca-cacert.crt*

		OS_USERNAME
		OS_PASSWORD
		OS_REGION_NAME
		OS_AUTH_URL
		OS_TENANT_ID
		OS_CACERT


	- Linux / Mac: Download and source the openrc.sh file using the Horizon management console.
	- Windows: Set the environment variables manually or specify the values as command line flags ( --os-username, --os-password, --os-region-name, --os-auth-url, --os-tenant-id, --os-cacert)

2.	Download the appropriate *cf-fix-kato-patch* tool for your operating system.
	- [MacOS](http://g7743e0143085e2793a5aef95989b09ea.cdn.hpcloudsvc.com/cf-fix-kato-patch/darwin/cf-fix-kato-patch)
	- [Linux](http://g7743e0143085e2793a5aef95989b09ea.cdn.hpcloudsvc.com/cf-fix-kato-patch/linux/cf-fix-kato-patch)
	- [Windows](http://g7743e0143085e2793a5aef95989b09ea.cdn.hpcloudsvc.com/cf-fix-kato-patch/windows/cf-fix-kato-patch.exe)
3.	Run the *cf-fix-kato-patch* tool from a machine that can SSH into your cluster nodes.
	-	Linux / Mac:
		
			./cf-fix-kato-patch <key file> <cluster prefix>
	- Windows:
		
			cf-fix-kato-patch.exe <key file> <cluster prefix>
 
The `<key file>` is the path to the private key file corresponding to the keypair you used when creating the cluster. 

The `<cluster prefix>` is the prefix at the beginning of all of the nodes in the cluster. For example, if your prefix was *cluster1*, the core node of your cluster should be named *cluster1-core*.
 
If any errors occur while the *cf-fix-kato-patch* tool is running, the tool will halt execution. Simply run the tool again; applying the tool multiple times will have no negative effects.

**ALS Constructor fails with "No valid host was found" Error**

Resolution: Attempt to spin up a Nova instance with **Flavor** set to **Tiny**. Verify that the Nova flavors were NOT updated to invalid values. Verify the Flavor IDs, as updates cause flavor IDs to change.

##Creating Instances {#instance-create}

###DbaaS instances, ALS clusters, Marketplace, and Messaging clusters all fail to start.

Resolution: Nova and Neutron quotas have been exceeded. Increase quotas to support your desired configuration.

###Issue: "No valid host was found" Error Received During Installation of the Development Platform and DNaaS

Resolution: This Nova error could have multiple causes. Do not assume that  it is out of compute resources. Check the *nova-scheduler* logs on the overcloud controllers to find the actual reason why Nova failed to schedule the instance; correct the issue; and then attempt the DNSaaS deployment again.

