<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic6108">
    <title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Carrier Grade 2.0: Changes and Additions from
        Version 1.1</title>
    <prolog>
        <metadata>
            <othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
            <othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Administrator"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Architect"/>
            <othermeta name="role" content="Michael B"/>
            <othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
        </metadata>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <p><b>Differences from HCG 1.1 Architecture</b></p>
        <p>HCG 2.0 Architecture is built upon HCG 1.1 with the following key differences:</p>
        <ol id="ol_azt_whc_f5">
            <li>WR computes can support vSwitch of your choice - AVS or VRS: To enable this feature,
                we are replacing AVS with VRS based on the product SKU being selected. The
                architecture toggles between Neutron being a shared service (HCG-VRS) to dedicated
                service per region (HCG-AVS). The architecture for both products is documented on
                this one architecture page. Both products share many components. Many of the
                interfaces have not changed since HCG 1.1 other than being renumbered as part of
                cleaning up this page. </li>
            <li>Baremetal Region to provide baremetal provisioning as a service: We extended the
                architecture by adding another control plane (single node) running identical
                services plus ironic but in different region - nova, neutron and ironic</li>
            <li>VxLAN to VLAN bridging: We are now using HPN 5930/7900 switches in the architecture
                as enabler for providing VxLAN to VLAN switching. This is specifically for VMs with
                virtio vNICs to communicate with baremetal ports like SR-IOV, PCI-PT and Host
                Port.</li>
            <li>Enhance Standard control plane for Backup, Logging and Monitoring services for
                Standard region services: Added and enhanced new services like Icinga,
                Elastic-Logstash-Kibana (ELK), Attis services. </li>
            <li>Infoblox as IPAM plugin: Neutron has now a plugin to support IP reservation through
                Infoblox appliance. Architecturally, it is an enhancement to Neutron Service running
                in each region.</li>
        </ol>
        <p><b>Added Components</b></p>
        <ul id="ul_bzt_whc_f5">
            <li><b>Standard Controller</b> (Controller running on hLinux): Standard IaaS control
                plane very similar to HOS. The main difference is that DCN/Nuage is used for
                networking rather than OVS to enable cloud-to-cloud communication. Icinga has also
                been upgraded to Icinga2 to enable more monitoring features. Many components of this
                region are shared with the WR Region.</li>
            <li><b>ESX Compute</b>: Standard IaaS compute node using DCN/Nuage components for
                networking. <b>The product has evolved such that there will be no compute nodes
                    based on hLinux KVM for 2.0. One offering will not have any ESX compute nodes
                    and also no DCN nodes. Another offering will have vCenter based ESX compute
                    nodes.</b> This component has sub component <b>DCN VRS</b> (Virtualized Routing
                &amp; Switching). It provide L2/L3 capabilities to enable VMs to communicate within
                the cloud and for remote cloud communication.</li>
            <li><b>WR Compute</b>: Realtime compute node with Wind River (WR) networking components.
                Wind River Linux with a modified, realtime KVM run on these nodes. A change for 2.0
                is that one of the HCG products will ship with DCN VRS and the other will ship with
                AVS networking configured.</li>
            <li><b>BM Controller</b>: Ironic server and compute proxy along with dependent services
                such as DHCP and DNS run on this single node to control requests for bare metal
                compute nodes. The bare metal controller and compute nodes run in their own region
                of the cloud.</li>
            <li><b>BM Node</b>: Bare metal node to be allocated and used on demand similar to a VM.
                They are managed by the BM Controller.</li>
            <li><b>5930 Switch</b>: HP Networking hardware switch to provide VxLAN to VLAN Bridging
                for SR-IOV, PC-PT or Baremtal Host ports. It also provides DHCP services to these
                baremetal ports. We have plans to use this for external network connectivity to
                replace software gateway VRS-G.</li>
            <li><b>Infoblox</b>: 3rd party product requested by Telefonica to support IPAM. Infoblox
                will be optional for other customers and is not expected to be used.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>Service Architecture Diagram</b></p>
        <p><b>1. VRS SKU</b></p>
        <p><b>Control Plane Interfaces</b></p>
        <p>
            <image href="../../media/CGH-2-control-plane-intf.png" id="image_mrd_1jc_f5"/></p>
        <p><b>Data Plane Interfaces </b></p>
        <image href="../../media/CGH-2-data-plane-intf.png" id="image_tlh_2jc_f5"/>
        <p><b>2. AVS SKU</b></p>
        <p><b>Dependencies</b></p>
        <p>The following dependencies are new to Version 2.0:</p>
        <ul id="ul_ams_r3c_f5">
            <li>Helion OpenStack 2.0</li>
            <li>Helion Lifecycle Management (HLM) - Pre 2.0</li>
            <li>Nuage/DCN 3.2</li>
            <li>Wind River Titanium 15.09</li>
            <li>Infoblox</li>
            <li>HPN 5930/7900 OVSDB Firmware</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>Summary of Controls</b></p>
        <p>Summary of controls spanning multiple components and interfaces:</p>
        <ul id="ul_gms_r3c_f5">
            <li><b>Audit:</b> OpenStack services, mySQL, RabbitMQ, HLM CP, Ansible, Cobbler perform
                logging. Logs are collected by the centralized logging service.</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>Authentication: </b>Authentication via Keystone tokens at APIs. Password
                    authentication to Nuage components and StoreVirtual.</p>
            </li>
            <li><b>Authorization</b>: OpenStack provides admin and non-admin roles that are
                indicated in session tokens. Processes run at minimum privilege. Processes run as
                unique user/group definitions. Appropriate filesystem controls prevent other
                processes from accessing service’s files. IPtables and ACLs at the network perimeter
                ensure that no unneeded ports are open.</li>
            <li><b>Availability:</b> Redundant hosts, clustered DB, clustered MQ, fail-over.
                Monitoring via centralized monitoring service.</li>
            <li>
                <p><b>Confidentiality:</b> Network connections for outside access to APIs over TLS.
                    Network separation via VLANs. Data and config files protected via filesystem
                    controls. Separation of customer traffic on the TUL network via Open Flow
                    (VxLANs).</p>
            </li>
            <li><b>Integrity:</b> Network connections for outside access to APIs over TLS. Network
                separation via VLANs. Data and config files are protected by filesystem controls.
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p> </p>
    </body>
</topic>
