<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_sm4_tm1_h5">
  <title>HPE Helion 2.0 Development Platform: Installation Overview</title>
  <body>
    <section>
      <p>The HPE Helion Development Platform is made up of several services. Each of these services
        can be installed independently. You do not have to install them in any particular order.</p>
      <p>Services are installed using the HDP Installer, also known as HDPI. This tool is a plugin
        for the python-openstackclient (OSC). You will download and set up the HDPI before
        installing any services.</p>
      <p>During installation, the HDPI refers to a configuration file named clouds.yaml for the
        parameters it needs. There is only one clouds.yaml file. Each service has its own section
        within that file containing parameters specific to that service. The information must be in
        the clouds.yaml file before you install the service. However, since each service can be
        installed separately, you can populate the whole file at once, or only one section at a
        time, as you prefer.</p>
      <p>During installation, the required files will be downloaded from the Helion Download Network
        (HDN). Depending on network traffic, this may take up to 90 minutes. This download may also
        be problematic if your HPE Helion OpenStack lifecycle manager (previously known as the
        deployer node), is behind significant layers of security. To avoid possible delay,
        interruption, or just for convenience, you can download the files before beginning the
        installation process. If the installer finds the files already in the appropriate location,
        it will not download them again.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>General Installation Procedure</title>
      <p>You do not have to install all available services at the same time.</p>
   <ol>
        <li>(optional) Download the installation files from the Helion Download Network (HDN) and,
          if necessary, copy them to the correct location.</li>
        <li>Ensure all prerequisites are satisfied. Check environmental configuration, gather
          required information, and verify required connectivity.</li>
        <li>Create the clouds.yaml file and populate it with the minimum required information.</li>
        <li>Download and set up the HDPI.</li>
        <li>Populate the clouds.yaml file with the remaining information required for all services /
          the next service you intend to install.</li>
        <li>Using the HDPI, install each service.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
