<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_gly_xmh_ts">
  <title>Install the HPE Helion Development Platform</title>
  <body>
    <section><p>The installation procedure has changed significantly since the last release. The HDP Installer
        2.0, also known as HDPI, is a plugin for the the python-openstackclient (OSC). It is able to
        leverage the authentication, configuration and command line option parsing that is already
        part of OSC to greatly simplify the installation process.</p>
      <p>
        <note type="warning">You must have <xref
            href="devplatform_install_prereq.dita#topic_x54_njh_ts">satisfied all
            prerequisites</xref> before beginning installation.</note>
      </p>

      <title>Download the Latest Version of HPE Helion Development Platform Installation
        Client</title>
      <p>The installation is provided as a small compressed tar file. The images for the individual
        services will be downloaded during each service installation.</p>
      <ol id="ol_ogs_qpt_nt">
        <li>Navigate to the <xref href="https://helion.hpwsportal.com/catalog.html#/Home/Show"
            format="html" scope="external">HPE Helion Download Network</xref> (HDN) and log in. If
          necessary, create an account first.</li>
        <li>Download the Development Platform Installer 2.0.0.0 beta package.</li>
      </ol>
    </section>

    <section id="pre-installing-the-hp-helion-development-platform">
      <title>Install the HPE Helion Development Platform Installation Client</title>
      <note type="important">Do not source <codeph>service.osrc</codeph>, <codeph>keystone.osrc</codeph>, or any other <codeph>*rc</codeph> file before you begin.</note>
      <ol>
        <li>SSH to the HPE Helion OpenStack Deployer. </li>
        <li>Check to ensure that all Keystone AUTH_URL IP addresses have been added to the <xref
            href="devplatform_install_prereq.dita#topic_x54_njh_ts/proxy">no-proxy </xref>list.</li>
        <li>Check to ensure that all OS_ variables are unset. To check this, run
          <codeblock>env | grep OSX_ </codeblock>and then <codeph>unset</codeph> any OS_ variables
          which appear in the list of results. </li>
        <li>Create and source the Virtual Environment. In this example,
            <codeph>&lt;dpi-venv&gt;.tgz</codeph> is the name of the
          installer.<codeblock>mkdir -p /opt/stack/venv/&lt;dpi-venv> 
tar -C /opt/stack/venv/&lt;dpi-venv&gt; -xzf &lt;dpi-venv&gt;.tgz
source /opt/stack/venv/&lt;dpi-venv&gt;/bin/activate</codeblock></li>
        <li>Test the installation by retrieving a list of installable files. The <codeph>--debug
          </codeph>option will return information vital for troubleshooting, if
          necessary.<codeblock>openstack hdpi --os-cloud mycloud hdpi list --debug</codeblock></li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
