<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic2394">
<title>HPE Helion 2.0 Development Platform: Deploying Windows Applications with the IIS Buildpack</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HPE Helion Development Platform"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HPE Helion Development Platform 2.0"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Systems Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="System Engineer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Cloud Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Network Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="ISV Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Service Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Patrick F"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--PUBLISHED-->
 <!--./devplatform/windows/windows_custom_buildpacks.md-->
 <!--permalink: /helion/devplatform/windows/buildpack/--></p>
<p>
  <!--Original: <span @class=>--><ph>
    <i>Windows, .NET, SQL Server, and IIS are either registered trademarks or trademarks of Microsoft Corporation in the United States and/or other countries.</i>
  </ph>
</p>
<p>A <b>Buildpack</b> is a collection of scripts that specify what frameworks and runtimes are to be deployed with an application.</p>
<p>When you build and deploy a Windows application, the following steps take place:</p>
<ol>
<li> You will be prompted for connection data (Endpoint, login, and password), and whether to ignore
        SSL errors. You should check "Ignore SSL errors" in the dialog if your deployment
        environment uses self-signed SSL certificates (such as HPE Helion Public Cloud).<p>
          <image href="../../../media/windows_publish_credentials.png" placement="break"/>
        </p></li>
<li>Application settings are collected from <codeph>manifest.yml</codeph>.</li>
<li>If a local build is requested, projects in the solution directory are deployed to a temporary folder and compiled with <b>MSBuild</b>.</li>
<li>Projects are deployed using the <b>CloudFoundry MS Build Tasks</b>.</li>
</ol>
<p>After the project is deployed, the IIS Buildpack performs the following tasks:</p>
<ol>
<li>If there is no solution or project file present, the application is simply copied to the "Build Path" directory (This is a directory determined internally by the Buildpack).</li>
<li>If a project file is present, but no solution file, the application is built with <b>MSBuild</b> with no parameters, and the built application is copied to the "Build Path" directory.</li>
<li>If a solution file is present, NuGet packages listed in the solution file will be restored, and the application will be built with <b>MSBuild</b>, and the application is copied to the "Build Path" directory.</li>
</ol>
<p>This process can fail if any of the following are true:</p>
<ol>
<li>There is more than one solution file present</li>
<li>The number of folders in the deployed site is not correct</li>
<li>There is no <codeph>Web.Config</codeph> file in the root of the "Build Path" directory after deployment</li>
</ol>
<p>For more information, please refer to the <xref href="https://github.com/hpcloud/cf-iis8-buildpack" scope="external" format="html" >Buildpack git project</xref>.</p>

</body>
</topic>
