<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_xx1_4bt_ts">
  <title>HP Helion OpenStack Object Storage (Swift)</title>
    <body>
      <p>
        With this release, HP Helion OpenStack introduces a concept of input data model. Input
        model allows you to provide the input data based (<b>data like .....?)</b> on your
        choice of configuration.
        <!--This input models ensures that you are deploying HP Helion OpenStack based on your preferences and configurations. This makes the product more flexible to your usage. -->
      </p>
      <p>
        Based on OpenStack® Object Sotrage, the HP Helion OpenStack® Object Storage service
        provides a highly available, resilient, and scalable storage pool for unstructured data.
        It is highly durable architecture with no single point of failure. 
      </p>
       <section id="input_model"><b>Input Model</b></section>
      <p><b> Enter the information what input model means in terms of swift. what all configurations
        can be set as an input data???</b>. </p>
      <section id="arch-overview"><b>Architecture Overview</b></section>
           <p> A Object Storage (Swift) cluster is Software Defined Storage (SDS) architecture, layered
      on top of industry standard servers, using native storage devices which are typically disk
      drives. 
        <note> It is not recommended to run Swift on top of other systems (hardware or
        software) that hide the failure domains or native storage devices like using RAID group on
        top of drives.</note></p>
      <p> The services in the Swift cluster are either <i>access</i> services or <i>storage</i>
      services. <ul id="ul_x1l_32z_ts">
        <li> The <i>access</i> services group is made up of the Swift Proxy Servers, which run
          Swift-Proxy, Account and Container Services, HTTP/HTTPS load balancers, and OpenStack®
          Keystone authentication service. </li>
        <li> The <i>storage</i> services group is composed of Swift Object Servers and various
          background services such as replicators. <p>Each of the service group can scaled
            independently to meet workload and redundany requirements. The storage service can
            scaled up as necessary. It can also be horizontally scalable to handle an increased
            number of simultaneous connections as well as large number of objects.</p><p>The
            following diagram depicts the architectural overview of the Swift
              deployment:</p><p><b>insert diagram</b>?????</p></li>
      </ul></p>
      <section id="storage-plocies"><b>Storage Policies</b></section>
       <p> 
       
       </p>
  </body>
</topic>
