<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic13345">
<title>HPE Helion Public Cloud CLI Software for Windows PowerShell Compute Examples</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--PUBLISHED-->
 <!--./publiccloud/cli.windows.2.compute.md-->
 <!--permalink: /publiccloud/cli/windows/compute/--></p>
<p>This page provides you some examples of how to use the various commands (sometimes called "cmdlets") for HPE Helion Public Cloud CLI software for Windows PowerShell implementation of Compute.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/Navigation">Navigation</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/ColorManagement">Availability Zone Color Management</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/KeyManagement">Key Management</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/SecurityGroups">Security Groups</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/BasicServerOperations">Basic Server Operations</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/AdvancedServerOperations">Advanced Server Operations</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/PasswordManagement">Password Management</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic13345/IPManagement">Floating IP Management</xref>
</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Note</b>: Use <codeph>get-help CMDLET -detailed</codeph> for details about the syntax of each of the cmdlets shown.  Just replace <codeph>CMDLET</codeph> with the command you want to learn about.  For example, to find the syntax for the <codeph>New-Server</codeph> cmdlet you could use <codeph>get-help New-Server -detailed</codeph>.</p>
<section id="Navigation"> <title>Navigation</title>
<p>To execute commands in Windows PowerShell, first open a Windows PowerShell window as Administrator.  Under the Start menu, it is typically under <codeph>All Programs &gt; Accessories &gt; Windows PowerShell</codeph>.  Select the shell appropriate to your system, either the 64-bit or 32-bit version.  If the prompt is not already at <codeph>PS HPCS:\&gt;</codeph> then enter the HPE Helion Public Cloud Services CLI by entering:</p>
<codeblock>
PS C:\&gt; cd HPCS:
</codeblock>
<p>Once in the HPCS area, you can move around as if you were in a standard directory structure.  For example, entering the <b>ls</b> command:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\&gt; ls
</codeblock>
<p>Generates the following output:</p>
<codeblock>
==========================================================================================================
Account Associations
==========================================================================================================

Name            Description                                                                                          Type          Path
----            -----------                                                                                          ----          ----
Servers         A place to manage Servers across the Account.                                                        Container     Servers
Flavors         Manage additional hardware configurations for Servers.                                               Container     Flavors
Images          Manage collections of files used to create or rebuild Servers.                                       Container     Images
Security        Manage Key Pair and Security Group Rules here.                                                       Container     Security
BlockStorage    A place to manage Block Storage Volumes and Snapshots.                                               Container     BlockStorage
Networks        Manage networks, subnets, ports and routers.                                                         Container     Networks
</codeblock>
<p>To view objects in each area, just <b>cd</b> to the appropriate location and run the command.  For example, if you want to view security objects:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; cd Security
</codeblock>
<p>An <codeph>ls</codeph> command shows further nested objects available.</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\Security&gt; ls
==========================================================================================================
Security Associations
==========================================================================================================

Name            Description
----            -----------
SecurityGroups  Container objects used for security group rules
KeyPairs        A place to manage public/private keys used to create secure connections to compute instances.
</codeblock>
<p>
<b>Note:</b> When referencing an argument, like a container name, that has a space, use quotes to access that resource. For example:</p>
<codeblock>
PS: HPCS:\&gt; cd "my container:"
PS: HPCS:\&gt; new-container "my new container"
</codeblock>
</section>
<section id="ColorManagement"> <title>Availability Zone Color Management</title>
<p>Each availability zone is assigned a color to make it easier for you to recognize which zone you are in.  For example, if availability zone 1 is assigned cyan, whenever you are in that zone, all the command-line text is cyan.  To see what colors are assigned to each zone, use the <codeph>get-zones</codeph> command:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; get-zones

Current Availability Zones include

Zone Id  Name                 Shell Foreground Color  Is Default
-------  ----                 ----------------------  ----------
1        region-a.geo-1       Green                   False
2        region-b.geo-1       Green                   True
</codeblock>
<p>To assign a new color to a particular availability zone, use the <codeph>Set-ZoneColor</codeph> command.</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Set-ZoneColor 1 Cyan

az-1.region-a.geo-1 now assigned to Cyan.
</codeblock>
<p>Use the <codeph>Zone Id</codeph> value rather than the zone name to set the color.</p>
<p><b>Note</b>: The input to the command is case-sensitive; you must use an initial capital letter for the color name.  For example, <codeph>Cyan</codeph> rather than <codeph>cyan</codeph></p>
<p>After you change the zone color, when you navigate to the zone you see something similar to that shown below:</p>
<p>
  <image href="../media/wincli_color_change.png">
<alt/>
</image>
</p>
</section>
<section id="KeyManagement"> <title>Key Management</title>
<p>To create a new keypair:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; New-KeyPair "MyKey"
</codeblock>
<p>Created keys are stored locally in <codeph>C:\Users\*username*\Documents\HP</codeph> directory and in your Public Cloud account by default. A single key-pair can used to create multiple servers.</p>
<p><b>Note</b>: When you generate a private key, be sure to make a note of the keypair as this is the only time it is displayed.  Be sure to store your private keys in a safe location in order to allow ssh connections to that server.</p>
<p>To list keypairs, browse to the KeyPairs directory and perform the <codeph>ls</codeph> command:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; cd Security
PS HPCS:\Security&gt; cd KeyPairs
PS HPCS:\Security\KeyPairs&gt; ls
</codeblock>
<p>To remove an existing keypair:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Remove-KeyPair "MyKey"
</codeblock>
<p><b>Note</b>: When you remove the key it will be removed from your Public Cloud account by default but will remain in your local directory. Manual deletion of the local file will be necessary if desired.</p>
</section>
<section id="SecurityGroups"> <title>Security Groups</title>
<p>To list the currently-available security groups:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; cd Security
PS HPCS:\Security&gt; cd SecurityGroups
PS HPCS:\Security\SecurityGroups&gt; ls 
</codeblock>
<p>This command generates output that looks like:</p>
<codeblock>
============================================
The following SecurityGroups are available.
============================================

Id          Name          Description          
--          ----          -----------          
0         default       default              

1 SecurityGroup(s) found
</codeblock>
<p>To create a new security group, where <codeph>-n</codeph> is the name of the security group and <codeph>-d</codeph> is the description for the security group:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; New-SecurityGroup -n "TestGroup" -d "Test Security Group"
</codeblock>
<p>To create a new security group rule and assign it to an existing security group use the <codeph>Add-Rule</codeph> cmdlet.  Here is an example adding an Ingress rule to open TCP port 80:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Add-Rule -d "Ingress" -min "80" -max "80" -p "tcp" -ripp "15.185.118.75/0" -sgid "0"
</codeblock>
<p><b>Note</b>: Use <codeph>get-help Add-Rule -detailed</codeph> for details about the syntax of the command.</p>
<p>
<b>Note for Windows Images</b>: A security group requires port 3389 to connect to a Windows instance via the remote desktop protocol (RDP). Windows CLI automatically creates security group <codeph>rdp_group</codeph> with port 3389 open when it detects a Windows image type during creation, and automatically applies the <codeph>rdp_group</codeph> security group to that Windows instance. Security Group <codeph>rdp_group</codeph> is always added as a security group to Windows instances even when you specify other security groups as arguments with the <codeph>New-Server</codeph> cmdlet.</p>
<p>To list the rules of a security group just use <codeph>cd</codeph> to navigate to the security group and then <codeph>ls</codeph> to the list the rules, like below:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; cd Security
PS HPCS:\Security&gt; cd SecurityGroups
PS HPCS:\Security\SecurityGroups&gt; cd 0
PS HPCS:\Security\SecurityGroups\0&gt;  ls
</codeblock>
<p>To delete an existing security group rule:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Remove-Rule "d7c57985-a471-4f1d-b9f4-0e741554124d"
</codeblock>
</section>
<section id="BasicServerOperations"> <title>Basic Server Operations</title>
<p><b>Note</b>: For all of these commands you have to use the server ID, rather than the server name.  Your first server will usually have an ID of <codeph>0</codeph> and then go up chronologically.</p>
<p>To list the currently-available servers:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; cd Servers
PS HPCS:\Servers&gt; ls
</codeblock>
<p>To create a new server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; New-Server -n "TestServer" -i "f981eab8-2a2b-53e1-b737-104a9959477a" -f "101" -sg "default" -md "Namevalue1 | value1" -k "KeyName"
</codeblock>
<p><b>Note</b>: Use <codeph>get-help New-Server -detailed</codeph> for details about the syntax of the command.</p>
<p>The example command above shows a new server with name <codeph>TestSever</codeph>, image identifier <codeph>f981eab8-2a2b-53e1-b737-104a9959477a</codeph>, flavor identifier<codeph>101</codeph>, security group name <codeph>default</codeph>, metadata name-value pair <codeph>Namevalue1 | value1</codeph>, and keypair <codeph>KeyName</codeph>.  This command supports specifying multiple security groups as well as specifying the network to assign to the instance if you have multiple networks.  See syntax for more details.</p>
<p>
<b>Note for Windows Images</b>: When the Powershell CLI detects you are creating a Windows server, it looks for the keypair <i>.pem</i> file in a specific location. The default location for the .pem file is <codeph>C:\Users\*username*\Documents\HP</codeph>. When the new-server operation has completed, the output is the Administrator password to be used with an RDP client. Please make note of it.</p>
To reset a password for an existing server:
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\> Reset-Password -id "0" -p "testpassword08"
</codeblock>
<p><b>Note</b>: This command doesn't physically reset the password on the server itself, just in the <codeph>CredentialList.xml</codeph> file in your <codeph>C:\Users\*username*\Documents\HP</codeph> directory that stores passwords locally for use in the CLI.</p>
<p>To update the name of an existing server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Update-Server -id "0" -n "NewName"
</codeblock>
<p>To reboot a server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Reboot-Server "0" "SOFT"
</codeblock>
<p>
<b>Note</b>: A <i>soft</i> reboot signals the operating system to restart, which allows for a graceful shutdown of all processes. A <i>hard</i> reboot is the equivalent of cycling power on the server.</p>
<p>To delete an existing server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Remove-Server "0"
</codeblock>
</section>
<section id="AdvancedServerOperations"> <title>Advanced Server Operations</title>
</section>
<section id="CreateanImageofaServer"> <title>Create an Image of a Server</title>
<p>To create an image from an existing server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; New-Image -s "0" -n "Image01"
</codeblock>
<p>Where <codeph>-s</codeph> designates the server ID, and <codeph>-n</codeph> designates the image name. Use the <codeph>ls</codeph> command in the Images directory to view your created images.</p>
<p>Creating an image of an active server produces a state 'snapshot' of the server and makes it available as an <codeph>Image</codeph>. After creation you can use that image to create a new server. You can find the new image id by viewing the <codeph>Images</codeph> directory.</p>
<p><b>Note for Windows Images</b>: For instances created from snapshots of Windows images, the Administrator password matches the Administrator password of the server the snapshot was taken from, even if you changed it from the original password.</p>
</section>
<section id="QuickConnectWin"> <title>Quick-Connect to an Instance</title>
<p>To perform a quick-connect to an existing server instance:</p>
<p>
<b>Note</b>: In order for the <codeph>connect-server</codeph> command to work, your keypair <i>.pem</i> file needs to be in the appropriate location. The default location is <codeph>C:\Users\*username*\Documents\HP</codeph>.</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt;  Connect-Server 0
</codeblock>
<p>This connects you to the server with the ID <codeph>0</codeph>.  You can also connect to a server by navigating to a server directory and entering the <codeph>Connect-Server</codeph> command with no arguments:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt;  cd Servers
PS HPCS:\Servers&gt; cd 0
PS HPCS:\Servers\2111&gt; Connect-Server
</codeblock>
</section>
<section id="QuickConnectNonWin"> <title>Quick-Connect to a Non-Windows Instance</title>
<p>To connect to a non-Windows instance, such as Linux, follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Download the latest version of <xref href="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html" scope="external" format="html" >putty.exe</xref> and <xref href="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html" scope="external" format="html" >puttygen.exe</xref> for Windows.</li>
<li>Make note of the location of your <i>putty.exe</i> and <i>puttygen.exe</i> files downloaded in step 1.</li>
<li>Open <i>puttygen.exe</i> and load the .pem key file used to create the non-windows instance. This file is located at <codeph>C:\Users\*user_name*\Documents\HP</codeph>.</li>
<li>Convert the .pem file to the .ppk format by selecting the <i>Save Private Key</i> action.</li>
<li>Save the .ppk file into the same directory as your orginal .pem file and give it the same name.</li>
<li>Launch the SSH session with the <codeph>Connect-Server</codeph> cmdlet. Example: <codeph>connect-server 12345</codeph> where 12345 is your instance ID.</li>
</ol>
<p>
<b>Note:</b> If this is the first time to use <codeph>connect-server</codeph> with a non-windows instance, the system will prompt for the location of your <i>putty.exe</i> file. Please provide the fully qualified UNC path. For example: <codeph>C:\Users\*user_name*\Downloads\putty.exe</codeph>. This location is stored in your config file located at <codeph>C:\Users\*user_name*\Documents\HP\CLI.config</codeph>.</p>
<p>
<b>Note:</b> If you use the same keypair name for another instance, you do not need to convert the key from .pem to .ppk again.</p>
</section>
<section id="PasswordManagement"> <title>Password Management</title>
</section>
<section id="GetPassword"> <title>Get-Password</title>
<p>To retrieve your password for your Windows instance:</p>
<p>
<b>Note:</b> This cmdlet is currently available for Windows instances only.</p>
<codeblock>
PS C:\Program Files (x86)\HP\HPCS-Powershell&gt; cd HPCS:
PS HPCS:\&gt; Get-Password -s 123456 -k "key_1"
Log detected!
Administrator Password : [+&amp;/}4CF6EJi
</codeblock>
<p>This retrieves the password for server ID <codeph>12345</codeph> that was created with keypair name <codeph>key_1</codeph>.</p>
<p>
<b>Note</b>: The WinCLI looks for the keypair <i>.pem</i> file in a specific location. The default location for the .pem file is <codeph>C:\Users\*username*\Documents\HP</codeph>.</p>
<p>To use the <codeph>Get-Password</codeph> command, all of the following must be true:</p>
<ul>
<li>The server must appear in the server list</li>
<li>The listing of the EventLog for the server (<codeph>PS HPCS:\Servers\server_id\EventLog</codeph>), must display the encrypted key</li>
<li>The server has never rebooted after initial creation.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="ResetPassword"> <title>Reset-Password</title>
<p>For Windows Instances only, if you change your Windows password manually via <xref href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/desktop/aa383015(v=vs.85).aspx" scope="external" format="html" >RDP</xref>, you need to manually sync the password with the Windows CLI with the <codeph>Reset-Password</codeph> cmdlet for the <codeph>connect-server</codeph> command to work. If you use the <codeph>get-password</codeph> cmdlet to fetch your original de-crypted Administrator password, and it's available, it will overwrite the password sync.</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\&gt; Reset-Password -id 1234 -p "Thisisalongpassword!"
</codeblock>
<p>This resets the password for server <codeph>1234</codeph> to  <codeph>Thisisalongpassword!</codeph>.</p>
</section>
<section id="IPManagement"> <title>Floating IP Management</title>
<p>These commands will be under the <codeph>Networks</codeph> section in the CLI.</p>
<p>Requests a new Floating IP and adds to your IP pool for assignment availability to a server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; New-FloatingIP
</codeblock>
<p>Performing an <codeph>ls</codeph> command on the <codeph>Network\FloatingIPs</codeph> directory shows your allocated IPs.</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\Networks\FloatingIPs&gt; ls

==========================================================================================================
The following FloatingIPs are available.
==========================================================================================================

#   Id                                         Floating IP          Network Id                                 Fixed IP        Port Id         RouterId
-   --                                         -----------          ----------                                 --------        -------         --------
0   279dea62-9f2f-45e2-95eb-cbafd809e6e5       15.126.141.4         7da74520-9d5e-427b-a508-213c84e69616       10.0.0.136      ee5becec-341... c4881d79-7be...
1   2d4eae6f-1f29-4f38-9616-1fc028b81f0c       15.126.141.27        7da74520-9d5e-427b-a508-213c84e69616       10.0.0.145      0408a733-3f0... c4881d79-7be...
2   41240b6e-a332-4270-9c53-dcd706a2728d       15.126.141.37        7da74520-9d5e-427b-a508-213c84e69616       10.0.0.146      efd8e216-699... c4881d79-7be...
3   475f0a38-c0b6-4b49-807a-f60a3e8d764d       15.126.141.41        7da74520-9d5e-427b-a508-213c84e69616
4   5e5bc54b-142f-46a6-8d24-22ae939d9fea       15.126.141.254       7da74520-9d5e-427b-a508-213c84e69616
</codeblock>
<p>To assign an allocated IP address to an existing server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Assign-IP -s 2344 -ip "192.168.110.45"
</codeblock>
<p>To unassign an IP address for a particular server:</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Unassign-IP -s 2344 -ip "192.168.110.45"
</codeblock>
<p>To de-allocate (release) a previously-allocated IP address out of your IP pool</p>
<codeblock>
PS HPCS:\\&gt; Deallocate-IP -ip 1391
</codeblock>
<p>Where <codeph>-ip</codeph> represents the ID of the allocated IP address.</p>
<p>For a complete list of all the available Compute commands, please see <xref href="../publiccloud/cli.windows.2.help.dita" >Getting Help</xref>.</p>
</section>
</body>
</topic>