<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic2833">
<title>What's New with the HPE Helion Public Cloud Console</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--PUBLISHED-->
 <!--./publiccloud/hz.whatsnewjan.2014.md-->
 <!--permalink: /publiccloud/whats_new_with_HP_Cloud_Console/--></p>
<p>The HPE Helion Public Cloud Console now includes the following features:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>
<xref type="section" href="#topic2833/Enhancedidentitymanagement">Enhanced identity management</xref>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<xref type="section" href="#topic2833/Networktopologyvisualization">Network topology visualization</xref>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<xref type="section" href="#topic2833/Crossregionobjectreplication">Cross-region object replication</xref>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<xref type="section" href="#topic2833/Moreobjectstorageuses">More object storage uses</xref>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<xref type="section" href="#topic2833/Otherimprovements">Other improvements</xref>
</p>
</li>
</ul>
<section id="Enhancedidentitymanagement"> <title>Enhanced identity management</title>
<p>Particularly attractive for administrators in the enterprise, HPE Helion Public Cloud provides more flexibility and options for managing roles, domains, users and groups in the new <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Horizon-based HPE Helion Public Cloud Console. Specifically, roles can now be assigned to groups of users, or domain administrators can be defined for managing domains and respective users. In addition, you can assign roles around the latest platform services.</p>
</section>
<section id="Networktopologyvisualization"> <title>Network topology visualization</title>
<p>The new Horizon-based HPE Helion Public Cloud Console inherits network topology infographics to graphically display your network, routers, and instances.  In addition to visualizing network relationships, you can perform dynamic network management, interactively creating networks and routers, and launching instances through a 2-D visualization scene. Hover over graphical network elements to see detailed information and access links to perform tasks on that element.</p>
</section>
<section id="Crossregionobjectreplication"> <title>Cross-region object replication</title>
<p>With the OpenStack Storage infrastructure as its foundation, HPE Helion Public Cloud Object Store (previously known as "Object Storage") allows you to store and retrieve objects in a highly redundant cluster of publicly accessible physical machines hosted in HPE data centers. In a new enhancement, you can now setup and control object storage container synchronization across multiple regions with Object Store in the HPE Helion Public Cloud Console. When you activate synchronization between two containers in different regions, you can store objects in and access objects from both simultaneously.</p>
</section>
<section id="Moreobjectstorageuses"> <title>More object storage uses</title>
<p>With the new functionality of cross-region replication, you can also construct a more dependable business continuity plan for disaster recovery options, which are often high priorities for enterprise organizations.  HPE Helion Public Cloud Console users can also store duplicate versions of content within cross-regional storage containers for restoration from unintended failures and deletions, or data archiving and other purposes.</p>
</section>
<section id="Otherimprovements"> <title>Other improvements</title>
<p>The 50MB file upload size limitation within the classic console is no longer an impedance with the new Horizon-based HPE Helion Public Cloud Console. You'll also notice more consumable UI and UX changes with your account management and invoice presentation.</p>
</section>
</body>
</topic>