<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic3393">
<title>HPE Helion Public Cloud Identity Service Overview</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--PUBLISHED-->
 <!--./publiccloud/identity.md-->
 <!--permalink: /publiccloud/identity/--></p>
<!--This is a comment. Comments are not displayed in the browser-->
<p>
  <image href="../media/identity_service_overview_0.png">
<alt/>
</image>
</p>
<p>Based on <xref href="http://keystone.openstack.org/" scope="external" format="html" >Keystone, the <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Identity Service</xref>, the HPE Helion Public Cloud Identity Service provides one-stop authentication for all HPE Helion Public Cloud offerings.  Key terms include:</p>
<dl>
<dlentry>
<dt>
<b>User</b>
</dt>
<dd>A digital representation of a person, system, or service who uses HPE Helion Public Cloud. The Identity Service validates that incoming requests are being made by the user who claims to be making the call. Users have a login and may be assigned tokens to access resources. Users can scope their authentication to a tenant which then limits where and how their tokens can be used to interact with services. Users are associated with tenants based on roles assigned to them with that tenant.</dd>
</dlentry>

<dlentry>
<dt>
<b>Credentials</b>
</dt>
<dd>Data that belongs to, is owned by, and generally only known by a user that the user can present to prove they are who they are (since nobody else should know that data).</dd>
</dlentry>


<dlentry>
<dt>
<b>Authentication</b>
</dt>
<dd>In the context of the Identity Service, the act of confirming the identity of a user or the truth of a claim. The Identity Service will confirm that incoming request are being made by the user who claims to be making the call by validating a set of claims that the user is making. These claims are initially in the form of a set of credentials (username &amp; password, or user access keys). After initial confirmation, the Identity Service will issue the user a token which the user can then provide to demonstrate that their identity has been authenticated when making subsequent requests.</dd>
</dlentry>


<dlentry>
<dt>
<b>Token</b>
</dt>
<dd>An arbitrary bit of text that is used to access resources. Each token has a scope which describes which resources are accessible with it.  While the Identity Service supports token-based authentication in this release, the intention is for it to support additional protocols in the future.</dd>
</dlentry>

<dlentry>
<dt>
<b>Tenant</b>
</dt>
<dd>A collection of HPE service subscriptions and/or resources (Compute, Object Storage, etc).</dd>
</dlentry>


<dlentry>
<dt>
<b>Endpoint</b>
</dt>
<dd>A network-accessible address, usually described by URL, where a service may be accessed.</dd>
</dlentry>


<dlentry>
<dt>
<b>Role</b>
</dt>
<dd>A personality that a user assumes when performing a specific set of operations. A role includes a set of rights and privileges. A user assuming that role inherits those rights and privileges.  A token that is issued to a user includes the list of roles that user can assume. Services that are being called by that user determine how they interpret the set of roles a user has and which operations or resources each roles grants access to.</dd>
</dlentry>

</dl>
<p>To jump right in and start using the service yourself, go to the <xref href="https://horizon.hpcloud.com/" scope="external" format="html" >HPE Helion Public Cloud Console</xref>.  If you have any questions, try our <xref href="https://community.hpcloud.com" scope="external" format="html" >Forums</xref> where you can learn from our own internal experts as well as other users in the HPE Helion Public Cloud community.</p>
<!-- To help you get started with the service, we've got some introductory getting started material at our [Introduction to the HPE Helion Public Cloud Identity Service page](https://community.hpcloud.com/article/identity-service-introduction), and we've also provided you with a use case for [Migrating to the HPE Helion Public Cloud Identity Service](https://community.hpcloud.com/article/identity-service-change-guide).  And of course, if you want to jump right and start using the service yourself, you should go to the [Manage Console](https://console.hpcloud.com).  If you have any questions, try our [Forums](https://community.hpcloud.com) where you can learn from our own internal experts as well as other users in the HPE Helion Public Cloud community.-->
<section id="api"> <title>API</title>
<p>Do you need low level, raw REST API access to HPE Identity Services?  Take a look at our Compute API page for the version of HPE Helion Public Cloud you are using:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<xref href="../publiccloud/api/keystonev2-api.dita" >
<b>Identity Service v2 API page</b>
</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref href="../publiccloud/api/keystone-api.dita" >
<b>Identity Service v3 API page</b>
</xref>
</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="bindings"> <title>Bindings</title>
<p>If you are looking for an easier to use, language-specific way of using HPE Identity Services, check out our <xref href="../publiccloud/bindings.dita" >Bindings section</xref>.</p>
</section>
<section id="cli"> <title>CLI</title>
<p>Want scriptable access you can put in a cron job or something similar?  Go on over to our <xref href="../publiccloud/cli.dita" >CLI documentation</xref>.</p>
</section>
</body>
</topic>
