<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_replicate_database">
  <title>Replicating a database</title>
  <body>
    <p>Replicating a database creates a slave for your instance that replicates every action on the master. Creating a database instance that is automatically replicated results in more durable data and can 
      prevent data loss in a disaster scenario.</p>
      <section id="db-prerequisites"> <title>Prerequisites</title>
        <p>To follow this guide, you must have already <xref type="internal" href="devplatform.database-create-horizon.dita#topic_create_database_horizon">created</xref> a database instance that will be the master database.</p>
      </section>
    <section id="steps"> <title>Steps</title>
      <ol>
        <li>Log in to the Horizon console.</li>
        <li>Under your project, open the <b>Database</b> panel and then click the <b>Instances</b>
          tab.<image href="../../../media/createDBinstance9.png" placement="break"/>
        </li>
        <li>Click <b>Launch Instance</b>.</li>
        <li>In the <b>Details</b> tab, specify the following options:
          
          <ul>
            <li>
              <b>Instance Name</b> - the name of the MySQL instance that will be the slave instance.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Flavor</b> - the size of the instance to host the slave database on.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Volume Size</b>- the size of the volume to host the data on (in GB). Note: this <b>cannot</b> be changed later. </li>
            <li>
              <b>Datastore</b> - the MySQL datastore version to create.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Availability Zone</b> (optional) - the availability zone that the database will be
              created in. For replication, it is important for this to be in a different
              availability zone than the master.<image href="../../../media/createDBinstance10.png"
                placement="break" scale="75"/></li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>Under the <b>Networking</b> tab, specify the network to associate the database instance with.
          This is required and should be the same network that any application that accesses the
          database is on.<image href="../../../media/createDBinstance11.png" placement="break"
            scale="75"/></li>
        <li>Click the <b>Advanced</b> tab and then use the <b>Replicate from Instance</b> drop-down to
          select the master instance to
          replicate.<!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><image
            href="../../../media/createDBinstance12.png" placement="break" scale="75"/>
        </li>
        <li>Click <b>Launch</b> to create the replica.<image href="../../../media/createDBinstance13.png"
          placement="break"/>
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
  <related-links>
    <link href="devplatform.database-instance.dita#DatabaseService"/>
    <link href="devplatform.database-create-horizon.dita#topic_create_database_horizon"/>
  </related-links>
</topic>
