<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic2065">
<title>HPE Helion 2.0 Development Platform: Connecting the Database Service with the Application Lifecycle Service</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HPE Helion Development Platform"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HPE Helion Development Platform 2.0"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Systems Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="System Engineer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Cloud Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Network Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="ISV Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Service Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Jayme P"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
    <p>If a more durable or scalable MySQL database service is needed, ensure your ALS cluster is
      configured to use a database instance or master/slave pair provided by the Database Service.
      This is an option at cluster create time.</p>
    <p><cite>ALS cluster create wizard </cite></p>
    <p>
      <image href="../../../media/databaseALS.png"/>
    </p>
    <section id="configure">
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <p>Alternatively, if the Database Service was not integrated with the cluster at the time of
        cluster creation, the administrator of the ALS cluster can switch from the unmanaged MySQL
        service to the managed Database Service using the following kato commands:</p>
      <ol>
        <li>Enable the root user on the database instance you want to join to the ALS cluster</li>
        <li>SSH to the ALS cluster instances and use the kato admin client. </li>
        <li>Set the endpoint details including hostname, port, root user, and
          password:<codeblock>kato config set mysql_node mysql/host 10.5.120.101
kato config set mysql_node mysql/port 3306
kato config set mysql_node mysql/user root
kato config set mysql_node mysql/pass CorrectHorseBatteryStaple</codeblock></li>
        <li>Increase the timeout settings to make the <xref href="http://code.macournoyer.com/thin/"
            scope="external" format="html">
            <i>thin</i>
          </xref> mysql_gateway connect reliably to the database instance. </li>
        <li>Run the following
          commands:<codeblock>kato config set mysql_node connection_wait_timeout 100
kato config set mysql_node keep_alive_interval 60</codeblock></li>
      </ol>
      <p>Application deployment does not change between the managed and unmanaged versions of the
        MySQL service. A developer connects to and interacts with the MySQL database in exactly the
        same way regardless of which service is used.</p>
      <p>The benefits of the unmanaged service include a lighter footprint (fewer virtual machines)
        and no dependency on the Database Service being configured and available. The managed
        service provides full lifecycle management and scalability; capabilities not found in the
        unmanaged service.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
