<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic5773">
<title>HP Helion 2.0 Development Platform: Using the Database Service</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Development Platform"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Development Platform 1.3"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Security Engineer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="ISV Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Service Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Jayme P"/>
<othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Development Platform"/>
<othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Development Platform 1.3"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>The database service provides lifecycle services for MySQL database instances. Lifecycle services include provisioning, configuration, patching, backups, restores, and monitoring that can be administered from either a CLI interface, RESTful APIs or the Horizon dashboard.</p>
<p>These instances can then be utilized by your applications to provide standard datastore/back-end functionality.</p>
<p>The following topics explain how to create and manage a database:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic5773/create">Create a database instance</xref>
</li>
<li>
        <xref href="#topic5773/backup" format="dita">Create a database
          backup</xref>
      </li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic5773/replicate">Replicate a database</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic5773/floatIP">Attach a Floating IP</xref>
</li>
</ul>
<section id="prerequisites"> <title>Prerequisites</title>
<ol>
<li>Install the <xref href="installation/devplatform_commercial_install.dita" >HP Helion Development Platform</xref>. </li>
<li>
          <xref href="installation/devplatform_install_database.dita" type="section" >Configure
            the database service</xref>.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="create"> <title>Creating a Database Instance</title>
<ol>
<li> Log into the Horizon console.<p>Under your project, open the Database panel and then click the
              <b>Instances</b> tab. <!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><image
              href="../../media/createDBinstance1.png" placement="break" id="image_yb1_mlp_ms"
          /></p></li>
<li> Click <b>Launch Instance</b>.</li>
<li> In the <b>Details</b> tab, specify the following options:<ul>
            <li>
              <b>Instance Name</b> - the name of the MySQL instance to create </li>
            <li>
              <b>Flavor</b> - the size of the instance to host the database on.<image
                href="../../media/createDBinstance2.png" placement="break" scale="75"/></li>
            <li>
              <b>Volume Size</b> - the size of the volume to host the data on (in GB). Note: this
                <b>cannot</b> be changed later.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Datastore</b> - the MySQL database version to create</li>
            <li>
              <b>Availability Zone</b> (optional) the availability zone that the database will be
              created in.<!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><image
                href="../../media/createDBinstance1.png" placement="break"/></li>
          </ul></li>
<li> Under the <b>Networking</b> tab, specify the network to associate the database instance with.
          This is required and should be the same network that any application that accesses the
          database is on. <image href="../../media/createDBinstance3.png" placement="break"
            id="image_dbb_ylp_ms"/>
        </li>
<li>Optional - Specify the initial database to create on the database instance. This option can be
          used to pre-populate the instance with a database and a user for that database. <image
            href="../../media/createDBinstance4.png" placement="break" scale="75"/></li>
<li>Click <b>Launch</b>.</li>
<li>In the <b>Database</b> tab, open the <b>Instances</b> panel. This panel displays the status of the newly created database instance. <!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><image href="../../media/createDBinstance5.png" placement="break"/>
</li>
<li>Once the database instance has reached <b>Active</b> status, the instance is ready to use.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="backup"> <title>Creating a Database Backup </title>
<p>The following section will demonstrate how to back up an existing database instance. This will take a backup of the entire database instance. If necessary, the backup can be restored to a new instance at a later time.</p>
<ol>
<li>Log in to the Horizon console.</li>
<li>Under your project, open the <b>Database</b> panel and then click the <b>Instances</b> tab.</li>
<li>A list of active database instances will be displayed. Identify the database instance to back up
          and click <b>Create Backup</b> next to that
            instance.<!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><image
            href="../../media/createDBinstance6.png" placement="break"/></li>
<li>In the <b>Backup Database</b> dialog, specify the following information:

<ul>
<li>
<b>Name</b> - the name of the backup to create. This name will help you identify the backup in the future.</li>
<li>
<b>Database Instance</b> - The database instance that will be backed up.</li>
<li>
<b>Description</b> - a text description of the backup (optional).</li>
<li>
              <b>Parent Backup</b> - if a previous backup of this database instance exists. it is
              possible to take an incremental backup. An incremental backup will process faster
              because it only stores the differences between the two. Select the previous backup if
              an incremental backup is desired.<image href="../../media/createDBinstance7.png"
                placement="break" scale="75"/></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Click <b>Backup</b>.</li>
<li>In the <b>Database</b> panel, click the <b>Backups</b> tab to view all existing backups,
          including the newly-created
            backup.<!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><image
            href="../../media/createDBinstance8.png" placement="break"/></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="replicate"> <title>Replicating a Database</title>
<p>Replicating a database creates a slave for your instance that replicates every action on the master. Creating a database instance that is automatically replicated results in more durable data and can prevent data loss in a disaster scenario.</p>
</section>
<section id="db-prerequisites"> <title>Prerequisites</title>
<p>To follow this guide, you must have already <xref type="section" href="#topic5773/create">created</xref> a database instance that will be the master database.</p>
</section>
<section id="steps"> <title>Steps</title>
<ol>
<li>Log in to the Horizon console.</li>
<li>Under your project, open the <b>Database</b> panel and then click the <b>Instances</b>
            tab.<image href="../../media/createDBinstance9.png" placement="break"/>
        </li>
<li>Click <b>Launch Instance</b>.</li>
<li>In the <b>Details</b> tab, specify the following options:

<ul>
<li>
<b>Instance Name</b> - the name of the MySQL instance that will be the slave instance.</li>
<li>
<b>Flavor</b> - the size of the instance to host the slave database on.</li>
<li>
<b>Volume Size</b>- the size of the volume to host the data on (in GB). Note: this <b>cannot</b> be changed later. </li>
<li>
<b>Datastore</b> - the MySQL datastore version to create.</li>
<li>
              <b>Availability Zone</b> (optional) - the availability zone that the database will be
              created in. For replication, it is important for this to be in a different
              availability zone than the master.<image href="../../media/createDBinstance10.png"
                placement="break" scale="75"/></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Under the <b>Networking</b> tab, specify the network to associate the database instance with.
          This is required and should be the same network that any application that accesses the
          database is on.<image href="../../media/createDBinstance11.png" placement="break"
            scale="75"/></li>
<li>Click the <b>Advanced</b> tab and then use the <b>Replicate from Instance</b> drop-down to
          select the master instance to
            replicate.<!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><image
            href="../../media/createDBinstance12.png" placement="break" scale="75"/>
        </li>
<li>Click <b>Launch</b> to create the replica.<image href="../../media/createDBinstance13.png"
            placement="break"/>
        </li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="floatIP"> <title>Attaching a Floating IP to the Database Instance</title>
<p>It is possible to attach a floating IP address to a database instance - this will make it possible to access your instance from outside of your cloud environment.</p>
<p>To create a database with a floating IP address follow these steps from the command line. Note the following instructions require that you use the Trove CLI to create a database instance.</p>
<p>For more information on using the Trove CLI, refer to the <xref type="section" href="#topic5773/more">More Resources</xref> section at the end of this guide.</p>
<ol>
<li> Pre-provision a port on the network that the instance will be attached to using the neutron
          CLI. Note down the port-id of the port
          created:<codeblock>$ neutron port-create &lt;network-id&gt;</codeblock></li>
<li> When creating the Trove instance, pass in the <codeph>port id </codeph>as the
            <codeph>nic</codeph>
          parameter:<codeblock>$ trove create &lt;name&gt; &lt;flavor-id&gt; --size &lt;size&gt; --nic port-id=&lt;port-id&gt;</codeblock></li>
<li> Create a Floating IP using neutron and attach it to the port provisioned in step
          1:<codeblock>$ neutron floatingip-create &lt;floating-network&gt;
$ neutron floatingip-associate &lt;floating-ip-id&gt; &lt;port-id&gt;</codeblock></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="more"> <title>More Resources</title>
<ul>
<li>More information on <xref href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/trove/" scope="external" format="html" >Trove</xref>.</li>
<li>More information on <xref href="https://community.hpcloud.com/article/creating-and-configuring-database-instance" scope="external" format="html" >using the Trove CLI</xref> to create a database instance.</li>
</ul>
</section>
</body>
</topic>
