<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_odg_33x_rt">
  <title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> 2.0: Networking Solution for ESXi Hypervisor</title>
  <body><!--Needs Edit-->
    <p>To provide the <b>network as a service</b> for tenant VM's hosted on ESXi Hypervisor, a
      service VM named OVSvApp VM is deployed on each ESXi Hypervisor within a cluster managed by
      OpenStack Nova as shown in the following figure. </p>
    <p><image href="../../media/esx/esx_ovsvapp.png" id="image_a4n_t3x_rt"/></p>
    <p>  The OVSvApp VM runs hlinux as a guest Operating System and has Open vSwitch 2.1.0 or above
      installed. It also runs the agent called OVSvApp agent which is responsible for dynamically
      creating the port groups for the tenant VM’s and manages OVS bridges which contains the flows
      related to security groups and L2 networking.</p>
    <p>The OVSvApp VM will be orchestrated using EON. For more detail information  on EON service,
      refer to <xref href="eon_service.dita#topic_x2x_vy4_lt"/>.</p>
    <p>In order to facilitate Fault Tolerance and mitigation of data path loss for tenant VM’s, run
      the process named <b>neutron-ovsvapp-agent-montior</b> as part of <b>neutron-ovsvapp-agent
        service</b>  which is responsible for monitoring Open vSwitch module within the OVSvApp VM.
      It also uses <codeph>nginx</codeph> server to inform health status of Open vSwitch module to
      the neutron server for mitigation actions. There is a mechanism to keep alive the
        <b>neutron-ovsvapp-agent service</b> through  <codeph>systemd</codeph> script.</p>
    <p>When OVSvApp Service VM crashes, agent monitoring mechanism kick in a ‘cluster mitigation’
      process. You can mitigate data path traffic loss for VMs on the failed ESX host in that
      cluster by putting the failed ESX host in the maintenance mode; which in turn triggers the
      vCenter DRS migrates tenant VMs to other ESX hosts within the same cluster . This ensures data
      path continuity of tenant VM’s traffic. </p>
    <section><b>View cluster migration</b></section>
    <p>An admin can view the cluster mitigation status using the following CLIs.<ol
        id="ol_cmz_fjx_rt">
        <li><codeph>neutron ovsvapp-mitigated-cluster-list</codeph><p>Lists all those clusters where
            at least one round of host mitigation has happened.</p><p>Example:</p><p>
            <codeblock>neutron ovsvapp-mitigated-cluster-list
+----------------+--------------+-----------------------+---------------------------+
| vcenter_id     | cluster_id   | being_mitigated       | threshold_reached         |
+----------------+--------------+-----------------------+---------------------------+
| vcenter1       | cluster1     | True                  | False                     |
| vcenter2       | cluster2     | False                 | True                      |
+---------------+------------+-----------------+------------------------------------+</codeblock>
          </p></li>
        <li><codeph>neutron ovsvapp-mitigated-cluster-show --vcenter-id &lt;VCENTER_ID> --cluster-id
            &lt;CLUSTER_ID></codeph>
          <p> Shows the status of the particular cluster. </p><p>Example
            :<codeblock>neutron ovsvapp-mitigated-cluster-show --vcenter-id vcenter1 --cluster-id cluster1
+---------------------------+-------------+
| Field                     | Value       |
+---------------------------+-------------+
| being_mitigated           | True        |
| cluster_id                | cluster1    |
| threshold_reached         | False       |
| vcenter_id                | vcenter1    |
+---------------------------+-------------+</codeblock></p><p>There
            can be instances where a triggered mitigation may not succeed and the neutron server is
            not informed of such failure. For example:  if the selected agent which had to mitigate
            the host, goes down before finishing the task. In this case, the cluster will be locked.
            To unlock the cluster for further mitigations, use the update CLI.</p></li>
        <li><codeph>neutron ovsvapp-mitigated-cluster-update --vcenter-id &lt;VCENTER_ID>
            --cluster-id &lt;CLUSTER_ID></codeph><ul id="ul_kyn_qlp_st">
            <li>Update the status of a mitigated cluster. <p>Modify the values of
                  <b>being-mitigated</b> from <b>True</b> to <b>False</b> to unlock the
                cluster.</p><p>Example:
                <codeblock>neutron ovsvapp-mitigated-cluster-update --vcenter-id vcenter1 --cluster-id cluster1 --being-mitigated False</codeblock></p></li>
            <li>Update the threshold value<p>Update the threshold-reached value to <b>True</b>, if
                no further migration is required in the selected cluster.</p><p>Example :
                <codeblock>neutron ovsvapp-mitigated-cluster-update --vcenter-id vcenter1 --cluster-id cluster1 --being-mitigated False --threshold-reached True</codeblock></p></li>
          </ul><p>Rest API</p><ul id="ul_rkp_4kx_rt">
            <li>curl -i -X GET <xref href="http://%3cip%3e:9696/v2.0/ovsvapp_mitigated_clusters"
                format="html" scope="external"
                >http://&lt;ip&gt;:9696/v2.0/ovsvapp_mitigated_clusters</xref> -H "User-Agent:
              python-neutronclient" -H "Accept: application/json" -H "X-Auth-Token:
              &lt;token_id&gt;"  (<b>unable to understand this section?? )</b>
            </li>
          </ul></li>
      </ol></p>
  </body>
</topic>
