<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1410638776646" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">The Bridging Scenario</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The Bridging Scenario implements a Layer 2 test path using either Linux
    or DPDK-accelerated virtual bridges.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Michael B</author>
    <author ixia_locid="116">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
    <p ixia_locid="5"> The Bridging Scenario topology is illustrated in the following figure. The
      test path is shown as a red dotted line.</p>
    <fig id="sample-app-overview" ixia_locid="19">
      <title ixia_locid="20">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Deployment Scenarios for Bridging</title>
      <image href="jow1408980668760.image" id="image_fg1_rqf_fp" ixia_locid="112" placement="inline" width="5in"/>
    </fig>
    <p ixia_locid="7">Two end users, <nameliteral ixia_locid="8">user1</nameliteral> and
        <nameliteral ixia_locid="9">user2</nameliteral>, each launch an instance of the example
      guest image inside a virtual machine, deployed within the domain of corresponding tenants,
        <nameliteral ixia_locid="10">tenant1</nameliteral> and <nameliteral ixia_locid="11">tenant2</nameliteral>. Inside each instance, a user application creates a bridge
      dynamically configured to operate in one of two modes:</p>
    <ul id="ol_f3v_vhq_mn">
      <li ixia_locid="106">
        <p ixia_locid="108">Layer 2 bridging in the Linux kernel</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="16">
        <p ixia_locid="17">Layer 2 bridging using an Intel DPDK-accelerated virtual switch</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p ixia_locid="18">The selected mode of operation is passed to the instance using OpenStack user
      data.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="113">To demonstrate the performance optimizations offered by the AVP and AVS
      features of the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, the network interfaces in the test path use AVP network
      drivers in combination with the Linux or DPDK-accelerated bridging. You can also use standard
      Linux virtio network drivers in combination with standard Linux-kernel Layer 2 bridging, but
      this will yield poorer performance.</p>
    <note id="note_N10076_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="114">
      <p ixia_locid="115">To highlight DPDK and AVP performance without additional Layer 3 routing or application
        overhead, the Bridging Scenario uses a VM to bridge two tenant networks. This configuration
        can cause Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) failures in Layer 2 switches connected to the
        networks. Disabling STP on the switches, or on the bridged tenant network VLANs, is
        recommended.</p>
    </note>
  </conbody>
</concept-wr>