<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1411435660602" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="185">Networks Used in the Deployment Scenarios</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="186">Each virtual machine is attached to three networks.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="187">Michael B</author>
  <author ixia_locid="189">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <dl>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="23">
    <dt ixia_locid="24">Private tenant network (<nameliteral ixia_locid="25">tenant1-net</nameliteral> or <nameliteral ixia_locid="26">tenant2-net)</nameliteral></dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="27">
     <p ixia_locid="30">These networks are created by the end users for private use. They can be
      used to connect the virtual machines to testing equipment.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="38">
    <dt ixia_locid="39">Internal network (<nameliteral ixia_locid="40">internal</nameliteral>)</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="41">
     <p ixia_locid="42">This network is created by the system administrator and shared by the
      tenants. It provides network connectivity between the two private tenant networks.</p>
     <p ixia_locid="174">The private tenant networks and the internal network illustrate the use of
      high-performance tenant networking on the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade platform. Each virtual machine
      provides a Layer 2 or Layer 3 switched path to link the tenant's private network and the
      internal network.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="31">
    <dt ixia_locid="32">Management network (<nameliteral ixia_locid="33">tenant1-mgmt-net</nameliteral> and <nameliteral ixia_locid="34">tenant2-mgmt-net)</nameliteral></dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="35">
     <p ixia_locid="175">These networks are created by the system administrator on behalf of the end
      users. Each management network connects using a virtual router to a shared external network
      owned by the system administrator. The shared external network provides access to other
      networks, including the open Internet, as needed. </p>
     <p ixia_locid="177">The management network illustrates how to configure an access network for
      managing instances. For example, it can be used to provide provisioning access over an
      Internet connection to a router application running on a virtual machine.</p>
     <note id="note_N10082_N1006F_N1005D_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="188">
      <p ixia_locid="178">The management network, in combination with a virtual router, also
       provides connectivity between the virtual machine and platform services running on compute
       nodes. In particular, it enables communication with the OpenStack metadata server, which
       provides access to instance-specific data (<term ixia_locid="179">user data</term>) when an
       instance is started.</p>
     </note>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>