<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic12031">
<title><b>Beta 0 What's In The Build</b></title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack 2.0"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Systems Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Cloud Architect"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Storage Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Network Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Service Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Cloud Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Network Engineer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Joel B"/>
<othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Openstack 2.0"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
  <note>This document is under development.</note>
<p>HP Helion OpenStack is a commercial-grade distribution of OpenStack the leading open source cloud computing platform. This distribution, backed by HP, enables customers to more easily build, manage, and use open-source based hybrid clouds in a resilient, maintainable platform. HP Helion OpenStack enables cost-effective scalability of IT services and business agility and, as part of the HP Helion portfolio, it is backed by a wide range of related cloud products, services, and professional support.</p>
<p>In the Helion OpenStack 2.0 release, these are the features you can expect:</p>

<section id="OpenStackServices"> <title>HP Helion OpenStack Services</title>
<ul>
<li>Full set of Kilo-based OpenStack services</li>
<li>LBaaS (Load-Balancing-as-a-Service) is a Neutron extension that introduces a load balancing feature set. Helion OpenStack 2.0 includes the V2 version which allows implementation uses haproxy but 3rd party Load Balancers can be integrated as well. In case that a 3rd party driver doesn’t exist for LBaaS V2 installing LBaaS V1 instead of V2 is supported.
<ul>
<li>For more information, see: <xref href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/LBaaS" scope="external" format="html">https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/LBaaS</xref></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>FWaaS (FireWall-as-a-Service) is a Neutron extension that introduces a firewall eature set. The included reference implementation is using iptables to block traffic but 3rd party Firewalls can be integrated with this extension into Helion OpenStack as well.
<ul>
<li>For more information, see: <xref href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/FWaaS" scope="external" format="html">https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/FWaaS</xref></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>VPNaaS (Virtual-Private-Network-as-a-Service) is a Neutron extension that introduces a vpn feature set. It allows for encrypted traffic between two routers in (potentially) different datacenters hence supporting secure multi Availability Zone architectures for customers.
<ul>
<li>For more information, see: <xref href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/VPNaaS" scope="external" format="html">https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/VPNaaS</xref></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="BaremetalInstall"> <title>Baremetal Install Kit</title>
  <ul>
    <li>Uses Config Process v2.0</li>
    <li>updating the configuration</li>
    <li>adding nodes</li>
    <li>adding VSA, etc</li>
  </ul>
</section>
<section id="Networking">
      <title>Network Planning</title>
  <ul>
    <li>NIC bonding: Helion OpenStack 2.0 has native support for NIC bonding.</li>
    <li>Multi-NIC support</li>
    <li>Network separation (including VLAN)</li>
  </ul>
</section>
  <section id="OpsManagement">
    <title>Operational Management</title>
<ul>
  <li>Control Plane Backup and Restore: Allows you to backup and recover your Helion OpenStack environment with RPO=0.</li>
  <li>Monitoring</li>
  <li>OpsConsole: The HP Helion OpenStack OpsConsole provides a graphical user interface (GUI) that allows you to interact and manage your Monitoring setup.</li>
</ul>
</section>
  <section id="OtherFeatures"><title>Other Features</title>
    <ul>
  <li>VSA as a Cinder block storage provider</li>
  <li>Basic NTP and DNS integration</li>
  <li>TLS only on external API</li>
    </ul>
  </section>
  </body>
</topic>
