<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1414074190480" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Managing Controller Nodes</title>
    <shortdesc>You can replace controller nodes or disks while the system is
        running.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p>The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade system uses exactly two controllers; you cannot
                add or remove a controller. However, you can replace the primary or secondary disks,
                and you can replace faulty controller nodes.</p>
            <note id="note_N1002C_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
                <p>If you are replacing disks in order to increase the controller
                    storage capacity, follow the instructions for <xref href="jow1413727075983.xml"/>.</p>
            </note>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>Lock the standby controller.</li>
                
                    <p>Open the <b>Hosts</b> list by
                        clicking <b>Inventory</b> on the<b> System Panel</b> section of the <b>Admin</b> menu, and then selecting the <b>Hosts</b> tab.</p>
                    <p>Click <menucascade>
                            <b>More</b>
                            <b>Lock Host</b>
                        </menucascade> for the controller. </p>
                    <p>Wait for the procedure to be completed.</p>
                
            
             
                <li>Power down the standby controller and make any required
                    hardware changes.</li>
                
                    <p>This may involve replacing disks, or replacing the host
                        completely. </p>
                
            
             
                <li>Place the new or modified controller into service.</li>
                <info/>
                 <ol>
                    
                        <li>Power up the controller.</li>
                        
                            <p>Wait until the controller is reported as
                                    <codeph>Locked</codeph>, <codeph>Enabled</codeph>, and <codeph>Available</codeph>.</p>
                        
                    
                    
                        <li>If required, reinstall the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software on the
                            controller.</li>
                        
                            <p>If you are making disk changes to increase storage
                                capacity, you must re-install the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software. For more
                                information, see <xref href="jow1413727075983.xml"/>.</p>
                            <p>To reinstall the software on a host , click
                                    <menucascade>
                                    <b>More</b>
                                    <b>Reinstall</b>
                                </menucascade>.</p>
                            <note conref="rst1432737677834.xml#rst1432737677834/note_N10195_N10154_N1001F_N10001" id="note_N10195_N10154_N1001F_N10001"/>                            
                            <p>Wait for the host to be reported as <codeph>Locked</codeph>, <codeph>Disabled</codeph>, and <codeph>Online</codeph>.</p>
                        
                    
                    
                        <li>Perform a swact.</li>
                        
                            <p>Click <menucascade>
                                    <b>More</b>
                                    <b>Swact Host</b>
                                </menucascade> for the active controller.</p>
                        
                        
                            <p>The standby controller becomes the active controller, and the
                                original active controller is placed into standby.</p>
                        
                    
                </ol>
            
             
                <li>Lock the original active controller (now in standby).</li>
                
                    <p>Open the <b>Hosts</b> list by
                        clicking <b>Inventory</b> on the<b> System Panel</b> section of the <b>Admin</b> menu, and then selecting the <b>Hosts</b> tab.</p>
                    <p>Click <menucascade>
                            <b>More</b>
                            <b>Lock Host</b>
                        </menucascade> for the controller. </p>
                    <p>Wait for the procedure to be completed.</p>
                
            
             
                <li>Power down the controller and make the same hardware
                    changes.</li>
                
                    <note id="note_N1002F_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" type="caution">
                        <p>The configurations for controller-0 and controller-1,
                            including disk types and sizes, must be identical.</p>
                    </note>
                
            
             
                <li>Power up the new or modified controller.</li>
            
             
                <li>If required, reinstall the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software on the controller.</li>
            
        </ol>
        Host
            <p>The updated controllers are now in service.  The controller that was formerly active
                is now the standby controller. </p>
        
    </body>
</topic>