<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1443470081421" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title>Instances Logical Volume Considerations</title>
 <shortdesc>On compute nodes that use local storage, dedicated space is required by
    the <nameliteral>nova</nameliteral> service.</shortdesc>
 <prolog><author/>
  <author/>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p><draft-comment author="jowens"> US65502 new
        topic</draft-comment>The space is needed to store files that track each launched instance,
      and to cache boot images for boot-by-image VMs. Boot images are always cached in RAW format;
      Glance images formatted as QCOW2 are expanded to RAW format. The use of a cache speeds up
      instance launch, because the image does not need to be fetched from the Glance image
      store.</p>
    <p>In HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, the space is called the <term>instances
        logical volume</term> or <nameliteral>Instances LV</nameliteral> space. To
      provide for scalability, it is located on the <nameliteral>nova-local</nameliteral> local volume group instead of the root partition.</p>
  <p>By default, no size is specified. The minimum required space is 2 GB for a
      volume group with a total size less that 80 GB, and 5 GB for a volume group larger than 80 GB;
      you must specify at least this amount. You can allocate more to support the anticipated number
      of boot-from-image VMs, up to 50% of the maximum available storage for the local volume group.
      At least 50% free space in the volume group is required to provide space for allocating
      logical volume disks for launched instances. The value provided for the <uicontrol>Instance LV Size</uicontrol> is limited by this maximum.</p>
  <p>Instructions for allocating the <uicontrol>Instances LV
    Size</uicontrol> using the web administration interface are included in <xref href="jow1426183480976.xml"/>. To allocate space using the CLI, use the
    <cmdname>system host-lvg-modify</cmdname> command.</p>
  <note id="note_N10059_N10022_N1001F_N10001" type="caution">
   <p>If less than the minimum required space is available, the compute host cannot
    be unlocked.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>