<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="jow1425236666266" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title id="1">Configuring the NUMA Node Allocations for a VM</title>
    <shortdesc id="2">You can use flavor extra specs or image properties to allocate virtual
        memory and vCPU resources to virtual NUMA nodes.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author id="3">Jim Owens</author>
    </prolog>
    <taskbody>
        <context id="context_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" id="4">
            <p id="5">By default, the memory and CPU resources defined for a flavor are
                assigned to a single virtual NUMA node, which is mapped to an available host NUMA
                node when an instance is launched or migrated. You can specify the use of multiple
                NUMA nodes using either flavor extra specifications (which take the general form
                    <nameliteral id="93">hw:specification</nameliteral>), or image properties (which take
                the general form <nameliteral id="94">hw_specification</nameliteral>).</p>
            <p id="6">By default, the available CPU and memory resources for the flavor are
                distributed equally among the NUMA nodes. You can customize the distribution of
                resources. For example, given a flavor with two NUMA nodes, three vCPUs, and 1024 MB
                of RAM, you can assign one vCPU and 512 MB to virtual NUMA node 0, and two VCPUs and
                512 MB to virtual NUMA node 1. The ability to allocate resources is useful when
                pinning virtual NUMA nodes to host NUMA nodes to optimize VM performance.</p>
            <p id="77">By default, the memory required for a virtual NUMA node is pinned to a single host
                NUMA node to ensure high performance. For applications where this is not a concern,
                you can relax the memory allocation requirements so that the memory for a virtual
                NUMA node can be drawn from more than one host NUMA node if necessary.</p>
            <p id="261">When deploying network guest images operating on the data path, it
                is advisable to co-locate the virtual machines, the AVS switch, physical ports, and
                all other networking elements on the same node.</p>
            <p id="262">Use of this option should be limited to cases where fine-tuning of
                the data path on guest applications is important.</p>
            <note id="note_N10055_N10022_N1001F_N10001" id="264" type="caution">
                <p id="265">If the virtual CPUs cannot be allocated to run on the specified node on any
                    compute node, the virtual machine may fail to launch</p>
            </note>
        </context>
        <steps id="steps_q4v_blj_gr">
            <step id="step_N10038_N10034_N1001F_N10001" id="8">
                <cmd id="9">Declare the number of NUMA nodes to expose to the guest.</cmd>
                <info id="10">
                    <p id="11">The following extra specification sets the number of NUMA
                        nodes:</p>
                    <codeblock id="12">hw:numa_nodes=<varname id="13">n</varname></codeblock>
                    <p id="14">where <varname id="15">n</varname> is the number of NUMA nodes to expose (1 or
                        more).</p>
                </info>
                <stepxmp id="16">
                    <p id="320">For example, given the flavor <nameliteral id="18">numa.pinned.asym</nameliteral>, use the following command to expose two
                        NUMA nodes.</p>
                    <codeblock id="95"><systemoutput id="97">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput id="99">nova flavor-key numa.pinned.asym set hw:numa_nodes=2</userinput></codeblock>
                </stepxmp>
                <info id="101">
                    <p id="102">To set an image property instead, you can use the following command:</p>
                    <codeblock id="96"><systemoutput id="98">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput id="100">nova image-meta <varname id="103">image</varname> hw_numa_nodes=2</userinput></codeblock>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step id="step_N1006D_N10034_N1001F_N10001" importance="optional" id="22">
                <cmd id="23">For each NUMA node, assign a list of CPUs.</cmd>
                <info id="24">
                    <p id="25">This step is optional. By default, available CPUs for the
                        flavor are distributed evenly across the available NUMA nodes.</p>
                    <p id="26">The following extra specification assigns CPUs to a NUMA node:</p>
                    <codeblock id="27">hw:numa_cpus.<varname id="28">vnode_id</varname>=<varname id="29">cpu_list</varname></codeblock>
                    <p id="30">where</p>
                    <parml>
                        <plentry id="31">
                            <pt id="32"><parmname id="33">vnode_id</parmname></pt>
                            <pd id="34">
                                <p id="35">is the number used to identify the virtual NUMA
                                    node (0 for the first node, 1 for the second, and so on).</p>
                            </pd>
                        </plentry>
                        <plentry id="36">
                            <pt id="37"><parmname id="38">cpu_list</parmname></pt>
                            <pd id="39">
                                <p id="40">is a comma-separated list of vCPUs to assign to the node. The
                                    vCPUs for the flavor are enumerated beginning with 0.</p>
                            </pd>
                        </plentry>
                    </parml>
                </info>
                <stepxmp id="41">
                    <p id="263">For example, given flavor <nameliteral id="43">numa.pinned.asym</nameliteral>, use the following command to assign
                        vCPU 0 to the first NUMA node, and vCPUs 1 and 2 to the second NUMA
                        node:</p>
                    <codeblock id="44"><systemoutput id="45">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput id="46">nova flavor-key numa.pinned.asym set hw:numa_cpus.0=0 \
hw:numa_cpus.1=1,2</userinput></codeblock>
                </stepxmp>
            </step>
            <step id="step_N100CF_N10034_N1001F_N10001" importance="optional" id="47">
                <cmd id="48">For each NUMA node, assign an amount of memory.</cmd>
                <info id="49">
                    <p id="50">This step is optional. By default, available memory for the
                        flavor is distributed evenly across the available NUMA nodes.</p>
                    <p id="51">The following extra specification assigns memory to a NUMA node:</p>
                    <codeblock id="78">hw:numa_mem.<varname id="80">vnode_id</varname>=<varname id="54">ram_size</varname></codeblock>
                    <p id="55">where</p>
                    <parml>
                        <plentry id="56">
                            <pt id="57"><parmname id="58">vnode_id</parmname></pt>
                            <pd id="59">
                                <p id="60">is the number used to identify the virtual NUMA
                                    node (0 for the first node, 1 for the second, and so on).</p>
                            </pd>
                        </plentry>
                        <plentry id="61">
                            <pt id="62"><parmname id="63">ram_size</parmname></pt>
                            <pd id="64">
                                <p id="65">is the amount of RAM in MB.</p>
                            </pd>
                        </plentry>
                    </parml>
                </info>
                <stepxmp id="66">
                    <p id="67">For example, given flavor <nameliteral id="68">numa.pinned.asym</nameliteral>, use the following command to assign 512
                        MB of RAM to each of two NUMA nodes:</p>
                    <codeblock id="69"><systemoutput id="70">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput id="71">nova flavor-key numa.pinned.asym set hw:numa_mem.0=512 \
hw:numa_mem.1=512</userinput></codeblock>
                </stepxmp>
            </step>
            <step id="step_N10181_N10044_N1001F_N10001" importance="optional" id="82">
                <cmd id="83">Specify whether memory for the flavor can be drawn from more than one NUMA node
                    if necessary. </cmd>
                <info id="84">
                    <p id="90">This step is optional. By default, memory is allocated from the designated
                        host NUMA node only.</p>
                    <p id="85">To control whether memory for the flavor can be drawn from more than one host
                        NUMA node, use the following extra specification:</p>
                    <codeblock id="79">hw:numa_mempolicy=<varname id="81">policy</varname></codeblock>
                    <p id="86">where <parmname id="87">policy</parmname> is either
                            <nameliteral id="88">strict</nameliteral> (to use only memory
                        from the designated host NUMA node) or <nameliteral id="89">preferred</nameliteral> (to permit memory from other host NUMA nodes to
                        be used if necessary).</p>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <postreq id="postreq_N1012F_N1001F_N10001" id="72">
            <p id="73">To pin the virtual NUMA nodes to host NUMA nodes, see <xref href="jow1425236723556.xml" id="74"/>.</p>
        </postreq>
    </taskbody>
</task-wr>