<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1423169316542" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title>Ethernet Interface Configuration</title>
 <shortdesc>You can review and modify the configuration for physical or virtual
  Ethernet interfaces using the web administration interface or the CLI.</shortdesc>
 <prolog><author/>
  <author/>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <section id="section_N1001F_N1001C_N10001">
   <title>Physical Ethernet Interfaces</title>
   <p>The physical Ethernet interfaces on HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade nodes are configured to
    use the following networks: </p>
   <ul id="ul_lk1_b4j_zq">
    <li>
     <p>the internal management network</p>
    </li>
    <li>
     <p>the external OAM network</p>
    </li>
    <li>
     <p>the infrastructure network, if present</p>
    </li>
    <li>
     <p>one or more data networks</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
   <p>A single interface can optionally be configured to support more than one
    network using VLAN tagging (see <xref href="jow1423173019489.xml"/>). In
    addition, the management or infrastructure interfaces, or both, can be configured with an
    additional data network (see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation
     Guide: Editing Interface Settings</cite>).</p>
   <p>On the controller nodes, all Ethernet interfaces are configured automatically
    when the nodes are initialized, based on the information provided in the controller
    configuration script (see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Installation Guide: The
     Controller Configuration Script</cite>). On compute nodes, the Ethernet interfaces
    for the management network are configured automatically. The remaining interfaces require manual
    configuration. Interface configurations are summarized in the following table.</p>
   <note id="note_N10071_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
    <p> If a network attachment uses LAG, the corresponding interfaces on the
     storage and compute nodes must also be configured manually to specify the interface type.</p>
   </note>
   <table frame="all" id="table_xs4_npp_zq">
    <title>Interface Configuration by Network Type</title>
    <tgroup cols="3">
     <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.02*"/>
     <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.04*"/>
     <colspec colname="c4" colnum="3" colwidth="1.02*"/>
     <thead>
      <row>
       <entry/>
       <entry>
        <p>Controller</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Compute</p>
       </entry>
      </row>
     </thead>
     <tbody>
      <row>
       <entry>
        <p>Mgmt</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Configured automatically</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Configured automatically</p>
       </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
       <entry>
        <p>OAM</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Configured automatically</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Not used</p>
       </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
       <entry>
        <p>Infra</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Configured automatically</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Configured manually</p>
       </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
       <entry>
        <p>Data</p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Not used </p>
       </entry>
       <entry>
        <p>Configured manually</p>
       </entry>
      </row>
     </tbody>
    </tgroup>
   </table>
   <p>You can review and modify physical interface configurations from the web
    administration interface or the CLI. For more information, see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Installation Guide: Editing Interface Settings</cite>, the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Installation Guide: Creating Data Interfaces</cite>, and the
     <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Installation Guide: Command-line Installation</cite>.</p>
   <p>You can also save the interface configurations for a particular node to use as
    a <i>profile</i> or template when setting up other nodes. For more information,
    see <xref href="jow1404333777760.xml"/>.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N10059_N1001C_N10001">
   <title>Virtual Ethernet Interfaces</title>
   <p>The virtual Ethernet interfaces for guest VMs running on HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade are
    defined when an instance is launched. They connect the VM to <term>tenant
     networks</term>, which are virtual networks defined over <term>provider
     networks</term>, which in turn are abstractions associated with physical interfaces assigned to
    data networks on the compute nodes. Several virtual interface driver options are available. For
    more information about launching instances and connecting their virtual Ethernet interfaces, see
    the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Reference Deployment Scenarios</cite>. The chapters on
     <cite>Deploying the Bridging Scenario</cite> and <cite>Deploying the Routing Scenario</cite> contain detailed examples for defining virtual Ethernet
    interfaces.</p>
   <p>You can also connect a VM directly to a physical interface using PCI
    passthrough (see <xref href="psa1413402160578.xml"/>) or SR-IOV (see <xref href="psa1428687672712.xml"/>).</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>