<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333738594" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">Provider Networks</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Provider networks are the payload-carrying networks used implicitly by end users when
  they move traffic over their tenant networks.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="4">You must consider the following guidelines:</p>
        <ul id="ul_cmp_rl2_4n">
            <li ixia_locid="5">
                <p ixia_locid="6">From the point of view of the tenants, all networking happens over the tenant networks
     created by them, or by the <nameliteral ixia_locid="7">admin</nameliteral> user on their behalf. Tenants are
     not necessarily aware of the available provider networks. In fact, they cannot create tenant
     networks over provider networks not already accessible to them. For this reason, the system
     administrator must ensure that proper communication mechanisms are in place for tenants to
     request access to specific provider networks when required.</p>
                <p ixia_locid="8">For example, a tenant may be interested in creating a new tenant
                    network with access to a specific network access device in the data center, such
                    as an access point for a wireless transport. In this case, the system
                    administrator must create a new tenant network on behalf of the tenant, using  a
                    VLAN ID in the provider network's segmentation range that provides connectivity
                    to the said network access point.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="9">
                <p ixia_locid="10">Consider how different offerings of bandwidth, throughput commitments, and class-of-service,
     can be used by your users. Having different provider network offerings available to your
     tenants enables end users to diversify their own portfolio of services. This in turn gives the
     HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade administration an opportunity to put different revenue models in place.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="11">
                <p ixia_locid="12">For the IPv4 address plan, consider the following:</p>
                <ul id="ul_ixv_ct2_4n">
                    <li ixia_locid="13">
                        <p ixia_locid="14">Tenant networks attached to a public network, such as the
                            Internet, have to have external addresses assigned to them. Therefore
                            you must plan for valid definitions of their IPv4 subnets and default
                            gateways.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li ixia_locid="15">
                        <p ixia_locid="16">As with the OAM network, you must ensure that suitable
                            firewall services are in place on any tenant network with a public
                            address.</p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="17">
                <p ixia_locid="18">Segmentation ranges defined on a provider network may be owned by
                    the administrator, a specific tenant, or may be shared by all tenants. With this
                    ownership model:</p>
                <ul id="ul_kgw_jdl_hp">
                    <li ixia_locid="19">
                        <p ixia_locid="20">A base deployment scenario has each compute node using a
                            single data interface defined over a single provider network. In this
                            scenario, all required tenant networks can be instantiated making use of
                            the available VLANs or VNIs in each corresponding segmentation range.
                            You may need more than one provider network when the underlying physical
                            networks demand different MTU sizes, or when boundaries between provider
                            networks are dictated by policy or other non-technical
                            considerations.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li ixia_locid="21">
                        <p ixia_locid="22">Segmentation ranges can be reserved and assigned on-demand without having
                            to lock and unlock the compute nodes. This facilitates day-to-day
                            operations which can be performed without any disruption to the running
                            environment.</p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>