<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="jow1438192231731" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Connecting Virtual Machines to External Networks</title>
    <shortdesc>You can provide VMs with external connectivity using one of several
        methods.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <context id="context_N1001F_N1001C_N10001">
            <p>You can use source network address translation (SNAT) or floating IP
                addresses to expose VMs to an external network. Alternatively, you can use an
                external NAT device, or use a network address space for the VMs that is directly
                visible from the external network.</p>
            <p>You can associate a floating IP address with a VM using a pool of
                available floating IP addresses configured by the system administrator. When a host
                on an external network initiates a connection to a public floating IP address, the
                virtual router updates a connection table to enable bidirectional traffic flow
                between the host and the VM.</p>
            <p>When SNAT is enabled, the virtual router updates the connection table
                only when a VM initiates connection to an external host. Until this happens, the VM
                is inaccessible from the external network. This is true even if the private IP
                address of the VM is used directly by incoming traffic.</p>
            <p>You can use floating IP addresses and SNAT in any combination. The
                following table presents an overview. </p>
            <table frame="all" id="table_wbq_4p1_ws" rowheader="firstcol">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry/>
                            <entry>
                                <p>Floating IP disabled</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p>Floating IP enabled</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <p>SNAT disabled</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p>VMs are directly accessible from the external
                                    network, provided the tenant network address space is directly
                                    visible from the external network, or NAT is implemented using a
                                    separate device.</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p>VMs cannot initiate connections to the external
                                    network unless they have assigned floating IP addresses.
                                    External hosts can initiate connections to VMs that have
                                    assigned floating IP addresses.</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <p>SNAT enabled</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p>VMs can initiate connections to the external
                                    network. External hosts cannot initiate connections to the
                                    VMs.</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <p>VMs can initiate connections to the external
                                    network. External hosts can initiate connections to VMs that
                                    have assigned floating IP addresses. </p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <p>To enable or disable SNAT, see <xref href="jow1438192116883.xml"/>.</p>
            <p>To configure floating IP addresses for VMs, refer to the public
                OpenStack documentation.</p>
        </context>
        <prereq id="prereq_N100FD_N1001F_N10001">
            <p>To connect VMs to external networks, you require an internal tenant network for the
                VMs, an external tenant network connected to an edge router, and a virtual router
                attached to both networks. For more information about adding and configuring these
                components, see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Reference Deployment Scenarios</cite>.</p>
        </prereq>
    </body>
</task-wr>