<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1429631834947" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Adding Virtual Router Interfaces</title>
    <shortdesc>You can create router interfaces to tenant networks using the web
        administration interface or the CLI.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p><draft-comment author="jowens">CGTS-2523 (nominal) Remove material
                    about adding a gateway</draft-comment>For more information about virtual
                routers, see <xref href="jow1429628777191.xml"/>.</p>
        
        
            <p>Before you can create interfaces to tenant networks, you must create
                the tenant networks and associated subnets. For examples, see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Reference Deployment Scenarios</cite>. For more
                information about tenant networks and subnets, see <xref href="jow1404333739174.xml"/> and <xref href="psa1412702861873.xml"/>. </p>
        
        
            <p>As an alternative to the web administration interface, you can use
                CLI commands to add router interfaces. First, become the appropriate keystone user.
                The examples in this section assume you are the <codeph>admin</codeph> user.</p>
            <p>Then use the <cmdname>neutron
                    router-interface-add</cmdname> command to add interfaces. For example: </p>
            <codeblock>
<codeph>~(keystone_admin)$ neutron router-interface-add <varname>router_id</varname> <varname>subnet-id</varname></codeblock>
            <p>where <varname>router_id</varname> is the name or
                UUID of the router, and <varname>subnet_id</varname> is the name or
                UUID of the subnet to which you want to attach an interface. By default, the
                interface is assigned the gateway address on the subnet.</p>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>Log in as the user associated with the tenant.</li>
            
             
                <li>Select 
                        <b>Project</b>, then
                        <b>Network</b>, then
                        <b>Routers</b>
                    .</li>
            
             
                <li>In the list of existing routers, click the name of the router to be
                    configured.
                
                    <p>The <b>Router Details</b> page
                        appears.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1404333604053.image" id="image_kr5_jz2_yn" placement="inline"/>
                    
                </li>
            
             
                <li>On the <b>Interfaces</b> tab, click <b>Add Interface</b>.
                
                    <p>The <b>Add Interface</b> dialog box appears.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1404333605539.image" id="image_yrl_qbf_yn" placement="inline"/>
                    
                    <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt>Subnet</dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>Use the drop-down list to select from existing subnets defined
                                    for the tenant. Each subnet is identified by a tenant network
                                    name, followed by a subnet address and mask created for the
                                    tenant network.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt>IP Address (optional)</dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>You can optionally specify an IP address for the
                                    interface. By default, the gateway address for the subnet is
                                    used (for example, 192.168.102.1).</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt>Router Name</dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>This field is shown for information only.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt>Router ID</dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>This field is shown for information only.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                    </dl>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>To save your settings and close the dialog box, click
                        <b>Add Interface</b>.
                
                    <p>The new interface is shown in the <b>Router Details</b>.</p>
                
                </li>
        </ol>
    </body>
</topic>
