<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1414074138348" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Managing Storage Nodes</title>
    <shortdesc>On systems that use a <codeph>Ceph</codeph> backend for Cinder storage, you can add or replace storage disks or
        swap a storage node while the system is running, even if the storage resources are in active
        use.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p>A HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade system with a Ceph storage backend uses exactly
                two storage nodes; you cannot add or remove storage nodes. However, you can add
                disks to a storage node to increase capacity, and you can replace a faulty host.</p>
            <note id="note_N1002C_N10024_N10021_N10001">
                <p>The storage node pair in a HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade system provides
                    redundancy for High Availability. A balanced storage capacity is recommended, in
                    which each host has sufficient independent resources to meet the operational
                    requirements of the system.</p>
            </note>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>Lock the host to be modified or replaced.</li>
                
                    <p>Open the <b>Hosts</b> list by
                        clicking <b>Inventory</b> on the<b> System Panel</b> section of the <b>Admin</b> menu, and then selecting the <b>Hosts</b> tab.</p>
                    <p>Click <menucascade>
                            <b>More</b>
                            <b>Lock Host</b>
                        </menucascade> for the host. </p>
                    <p>Wait for the procedure to be completed.</p>
                
            
             
                <li>Power down the host and make any required hardware
                    changes.</li>
                
                    <p>This may involve replacing or adding disks, or replacing the
                        host completely.</p>
                
            
             
                <li>Place the new or modified host node into service.</li>
                
                    <ul id="ul_zhp_2fv_hp">
                        <li>
                            <p>For disk replacement, no additional configuration
                                changes are needed. To begin using the new disk, power up the host
                                and unlock it. </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p>For disk addition, you must create a new storage
                                volume (OSD) before you can use the new disk. For more information,
                                see the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide: Creating
                                    Storage Volumes</cite>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p>For host replacement, you must delete the existing
                                host using <menucascade>
                                    <b>More</b>
                                    <b>Delete Host</b>
                                </menucascade>. Then you must initialize the new host with a
                                personality as a storage node, configure its interfaces, and create
                                storage volumes. For more information on initializing and
                                configuring a storage node, see the <cite>Titanium
                                    Server Software Installation Guide: Initializing and Configuring
                                    Storage Nodes</cite>.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                
            
        </ol>
    </body>
</topic>