<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1413726521641" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">System Configuration Management</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">You can make changes to the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade's initial configuration at
  any time after installation.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="4">The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade's initial configuration is defined during
   software installation, using the <nameliteral ixia_locid="5">region_config</nameliteral> script
   (see <xref
    href="http://docs-staging.hpcloud.com/DRAFT/#CarrierGrade/Installation/carrier-grade-install-pb-overview.html"
    format="html" scope="external">Installing HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade</xref>).  After
   installation, you can make changes using the web administration interface or the CLI. For most
   types of changes, you can do this without interrupting system operations.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="8">You can change the initial configuration as follows:</p>
  <ul id="ul_ghh_hfp_5p">
   <li ixia_locid="9">
    <p ixia_locid="10">Reconfigure aspects of the External OAM network, including the subnet,
     controller IP addresses, gateway IP address, and floating IP address.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="11">
    <p ixia_locid="12">Change the DNS server IP addresses.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="13">
    <p ixia_locid="14">Change the NTP server IP addresses.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="15">
    <p ixia_locid="16">Change the disk allocations for database storage, image storage, backup
     storage, and Cinder volume storage.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="48">
    <p ixia_locid="49">Add an infrastructure network if one is not already configured.</p>
    <note id="note_N10069_N10062_N10036_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="50">
     <p ixia_locid="51">A service interruption is required to add an infrastructure network; all
      nodes except the active controller must be locked. In addition, you must use the CLI to make
      this change.</p>
    </note>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="26">Immediately before making a change, ensure the following:</p>
  <ul id="ul_o1p_hb2_vp">
   <li ixia_locid="27">
    <p ixia_locid="28">All hosts are unlocked.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="40">
    <p ixia_locid="42">No <nameliteral ixia_locid="44">Major</nameliteral> or <nameliteral ixia_locid="45">Critical</nameliteral>
     alarms are shown for the system on the Fault Management page.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="41">
    <p ixia_locid="43">No <nameliteral ixia_locid="46">250.001 Configuration out-of-date</nameliteral> alarms are
     shown for the system on the Fault Management page.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="37">During these changes, the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade can remain online and operational.
   For some types of changes, alarms are raised while the settings are in transition.  To make the
   changes take effect and to clear the alarms, individual hosts must be locked and then unlocked
   one at a time. For more information, see <xref href="jow1413726817770.xml" ixia_locid="39"/>.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="38">Only hosts with <nameliteral ixia_locid="47">250.001 Configuration out-of-date</nameliteral>
   alarms need to be locked and then unlocked. When locking and unlocking the hosts to clear the
   alarms, use the following order:</p>
  <ol id="ol_wnd_nzd_vp">
   <li ixia_locid="31">
    <p ixia_locid="32">controller nodes</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="35">
    <p ixia_locid="36">compute nodes</p>
   </li>
  </ol>
  <note id="note_N1006C_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="24">
   <p ixia_locid="25">To keep the system operational during an OAM network change, sufficient
    resources must be available to migrate the virtual machines on a compute node while it is locked
    for changes.</p>
  </note>
  <p ixia_locid="52">To make changes using the web administration interface, you must be logged in
   as the <nameliteral ixia_locid="7">admin</nameliteral> user.  Use the <wintitle ixia_locid="18">System Configuration</wintitle> pane, is available from the <uicontrol ixia_locid="19">System
    Panel</uicontrol> section of the <uicontrol ixia_locid="20">Admin</uicontrol> menu. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="53">To make changes using the CLI, you must be logged in as the
    <nameliteral ixia_locid="54">wrsroot</nameliteral> user on the active controller, and sourced as the Keystone
    <nameliteral ixia_locid="55">admin</nameliteral> user. For more information, see <xref href="jow1413729179585.xml" ixia_locid="22"/>.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>
