<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1406727863674" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">The Board Management Network</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The board management network is an optional network used for out-of-band
  reset, power-up, and power-down operations.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="46">Pedro Sanchez</author>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="47">This network provides access to iLO3 or iLO4 (Integrated Lights Out) baseboard
   management modules optionally installed in the hosts. These modules provide support for remote
   reset and power control of the hosts.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="48">The board management network can be implemented so that it is accessible
   externally using the OAM network, or only accessible internally to the hosts in the cluster. This
   choice is made at system installation, during the configuration controller script. For details,
   see the <cite ixia_locid="25">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide: The Controller
    Configuration Script</cite>.</p>
  <section id="section_N10036_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="71">
   <title ixia_locid="72">Configuration for External Access</title>
   <p ixia_locid="73">For external access, do not configure a board management network during the
    controller configuration script (press <userinput ixia_locid="75">n</userinput> when prompted). </p>
   <p ixia_locid="74">After completing the script, you must also do the following:</p>
   <ul id="ul_kw4_qpp_ds">
    <li ixia_locid="97">
     <p ixia_locid="99">Configure each iLO module to use static IP addressing.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="76">
     <p ixia_locid="77">Peform additional host and module provisioning, as described in <xref format="dita" href="#jow1406727863674/module_and_host_provisioning" ixia_locid="78"/>.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="81">
     <p ixia_locid="82">Ensure that the OAM Default Gateway specified during controller
      configuration has access to the board management network.</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1006F_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="83">
   <title ixia_locid="84">Configuration for Internal Access</title>
   <p ixia_locid="50">For internal access, configure a board management network during the
    controller configuration script (press <userinput ixia_locid="85">y</userinput> when prompted,
    and then specify a VLAN ID and a subnet). This configures a VLAN ID on the controller management
    interface for use with a board management network. To complete the VLAN, you must connect the
    modules to VLAN-tagged ports on an internal L2 switch. The modules are assigned IP addresses
    from the specified subnet.</p>
   <fig id="fig_lwg_xlp_ds" ixia_locid="26">
    <title ixia_locid="41">Internal-access board management network</title>
    <image href="psa1408575952625.image" id="image_mwg_xlp_ds" ixia_locid="27" width="6in">
     <alt ixia_locid="28">board management network</alt>
    </image>
   </fig>
   <p ixia_locid="42">The figure above illustrates how the board management network operates when
    configured for internal access. Computenodes connect using iLO modules, while
    controller nodes use the management port in tagged mode. As indicated in the figure, the
    controller nodes can optionally attach using their own iLO modules, if available.</p>
   <ul id="ul_n5g_xlp_ds">
    <li ixia_locid="21">
     <p ixia_locid="22">On the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade:</p>
     <ul id="ul_x5g_xlp_ds">
      <li ixia_locid="29">
       <p ixia_locid="30">Designate a VLAN ID for use by the board management network.</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="31">
       <p ixia_locid="32">Configure this VLAN ID as part of the software installation process.</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="33">
       <p ixia_locid="34">Ensure that the internal management network is operational and that all
        participant hosts are attached to it.</p>
      </li>
     </ul>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="9">
     <p ixia_locid="7">On the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade internal L2 switch:</p>
     <ul id="ul_y5g_xlp_ds">
      <li ixia_locid="35">
       <p ixia_locid="36">Configure a VLAN using the designated VLAN ID for the board management
        network.</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="37">
       <p ixia_locid="38">Add each of the ports used to connect an iLO module to the VLAN.</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="39">
       <p ixia_locid="40">Add the ports used to connect the controllers to the internal management
        network to the VLAN. You must ensure that these ports are tagged ports for this VLAN, that
        is, that outgoing board management traffic (toward the controllers) uses ﻿IEEE 802.1Q
        tagging. Other management traffic on this port is untagged.</p>
      </li>
     </ul>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="98">
     <p ixia_locid="100">Configure each iLO module to use DHCP.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="86">
     <p ixia_locid="87">Peform additional host and module provisioning, as described in <xref format="dita" href="#jow1406727863674/module_and_host_provisioning" ixia_locid="88"/>.</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
   <p ixia_locid="18">For details on configuring or provisioning switch ports or iLO modules,
    consult the user documentation supplied with the equipment.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="module_and_host_provisioning" ixia_locid="89">
   <title ixia_locid="90">Host and iLO Module Provisioning for a Board Management Network</title>
   <p ixia_locid="70">For internal or external access, you must perform the following additional
    provisioning:</p>
   <ul id="ul_tmg_cmp_ds">
    <li ixia_locid="52">
     <p ixia_locid="54">Provision each iLO module with a username and password for secure
      access.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="56">
     <p ixia_locid="58">Provision each host with the MAC address of the attached iLO module. This is
      required so that the system can associate the module's assigned IP address with the correct
      host.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="95">
     <p ixia_locid="96">For external-access configurations only, provision each host with the IP address of the
      attached iLO module.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="66">
     <p ixia_locid="68">Provision each host with the username and password of the attached iLO
      module. This is required for controller access to the module.</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
   <p ixia_locid="91">For module provisioning, consult the user documentation supplied with the
    equipment.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="92">For host provisioning, you can use the <wintitle ixia_locid="93">Board
     Management</wintitle> tab on the <wintitle ixia_locid="94">Edit Host</wintitle> dialog box, or
    the CLI. For more information, see the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide.</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>