<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1426948577755" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Network Interface Provisioning</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Interfaces on compute nodes require initial provisioning to attach them to
  networks.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="6"> On compute nodes, some interfaces require manual provisioning
   before the nodes can be unlocked.</p>
  <ul id="ul_ecp_4fk_lr">
   <li ixia_locid="10">
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="37">US62814 removed statement that you must manually attach storage
     interface to infra network; added clauses for static assignment, for compute nodes.</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="11">For a storage node, if the infrastructure network uses static IP address
     assignment, you must assign an IP address to the infrastructure interface using the <cmdname ixia_locid="38">system host-addr-add</cmdname> command before you can unlock the node . For
     more information, see the <cite ixia_locid="39">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Administration Guide: Adding an
      IP Address to an Interface</cite>.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="12">
    <p ixia_locid="29">For a compute node, you must attach interfaces to provider networks before
     you can unlock the node. The provider networks must be set up beforehand; for more information,
     see <xref href="jow1404333519516.xml" ixia_locid="14"/>. </p>
    <p ixia_locid="30">If the cluster uses an infrastructure network, you must attach an interface
     to the infrastructure network before you can unlock the node. In addition, if the
     infrastructure uses static addressing, you must assign an IP address to the interface using the
      <cmdname ixia_locid="40">system host-addr-add</cmdname> command.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="15">The procedure for attaching an interface depends on whether the interface is an
   Ethernet, aggregated Ethernet, or shared (VLAN) interface.</p>
  <ul id="ul_pcn_f5q_lr">
   <li ixia_locid="16">
    <p ixia_locid="17">To attach an Ethernet interface, see <xref href="jow1426949897008.xml" ixia_locid="18"/>.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="19">
    <p ixia_locid="20">To attach an aggregated Ethernet interface, see <xref href="jow1426951671346.xml" ixia_locid="21"/>.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="22">
    <p ixia_locid="23">To attach a VLAN interface, see <xref href="jow1426951757970.xml" ixia_locid="24"/>.</p>
    <note id="note_N1007F_N10071_N1004F_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="34">
     <p ixia_locid="35">To attach a data network to an existing management or infrastructure network
      interface<!-- using a method that supports VLAN provider networks-->, see <xref href="jow1414000462559.xml" ixia_locid="36"/>.</p>
    </note>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="25">As an alternative, you can use the CLI to attach interfaces. See <xref href="jow1427029415968.xml" ixia_locid="26"/>.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="27">For more information about interfaces, see the <cite ixia_locid="28">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Administration Guide:
    Ethernet Interfaces</cite>.</p>
  <note id="note_N10095_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="31">
   <p ixia_locid="32">On compute nodes, the Ethernet interface for the management network
    is attached automatically, to support installation using PXE booting. </p>
   <p ixia_locid="33">On controller nodes, interfaces are attached to the management, OAM, and
    optional infrastructure networks automatically according to the settings specified during the
    controller configuration script. They do not require further provisioning before system
    deployment. For more information, see <xref href="jow1419271369349.xml" ixia_locid="5"/>.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>