<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1423087781001" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Huge Page Provisioning</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">You can adjust the number and size of pages to allocate on a host for use
  as VM memory. For individual VMs, you can specify the page size to use.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="4">In each NUMA node on a host, a fixed amount of memory is reserved for use by
   VMs. By default, this memory is managed using 2 MiB huge pages. You can change this for
   individual NUMA nodes to use a combination of 2 MiB and 1 GiB huge pages. Using larger pages can
   reduce page management overhead and improve system performance for systems with large amounts of
   virtual memory and many running processes.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="5">You can use the <cmdname ixia_locid="6">system host-memory-list</cmdname> and
    <cmdname ixia_locid="7">system host-memory-show</cmdname> commands to see how much memory is
   available for VMs. This information is also shown on the <uicontrol ixia_locid="14">Memory</uicontrol> tab of the <wintitle ixia_locid="15">Host Inventory</wintitle> page (see
    <xref href="jow1404333795559.xml" ixia_locid="16"/>). To see how many pages of a given size you
   can successfully request on a node (assuming that pages of another size are not also requested),
   click the Information icon next to each field on the <wintitle ixia_locid="17">Update Hugepage
    Memory</wintitle> dialog box.</p>
  <fig id="fig_zdt_vzd_cs" ixia_locid="18">
   <image href="jow1432129731308.image" id="image_blt_xzd_cs" ixia_locid="19" width="2.5in">
    <alt ixia_locid="20">TiS Update Hugepage Memory: Maximum Pages info</alt>
   </image>
  </fig>
  <p ixia_locid="8">If the huge page request cannot be allocated from the available memory, an
   informative message is displayed. If the available memory is greater than the amount required by
   the huge page request, unallocated memory is automatically assigned as 4K pages.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="11">After setting the memory allocations for a compute node, you can save them as a <term ixia_locid="12">memory
    profile</term>, and then apply the profile to other compute nodes. For more information, see
    <xref href="jow1429811350849.xml" ixia_locid="13"/>.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="9">To specify the page size to use for a VM, see <xref href="jow1424723681500.xml" ixia_locid="10"/>.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>