<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333739778" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">L2 Access Switches</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">L2 access switches connect the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade hosts to the different
        networks. Proper configuration of the access ports is necessary to ensure proper traffic
        flow.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author></author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <section id="section_N1001D_N1001A_N10001" ixia_locid="4">
            <p ixia_locid="5">One or more L2 switches can be used to connect the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                hosts to the different networks. When sharing a single L2 switch you must ensure
                proper isolation of the network traffic. Here is an example of how to configure a
                shared L2 switch:</p>
            <ul id="ul_obf_dyr_4n">
                <li ixia_locid="6">
                    <p ixia_locid="7">one port- or MAC-based VLAN for the internal management network</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="8">
                    <p ixia_locid="9">one port- or MAC-based VLAN for the OAM network</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="23">
                    <p ixia_locid="24">one port-based VLAN for an optional board management network,
                        if the network is configured for internal access</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="10">
                    <p ixia_locid="11">one or more sets of VLANs for provider networks. For
                        example:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_ov4_kyr_4n">
                        <li ixia_locid="12">
                            <p ixia_locid="13">one set of VLANs with good QoS for bronze tenants</p>
                        </li>
                        <li ixia_locid="14">
                            <p ixia_locid="15">one set of VLANs with better QoS for silver tenants</p>
                        </li>
                        <li ixia_locid="16">
                            <p ixia_locid="17">one set of VLANs with the best QoS for gold tenants</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p ixia_locid="18">When using multiple L2 switches, there are several deployment
                possibilities. Here are some examples:</p>
            <ul id="ul_qmd_wyr_4n">
                <li ixia_locid="19">
                    <p ixia_locid="20">A single L2 switch for the internal management and OAM networks. Port- or MAC-based network
      isolation is mandatory.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="21">
                    <p ixia_locid="22">One or more L2 switches, not necessarily inter-connected, with one L2 switch per provider
      network.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="52">
                    <p ixia_locid="53">Redundant L2 switches to support link aggregation, using
                        either a failover model, or Virtual Port Channel (VPC) for more robust
                        redundancy. For more information, see <xref href="jow1437759656219.xml" ixia_locid="54"/>.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p ixia_locid="47">Switch ports that send tagged traffic are referred to as <term ixia_locid="48">trunk</term> ports. They usually participate in the Spanning
                Tree Protocol (STP) from the moment the link goes up, which usually translates into
                several seconds of delay before the trunk port moves to the forwarding state. This
                delay is likely to impact services such as DHCP and PXE which are used during
                regular operations of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="49">Therefore, you must consider configuring the switch ports to which
                the management interfaces are attached to transition to the forwarding state
                immediately after the link goes up. This option is usually referred to as a <term ixia_locid="50">PortFast</term>.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="51">You should also consider configuring these ports to prevent them from
                participating on any STP exchanges. This is usually done by configuring them to
                avoid processing inbound and outbound BDPU STP packets completely. Consult your
                switch's manual for details.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>