<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1417813748326" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title>Scaling Virtual Machine Resources</title>
 <shortdesc>You can scale the resources of individual instances up or
  down.</shortdesc>
 <prolog><author/>
  <author/>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p>Currently, the CPU resources for an instance are scalable.</p>
  <p>For an instance to be scalable, the following requirements must be
   satisfied:</p>
  <ul id="ul_jxz_vfv_hq">
   <li>
    <p>The image used to launch the instance must support scaling.</p>
    <p> The example image provided with HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade supports scaling. You can
     also build your own image, incorporating the required libraries and services. For more about
     building your own images, or about the technical requirements for scaling support, refer to the
     documentation included with the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Development Kit. </p>
   </li>
   <li>
    <p>The flavor used to launch the instance must be configured with maximum and
     minimum scaling limits (the <term>scaling range</term>) for the resource.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p>When scaling a VM, use the credentials of the user that launched the VM. This ensures that
   quotas are correctly managed.  </p>
  <p/>
  <p>Depending on the resource being scaled, the scaling behavior applied by
   HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade may be adjustable. For example, you can control which CPUs are released when the
   CPU resources for an instance are scaled down. To adjust scaling behavior, use the App Scale
   Helper script.</p>
  <p>Normally, scaling is performed under the direction of Heat orchestration.  For more about Heat
   autoscaling, see <xref href="jow1417818508589.xml"/>. If required, you can scale resources
   manually from the command line using the <cmdname>nova scale</cmdname> command, with the
   following syntax:</p>
  <codeblock><systemoutput>~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput>nova scale <varname>instance_id</varname> <varname>resource</varname> {up | down}</userinput></codeblock>
  <p>For example, to reduce the number of CPUs allotted to an instance, you can use this
   command:</p>
  <codeblock><systemoutput>~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput>nova scale <varname>instance_id</varname> cpu down</userinput></codeblock>
  <note id="note_N1006A_N1001C_N10001">
   <p>To scale up the resources for an instance, sufficient resources are required on the host. If
    all available resources are already allocated to other instances, you may need to free up
    resources manually.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>