<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333777760" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <!-- Modification History
   -->
    <title id="1">Interfaces</title>
    <shortdesc id="2">The <uicontrol id="3">Interfaces</uicontrol> tab on the
            <wintitle id="4">Inventory Detail</wintitle> page presents details about the
        logical L2 network interfaces on a node, as illustrated below for an unlocked controller
        node.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author id="5">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <fig id="fig_N10027_N10024_N10001" id="6">
            <image href="jow1404333771094.image" id="image_v3c_dc1_m4" id="7" width="6in"/>
        </fig>
        <p id="8"><!-- screen shot needs to match text! -->In this example the node has two allocated interfaces,
                <nameliteral id="135">eth0</nameliteral> connecting to the OAM network, and
                <nameliteral id="136">eth1</nameliteral> connecting to the internal management network. These
            interfaces are mandatory and therefore cannot be deleted. They reflect the allocation
            given when the node was provisioned. See the <cite id="10">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                Software Installation Guide</cite> for details.</p>
        <p id="11">On a properly configured compute node, the <uicontrol id="12">Interfaces</uicontrol> tab presents additional logical interfaces, as illustrated
            below for a locked node:</p>
        <fig id="fig_N10047_N10024_N10001" id="13">
            <image href="jow1404333772968.image" id="image_xyx_c21_m4" id="14" width="6in"/>
        </fig>
        <p id="15"><!-- screen shot needs to match text! -->In this example the node has three allocated interfaces, <nameliteral id="16">eth1</nameliteral> connecting to the internal management network,
            and <nameliteral id="17">data0</nameliteral> and <nameliteral id="18">data1</nameliteral> connecting to the provider networks <nameliteral id="19">group0-data0</nameliteral> and <nameliteral id="20">group0-data1</nameliteral> respectively. The interface <nameliteral id="21">eth1</nameliteral> is auto-provisioned as part of the automated software
            installation process on the compute node. It can be modified but not deleted.</p>
        <p id="22">Information about interfaces is presented in several columns, as follows:</p>
        <dl>
            <dlentry id="23">
                <dt id="24">Name</dt>
                <dd id="25">
                    <p id="26">The name given to the logical L2 interface.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="31">
                <dt id="32">Network Type</dt>
                <dd id="33">
                    <p id="34">The type of network the logical network interface is connected to. The options are:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_rtx_4g1_m4">
                        <li id="35">
                            <p id="36"><nameliteral id="37">data</nameliteral>, for a compute node data interface</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="41">
                            <p id="42"><nameliteral id="43">infra</nameliteral>, for
                                the optional infrastructure network</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="38">
                            <p id="39"><nameliteral id="40">mgmt</nameliteral>, for
                                the internal management network</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="44">
                            <p id="45"><nameliteral id="46">oam</nameliteral>, for the OAM network</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="131">
                            <p id="132"><nameliteral id="133">pci-passthrough</nameliteral>, for a PCI passthrough
                                interface</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="47">
                <dt id="48">Type</dt>
                <dd id="49">
                    <p id="50">Ethernet, or aggregated Ethernet (LAG).</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="137">
                <dt id="139">Vlan ID</dt>
                <dd id="141">
                    <p id="143">The VLAN ID of the network listed in the
                            <nameliteral id="153">Network Type</nameliteral> column,  if the network uses a
                        shared interface. For more information about shared interfaces, see <xref href="jow1423173019489.xml" id="154"/>.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="138">
                <dt id="140">Port(s)</dt>
                <dd id="142">
                    <p id="144">The physical ports on top of which the logical interface is
                        built. Multiple ports are displayed when the logical interface uses LAG.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="145">
                <dt id="146">Uses</dt>
                <dd id="147">
                    <p id="148">The interface used by the network listed in the
                            <nameliteral id="155">Network Type</nameliteral> column, if the network uses a
                        shared interface. The VLAN ID of the network is shown in the
                            <nameliteral id="156">Vlan ID</nameliteral> field.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="149">
                <dt id="150">Used By</dt>
                <dd id="151">
                    <p id="152">The networks that share the interface using VLAN tagging, if
                        the interface is shared. For more information about shared interfaces, see
                            <xref href="jow1423173019489.xml" id="157"/>.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="55">
                <dt id="56">Provider Networks</dt>
                <dd id="57">
                    <p id="58">This option is relevant for compute nodes only, and for interfaces of the
              <nameliteral id="59">data</nameliteral> network type. It lists the provider networks
            associated with the data interface.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="60">
                <dt id="61">Attributes</dt>
                <dd id="62">
                    <p id="63">The current MTU size for the interface.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="64">
                <dt id="65">Actions</dt>
                <dd id="66">
                    <p id="67">On a locked node, you can modify a logical interface, and execute management operations
            on it. This is implemented using the buttons <uicontrol id="68">Edit Interface</uicontrol> and
              <uicontrol id="69">More</uicontrol>. These buttons are not available when the node is
            unlocked.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
        </dl>
        <section id="section_N10133_N10024_N10001" id="70">
            <title id="71">Creating an Interface Profile</title>
            <p id="72">Use the <uicontrol id="73">Create Interface
                    Profile</uicontrol> button on the <uicontrol id="74">Interfaces</uicontrol> tab to display the <wintitle id="75">Create
                    Interface Profile</wintitle> window. From there you can create a new interface
                profile out of the currently defined node interfaces. An example for a compute node
                is illustrated below.</p>
            <fig id="fig_N1014D_N10135_N10024_N10001" id="76">
                <image href="jow1404333774522.image" id="image_gpp_pp1_m4" id="77" width="4in"/>
            </fig>
            <p id="78">In this window you enter the name of the new profile,
          <nameliteral id="79">HP-360-cmpt-iface-profile</nameliteral> in this case, and then click the
        button <uicontrol id="80">Create Interface Profile</uicontrol> to execute. Available interface
        profiles are listed, and can be removed, from the <wintitle id="81">System Inventory</wintitle>
        page, as described in <xref href="jow1404333787693.xml" id="82"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N1016B_N10024_N10001" id="83">
            <title id="84">Managing Interfaces</title>
            <p id="85">New logical interfaces can be created using the <uicontrol id="86">Create Interface</uicontrol> button on the <uicontrol id="87">Interfaces</uicontrol> tab. This button is available only on
                nodes in the locked state. When the button is clicked, the window <wintitle id="88">Create Interface</wintitle> is displayed, as illustrated
                below.</p>
            <fig id="fig_N10186_N1016E_N10024_N10001" id="89">
                <image href="jow1404333776177.image" id="image_dz4_jr1_m4" id="90" width="4in"/>
            </fig>
            <p id="91">The following fields are available:</p>
            <dl>
                <dlentry id="92">
                    <dt id="93">Interface Name</dt>
                    <dd id="94">
                        <p id="95">The name to be assigned to the new logical interface.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="96">
                    <dt id="97">Interface Type</dt>
                    <dd id="98">
                        <p id="99">The type of network interface, Ethernet or aggregated
                            Ethernet (LAG).</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="100">
                    <dt id="101">Ports</dt>
                    <dd id="102">
                        <p id="103">A list of physical ports available to the new logical
                            interface, with corresponding check-mark boxes. Physical ports already
                            allocated to other interfaces are not listed.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="104">
                    <dt id="105">Network Type</dt>
                    <dd id="106">
                        <p id="107">The type of network to attach the new logical interface
                            to (<nameliteral id="108">data</nameliteral> or <nameliteral id="109">infra</nameliteral>, for compute node data
                            interfaces and infrastructure network connections respectively). Note
                            that connections to the OAM and internal management networks are
                            auto-provisioned during the software installation process. </p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="110">
                    <dt id="111">Provider Network(s)</dt>
                    <dd id="112">
                        <p id="113">A list of provider networks available to the new logical
                            interface, with corresponding check-mark boxes. They can be selected for
                            networks of type <nameliteral id="114">data</nameliteral>, to
                            which multiple provider networks can be attached. Provider networks
                            already allocated to other data interfaces are not listed, since no
                            provider network can be associated with more than a single data
                            interface.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="115">
                    <dt id="116">MTU</dt>
                    <dd id="117">
                        <p id="118">The MTU size in bytes for the interface. For compute
                            nodes, values between 1500 and 9000 are supported. For controller nodes,
                            the MTU size cannot exceed 1500.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10203_N10024_N10001" id="119">
            <p id="134">To edit or remove a logical interface of network type <nameliteral id="121">data</nameliteral> or <nameliteral id="122">infra</nameliteral> you
                must first lock the target node. You can then use the <uicontrol id="124">Edit Interface</uicontrol> and <uicontrol id="126">More</uicontrol>
                buttons to perform these maintenance actions.</p>
            <p id="128">Logical interfaces of network types <nameliteral id="129">oam</nameliteral> and <nameliteral id="130">mgmt</nameliteral> cannot
                be deleted. They can only be modified to use different physical ports when required. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>