<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1423088885963" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Allocating Host Memory for VM Pages or Platform Use</title>
    <shortdesc>You can edit the platform and VM page memory allocations for a NUMA
        node from the web administration interface using the <b>Memory</b> tab on the <b>Inventory</b>
        pane.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p>Before requesting huge pages on a host, ensure that the host has
                enough available memory. For details, see <xref href="jow1423087781001.xml"/>. If a huge page request cannot be allocated from the available
                memory, an informative message is displayed.</p>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>On the <b>Inventory</b> pane, lock the host you
                    want to edit.</li>
            
             
                <li>Click the <b>Host Name</b> to
                    open the settings for the host.</li>
            
             
                <li>On the <b>Memory</b> tab, click
                        <b>Update Memory</b>.</li>
                
                    
                        <image href="jow1424729372811.image" id="image_kg3_sdf_2r" width="5in">
                            <alt>Update Memory button</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                
            
             
                <li>Use the <b>Update Memory
                        Allocation</b> dialog box to set the memory allocations for each NUMA
                    node. </li>
                
                    <p>For each available NUMA node, three fields are supplied, as
                        illustrated in the following example screen for two NUMA nodes.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1424729464258.image" id="image_tcp_tdf_2r" width="5in">
                            <alt>tis-hugepage-memory-dialog</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                    <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt>Platform Memory for Node <i>n</i></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>The amount of memory to reserve for platform use
                                    on the NUMA Node, in MiB. To see the minimum requirement, hover
                                    over the Information icon next to the field. </p>
                                
                                    <image href="jow1436294915672.image" id="image_drk_k4q_ps">
                                        <alt>TiS minimum platform memory tooltip</alt>
                                    </image>
                                
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt># of VM 2M Hugepages Node <i>n</i></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>The number of 2 MiB huge pages to reserve for VM
                                    use on the NUMA Node. If no 2 MiB pages are required, type
                                    0.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt># of VM 1G Hugepages Node <i>n</i></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>The number of 1 GiB huge pages to reserve for VM
                                    use on the NUMA Node. If no 1 GiB pages are required, type
                                    0.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                    </dl>
                    <p>To see how many huge pages of a given size you can
                        successfully request on a node (assuming that pages of another size are not
                        also requested), hover over the Information icon next to the field.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1432129731308.image" id="image_blt_xzd_cs" width="2.5in">
                            <alt>TiS Update Hugepage Memory: Maximum Pages info</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                    <p>Any unused memory is automatically allocated as 4 KiB pages
                        of regular memory for VMs. You must use the Memory Page Size extra spec, or
                        suitable image metadata, to use these 4 KiB pages as the backing mechanism
                        for VM memory allocation requests. See <xref href="jow1424723681500.xml"/>
                        for details.</p>
                
            
             
                <li>Click <b>Save</b>.</li>
            
             
                <li>Unlock the host and wait for it to be reported as
                        <codeph>Available</codeph>.</li>
            
        </ol>
    </body>
</topic>