<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1413727043334" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Changing the NTP Server Configuration</title>
    <shortdesc>You can change the NTP server addresses defined for HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
        at any time after installation.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p>During software installation, HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is configured with up
                to three NTP server IP addresses. You change these addresses using the web
                administration interface or the CLI.</p>
        
        
            <p>Before changing NTP server addresses, review the Fault Management
                page and ensure that any existing system alarms are cleared.</p>
            <note id="note_N1002F_N1002B_N1001D_N10001" type="caution">
                <p>For the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade system to use FQDN servers instead of
                    IPv4 servers, at least one valid DNS server must be specified.</p>
            </note>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>In the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade web administration interface, open the
                        <b>System Configuration</b> pane.
                
                    <p>The <b>System Configuration</b>
                        pane is available from the <b>System
                            Panel</b> section of the <b>Admin</b> menu. </p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Select the <b>NTP</b> tab.
                
                    <p>The <b>NTP</b> page appears, showing the
                        currently defined NTP servers and their IP addresses.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1413850406811.image" id="image_kll_h4z_5p" width="6in">
                            <alt>NTP page</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                </li>
            
             
                <li>Click <b>Edit NTP</b>.
                
                    <p>The <b>Edit NTP</b> dialog box
                        appears.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1413850437240.image" id="image_vcx_j4z_5p" width="4in">
                            <alt>Edit NTP dialog</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                </li>
            
             
                <li>Replace the NTP Server IP addresses or names with different
                    ones as required.
                
                    <p>If you specify the NTP servers using FQDNs you must have at
                        least one valid DNS server defined on your system. You must use IP addresses
                        otherwise.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Click <b>Save</b>.
                
                    <p>This raises major alarms against the controllers and
                        services. You can view the alarms on the Fault Management page.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Lock and unlock the controllers to clear the alarms.
                
                    <p>Open the <b>Hosts</b> list by
                        clicking <b>Inventory</b> on the<b> System Panel</b> section of the <b>Admin</b> menu, and then selecting the <b>Hosts</b> tab. Hosts requiring attention are
                        shown with the status <codeph>Config
                            out-of-date</codeph>.</p>
                    <p> To lock or unlock a host, click <b>More</b> for the host and then use the menu selections.</p>
                
                 <ol>
                    
                        <li>Lock the standby controller. 
                        
                            <p>Wait for the lock operation to be completed.</p>
                        
                        </li>
                    
                        <li>Unlock the standby controller.
                        
                            <p>Wait for the host to become available. It is updated
                                with the new NTP server addresses, and its error message is
                                cleared.</p>
                        
                        </li>
                    
                        <li>Perform a swact on the active controller.
                        
                            <p>Click 
                                    <b>More</b> >
                                    <b>Swact Host</b>
                                    
                                for the active controller.</p>
                        </li>
                    
                    
                        <li>Lock the original controller (now in standby
                            mode).
                        
                            <p>Wait for the lock operation to be completed.</p>
                        
                        </li>
                    
                        <li>Unlock the original controller.
                        
                            <p>Wait for it to become available. It is updated with
                                the new NTP server addresses, and its error message is cleared.</p>
                        </li>
                    
                
            
             
                <li>Ensure that the <codeph>250.001
                        Configuration out-of-date</codeph> alarms are cleared for both
                    controllers.</li>
            
        </ol></li></ol>
    </body>
</topic>