<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1441133993989" xml:lang="en-us">
    <!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Adding a Gateway to a Virtual Router</title>
    <shortdesc>You can configure a gateway for a virtual router as a tenant or an
        administrator. Users with administrator privileges have access to additional
        controls.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p><draft-comment author="jowens">CGTS-2523 (nominal)
                    added new topic, using material moved from an existing topic. The options for
                    setting a gateway differ for the admin user acting as admin (rather than as the
                    tenant called "admin"); trying to make this clear. . .</draft-comment>You can
                use either the web administration interface or the CLI to configure a gateway. Steps
                for the web administration interface are given later in this section.</p>
            <p>To use the CLI, become the appropriate keystone user. The examples
                in this section assume you are the <codeph>admin</codeph> user.</p>
            <p>To add a gateway interface, use a command of the following form:</p>
            <codeblock>
~(keystone_admin)$ neutron router-gateway-set <varname>router_id</varname> <varname>externalnet_id</varname> \
[--disable-snat] [--fixed-ip <varname>gateway_addr</varname>]</codeblock>
            <p>where</p>
            <parml>
                <plentry>
                    <pt><varname>router_id</varname></pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>is the name or UUID of the router</p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt><varname>externalnet_id</varname></pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p> is the name or UUID of a tenant network configured to provide external
                            connections</p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt><varname>gateway_addr</varname></pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>is the gateway interface IP address.  If <varname>gateway_addr</varname> is not specified, the server allocates the
                            next available external IP address.</p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
            <note id="note_N100B2_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
                <p>The <option>fixed-ip</option> and <option>disable-snat</option>
                    options require administrator privileges. For more about the SNAT option, see
                        <xref href="jow1438192116883.xml"/>.</p>
            </note>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>Log in as the user associated with the tenant.</li>
            
             
                <li>Open the <b>Routers</b> page.
                
                    <ul>
                        <li>To open the page with tenant privileges, select 
                                <b>Project</b>, then
                                <b>Network</b>, then
                                <b>Routers</b>.
                            </li>
                        <li>To open the page with administrator privileges, select 
                                <b>Admin</b>
                                <b>System</b>
                                <b>Routers</b>.</li>
                    </ul>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>In the list of existing routers, click the name of the router
                    to be configured.
                
                    <p>The <b>Router Details</b> page
                        appears.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1441134829532.image" id="image_qyv_pxh_ft">
                            <alt>TiS Add Gateway</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                </li>
            
             
                <li>On the <b>Interfaces</b> tab,
                    click <b>Set Gateway</b>.
                
                    <note id="note_N101CE_N101CA_N101B4_N100CF_N1001F_N10001">
                        <p>If a gateway has already been added, a <b>Clear Gateway</b> button is present
                            instead.</p>
                        <p> </p>
                    </note>
                    <p>The <b>Set Gateway</b> dialog
                        box appears. </p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1441136505281.image" id="image_k1p_kb3_ft">
                            <alt>Tis Set Gateway admin</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                    <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt><b>External Network</b></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>Select a tenant network configured to provide
                                    external access.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt><b>Router Name</b></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>This field is shown for information only.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt><b>Router ID</b></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>This field is shown for information only.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt><b>IP Address (optional)</b></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>This field is shown only for users with
                                    administrator privileges. You can optionally specify an IP
                                    address for the gateway interface. By default, the server
                                    allocates the next available external IP address.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt><b>Enable SNAT</b></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>This control is shown only for users with
                                    administrator privileges.  For more about the SNAT option, see
                                        <xref href="jow1438192116883.xml"/></p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                    </dl>
                    <p>To save the gateway gettings and close the dialog box, click
                            <b>Set Gateway</b>.</p>
                </li>
            
        </ol>
    </body>
</topic>