<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333640333" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <!-- Modification History
   -->
    <title id="1">Cluster Overview</title>
    <shortdesc id="2">The <wintitle id="3">Overview</wintitle> page appears when you
        log into the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade web management interface as the administrator. It presents a
        dashboard providing a quick health-check overview of the cluster.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author id="4">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p id="5">The <wintitle id="6">Overview</wintitle> page is an enhanced
            version of its OpenStack counterpart. It includes the following features:</p>
        <ul id="ul_rff_dwh_34">
            <li id="7">
                <p id="8">dynamically updated, relocatable resource charts. Click the top of
                    any chart, and drag it to the desired location to customize the presentation as
                    desired. The layout changes are persistent across logins.</p>
            </li>
            <li id="9">
                <p id="10">dynamically updated, relocatable Host Server Status summary
                    table. Presents the total number of hosts currently in one of the following
                    states:</p>
                <ul id="ul_t4l_vwh_34">
                    <li id="15">
                        <p id="16">locked</p>
                    </li>
                    <li id="17">
                        <p id="18">unlocked</p>
                    </li>
                    <li id="11">
                        <p id="12">available</p>
                    </li>
                    <li id="131">
                        <p id="133">unavailable</p>
                    </li>
                    <li id="132">
                        <p id="134">degraded</p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li id="129">
                <p id="130">dynamically updated, relocatable Alarms summary table. Lists the
                    current count of critical, major, minor, and warning alarms.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p id="19">Common attributes of the resource pages are:</p>
        <ul id="ul_hns_wm3_34">
            <li id="20">
                <p id="21">All resource charts display resource information in real-time, spanning over a
          time-window of ten minutes.</p>
            </li>
            <li id="22">
                <p id="23">Labels along the X-axis present the number of minutes elapsed since the last full-time
          hour of the system clock.</p>
            </li>
            <li id="24">
                <p id="25">Hovering the mouse over the charts overlays information windows with detailed values.</p>
            </li>
            <li id="26">
                <p id="27">History information is lost when the <wintitle id="28">Overview</wintitle> page is no longer
          displayed.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p id="29">The following charts are available:</p>
        <dl>
            <dlentry id="30">
                <dt id="31">Compute vCPU Usage</dt>
                <dd id="32">
                    <fig id="fig_N100A3_N100A0_N10099_N10096_N10020_N10001" id="33">
                        <image href="jow1404333631568.image" id="image_k1s_h13_34" id="34" width="2.25in"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p id="35">Presents information about the number of virtual CPUs across the entire cluster,
            available and allocated to virtual machines, and their average level of utilization.
            Elements in this chart are as follows:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_rbj_jm3_34">
                        <li id="36">
                            <p id="37">Y-axis is in units vCPUs.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="38">
                            <p id="39">A solid black line tracking the number of available vCPUs. This line settles at a
                constant value at the top of the chart, unless the number of compute nodes changes
                over time.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="40">
                            <p id="41">Light blue bars indicating the number of allocated vCPUs, that is, the number of
                vCPUs in use by virtual machines (one in the example). </p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="42">
                            <p id="43">Dark blue bars indicating the average level of utilization of the allocated vCPUs
                (varies from 30 to 83% in the example), presented as a relative height with respect
                to the light blue bars.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="51">
                <dt id="52">Instance CPU Utilization</dt>
                <dd id="53">
                    <fig id="fig_N10107_N10104_N100FD_N10096_N10020_N10001" id="54">
                        <image href="jow1404333633038.image" id="image_yf5_2p3_34" id="55" width="2.25in"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p id="56">Presents information about virtual CPU utilization levels on virtual machines, across
            the entire cluster or for individual instances. Elements in this chart are as
            follows:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_yq3_mp3_34">
                        <li id="57">
                            <p id="58">Y-axis displays the virtual CPU utilization level, from 0 to 100%.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="59">
                            <p id="60">A solid black line tracking the maximum utilization level.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="61">
                            <p id="62">Dark blue bars indicating the average utilization level.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="63">
                            <p id="64">A gray line tracking the minimum utilization level.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="65">
                            <p id="66">A filter drop-down menu to select the virtual machines on which to report
                utilization levels. The default value for this filter is "All Instances," and
                therefore it reports the same utilization levels indicated by the dark blue bars in
                the Compute vCPU Usage chart.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="67">
                <dt id="68">Compute Memory Usage</dt>
                <dd id="69">
                    <fig id="fig_N10150_N1014D_N10146_N10096_N10020_N10001" id="70">
                        <image href="jow1404333634455.image" id="image_u2h_gv3_34" id="71" width="2.25in"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p id="72">Presents information about memory usage levels on the compute nodes across the entire
            cluster. Elements in this chart are as follows:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_zzm_xv3_34">
                        <li id="73">
                            <p id="74">Y-axis is in units of bytes.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="75">
                            <p id="76">A solid black line tracking the available aggregated compute memory. This line
                usually settles as a constant value at the top of the chart, unless the number of
                compute nodes changes over time.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="77">
                            <p id="78">Dark blue bars indicating the amount of memory allocated to virtual machines (less
                than 1 GB in the example).</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="83">
                <dt id="84">Compute Disk Usage</dt>
                <dd id="85">
                    <fig id="fig_N1019D_N1019A_N10193_N10096_N10020_N10001" id="86">
                        <image href="jow1404333635945.image" id="image_a35_lv3_34" id="87" width="2.25in"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p id="88">Presents information about disk usage levels on the compute nodes across the entire
            cluster. Elements in this chart are as follows:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_qws_xv3_34">
                        <li id="89">
                            <p id="90">Y-axis is in units of bytes.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="91">
                            <p id="92">A solid black line tracking the available aggregated
                                storage capacity. This line usually settles as a constant value at
                                the top of the chart.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="93">
                            <p id="94">Dark blue bars indicating the amount of disk space allocated to virtual machines
                (about 1 GB in the example).</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="95">
                <dt id="96">AVS CPU Utilization</dt>
                <dd id="97">
                    <fig id="fig_N101D6_N101D3_N101CC_N10096_N10020_N10001" id="98">
                        <image href="jow1404333637433.image" id="image_ms4_3v3_34" id="99" width="2.25in"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p id="100">Presents information about AVS CPU utilization levels on the
                        compute nodes across the entire cluster. Elements in this chart are as
                        follows:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_csz_xv3_34">
                        <li id="101">
                            <p id="102">Y-axis displays the AVS CPU utilization level, from
                                0 to 100%.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="103">
                            <p id="104">A solid black line tracking the maximum utilization level.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="105">
                            <p id="106">Dark blue bars indicating the average utilization level.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry id="115">
                <dt id="116">Provider Network Port Utilization</dt>
                <dd id="117">
                    <fig id="fig_N10237_N10234_N1022D_N10096_N10020_N10001" id="118">
                        <image href="jow1404333638899.image" id="image_zcq_4v3_34" id="119" width="2.25in"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p id="120">Presents information about network traffic levels on provider networks across the
            entire cluster. Elements in this chart are as follows:</p>
                    <ul id="ul_t5r_yv3_34">
                        <li id="121">
                            <p id="122">Y-axis displays the port utilization level, from 0 to 100%.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="123">
                            <p id="124">A solid black line tracking the maximum utilization level.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="125">
                            <p id="126">Pairs of dark blue and dark green bars indicating the average utilization level,
                egress and ingress (Tx and Rx) traffic respectively.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li id="127">
                            <p id="128">A gray line tracking the minimum utilization level.</p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
        </dl>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>