<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE referable-content PUBLIC "-//IXIA//DTD DITA Referable-Content//EN" "../../system/dtd/ixia/referable-content.dtd">
<referable-content id="jow1439307476374" xml:lang="en-us">
<title ixia_locid="148">[RC:postreq] PCI passthrough and SR-IOV postrequisites</title>
<rcbody>
        <postreq id="postreq_N1023B_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="127">
            <p ixia_locid="128">Access switches must be properly configured to ensure that virtual
                machines using PCI-passthrough or SR-IOV Ethernet interfaces (the latter discussed
                in <xref href="psa1428687672712.xml" ixia_locid="129"/>) have the expected
                connectivity. In a common scenario, the virtual machine using these interfaces
                connects to external end points only, that is, it does not connect to other virtual
                machines in the same cluster. In this case:</p>
            <ul id="ul_pz2_w4w_rr">
                <li ixia_locid="130">
                    <p ixia_locid="131">Traffic between the virtual machine and the access switch
                        can be tagged or untagged.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="144">
                    <p ixia_locid="146">The connecting port on the access switch is part of a
                        port-based VLAN.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="145">
                    <p ixia_locid="147">If the port is tagged, the allowed VLAN ID range must not
                        overlap with VLAN ID ranges used by the AVS ports. </p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="134">
                    <p ixia_locid="135">The port-based VLAN provides the required connectivity to
                        external switching and routing equipment needed by guest applications to
                        establish connections to the intended end points.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p ixia_locid="136">For connectivity to other virtual machines in the cluster the
                following configuration is also required:</p>
            <ul id="ul_ngs_nvw_rr">
                <li ixia_locid="137">
                    <p ixia_locid="138">The VLAN ID used for the tenant network, 10 in this example,
                        and the default port VLAN ID of the access port on the switch are the same.
                        This ensures that incoming traffic from the virtual machine is tagged
                        internally by the switch as belonging to VLAN ID 10, and switched to the
                        appropriate exit ports.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="139">
                    <p ixia_locid="140">The target virtual machines are reachable through another
                        port on the compute node, which is managed by the AVS.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="141">
                    <p ixia_locid="142">That other port is configured as usual, as a VLAN trunk
                        port, and the tenant network's VLAN ID (10) is included in the tagged range.
                        This ensures that VLAN 10 is common to both the passthrough/SR-IOV interface
                        and the AVS port.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </postreq>
    </rcbody>
</referable-content>