<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="jow1437759656219" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Deploying Redundant Top-of-Rack Switches</title>
    <shortdesc>For a system that uses link aggregation on some or all networks, you
        can configure redundant top-of-rack switches for additional reliability. </shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <context id="context_N1001F_N1001C_N10001">
            <p>In a redundant ToR switch configuration, each link in a link
                aggregate is connected to a different switch, as shown in the accompanying figure.
                If one switch fails, another is available to service the link aggregate.</p>
            <fig id="fig_z3x_cqg_vs">
                <title>Redundant Top-of-Rack Switches</title>
                <image href="jow1438030468959.image" id="image_fnv_nqg_vs">
                    <alt>Redundant Top-of-Rack Switches</alt>
                </image>
            </fig>
            <p>Switches that support Virtual Port Channel (VPC) are recommended. When
                VPC is used, the aggregated links on the switches act as a single LAG interface.
                Both switches are normally active, providing full bandwidth to the LAG. If there are
                multiple failed links on both switches, at least one connection in each aggregate
                pair is still functional. If one switch fails, the other continues to provide
                connections for all LAG links that are operational on that switch. For more about
                configuring VPC, refer to your switch documentation.</p>
            <p>You can also use an active/standby failover model for the switches,
                but at some cost to overall reliability. If there are multiple failed links on both
                switches, then optimally the switch with the greatest number of functioning links is
                activated, but some links on that switch could be in a failed state. In addition,
                when only one link in an aggregate is connected to an active switch, the LAG
                bandwidth is limited to the single link.</p>
            <note id="note_N1003F_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
                <p>You can further enhance system reliability by using redundant
                    routers. For more information, refer to your router documentation.</p>
            </note>
        </context>
    </body>
</task-wr>