<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333736797" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">The Internal Management Network</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The internal management network is a private network, visible only to
        the hosts in the cluster.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
         
        <author></author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="4">You must consider the following guidelines:</p>
        <ul id="ul_gqd_gj2_4n">
            <li ixia_locid="13">
                <p ixia_locid="14"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="17">US62804
                        reworded</draft-comment>By default, the management network is used for PXE
                    booting of new hosts, and therefore must be untagged. If, for deployment
                    reasons, the management network needs to be on a VLAN-tagged network, you can
                    configure the optional untagged PXE boot network for PXE booting of new
                    hosts.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="7">
                <p ixia_locid="8">You can use any 1G or 10 G interface on the hosts to connect to
                    this network, provided that the interface supports network booting and can be
                    configured from the BIOS as the primary boot device.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="18">
                <p ixia_locid="19"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="20">US62814 added</draft-comment>You can choose
                    dynamic or static IP address assignment. If you use static assignment, you must
                    manually assign IP addresses on the management network for the other hosts in
                    the cluster using the <cmdname ixia_locid="21">system host-add</cmdname> or <cmdname ixia_locid="22">system
                        host-update</cmdname> commands. <note id="note_N1005C_N1004B_N10048_N1002A_N10022_N10001" ixia_locid="23">
                        <p ixia_locid="24">The infrastructure network is automatically assigned the same type of
                            address assignment as the management network.</p>
                    </note></p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="9">
                <p ixia_locid="10">For the IPv4 address plan, use a private IPv4 subnet as specified
                    in RFC 1918. This  helps prevent unwanted cross-network traffic on this
                    network.</p>
                <p ixia_locid="11">It is suggested that you use the default subnet and addresses provided by the controller
     configuration script.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="25">
                <p ixia_locid="26"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="27">US62814
                        added</draft-comment>You can assign a range of addresses on the management
                    subnet for use by HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. If you do not assign a range, HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                    takes ownership of all available addresses.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="15">
                <p conref="jow1419267499106.xml#jow1419267499106/multicast_in_use" ixia_locid="16"/>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>