<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="jow1438192116883" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Configuring SNAT on a Virtual Router</title>
    <shortdesc>Source Network Address Translation (SNAT) provides network address
        translation for internally initiated UDP and TCP traffic flows. A virtual router with SNAT
        enabled translates between IP addresses and ports used on an internal network, and an IP
        address and ports used on an external network.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <context id="context_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
            <p>You can enable or disable Source Network Address Translation for each
                individual external network connection on a virtual router. By default, SNAT is
                enabled for all external networks.</p>
            <p>When SNAT is enabled, the virtual router maintains network
                translation tables for all internally-initiated UDP and TCP traffic flows. An
                instance connected to an internal tenant network can initiate connections to servers
                on an external, usually public, network. SNAT does <i>not</i> allow
                external servers to initiate connections to external addresses mapped to internal
                addresses. For this capability, the use of floating IP addresses <!-- for future use: or DNAT -->is
                required.</p>
            <p>System administrators can enable or disable SNAT using the following
                command:</p>
            <codeblock><systemoutput>~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput>neutron router-update <varname>routername</varname> --external_gateway_info type=dict \
network_id=<varname>externalnetwork</varname>,enable_snat=<varname>boolean</varname></userinput></codeblock>
            <p>where:</p>
            <parml>
                <plentry>
                    <pt><varname>routername</varname></pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>is the name or UUID of the virtual router</p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt><varname>externalnetwork</varname></pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>is the name or UUID of the external network</p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
                <plentry>
                    <pt><varname>boolean</varname></pt>
                    <pd>
                        <p>is <option>true</option> (to enable SNAT)
                            or <option>false</option> (to disable SNAT)</p>
                    </pd>
                </plentry>
            </parml>
            <note id="note_N100A7_N10022_N1001F_N10001" type="caution">
                <p>For SNMP implemented on guests, the following limitations apply
                    when SNAT is enabled:</p>
                <ul id="ul_h2h_czk_xs">
                    <li>
                        <p>An SNMP agent on an internal network cannot receive
                            requests from SNMP managers on external networks.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p>An SNMP manager on an internal network cannot receive
                            traps from SNMP agents on external networks, even if communication is
                            initiated by the manager. This is because SNMP traps are sent to UDP
                            port 162, not to the source port.</p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>Only agent responses to requests from a manager on the internal
                    network are processed appropriately.</p>
                <p>To overcome these limitations, you can use floating IP addresses
                    or make internal addresses public. For more information, see <xref href="jow1438192231731.xml"/>.</p>
            </note>
        </context>
    </body>
</task-wr>