<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1443819549360" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title>Sensors</title>
 <shortdesc>The <b>Sensors</b> tab on the <b>Inventory Detail</b> page presents details for sensors used to monitor host
  hardware health.</shortdesc>
 <prolog><author/>
  <author/>
 </prolog>
 <body>
  <p><draft-comment author="jowens">US64069 new
   topic</draft-comment>If an optional board management control (BMC) module is present on the host
   and configured for the host in the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade inventory, and sensor support is implemented
   for the BMC type in HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, this tab lists the available sensors and shows their status.
   It also lists <term>sensor groups</term> that have been defined for the sensors. </p>
  <note id="note_N10035_N10024_N10001">
   <p>Currrently, sensor support is implemented for Quanta BMCs. For more about BMC
    modules, see <xref href="jow1406727863674.xml"/>.</p>
  </note>
  
   <image href="jow1443825878164.image" id="image_mxs_pk1_4t">
    <alt>TiS Inventory Detail Sensors tab</alt>
   </image>
  
  <section id="section_N100AE_N10024_N10001">
   <title>Sensor Status</title>
   <p>Each of the individual sensors in the <codeph>Sensors</codeph> list can report the following <codeph>Status</codeph> conditions:</p>
   <ul id="ul_uzg_q5t_4t">
    <li>
     <p>OK</p>
    </li>
    <li>
     <p>Minor</p>
    </li>
    <li>
     <p>Major</p>
    </li>
    <li>
     <p>Critical</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
   <!-- controversial, so hidden for now: dl>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>OK</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>normal; no action required</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>Minor</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>sub-optimal, but within working tolerances</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>Major</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>outside working tolerances, but within functional tolerances</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>Critical</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>outside functional tolerances</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
   </dl -->
   <p>The status of each sensor is audited periodically to refresh the system
    monitoring data. You can configure the refresh period, or <codeph>audit
     interval</codeph>, for sensor groups.</p>
   <!-- NOT FOR ER2: p>Ceilometer meter samples are generated for each sensor at intervals of one hour, or more
    frequently if a significant change occurs.</p -->
  </section>
  <section id="section_N10105_N10024_N10001">
   <title>Actions</title>
   <p>You can configure different actions for each status level using sensor groups.
    The configured action applies to all sensors in the sensor group. Currently two types of action
    are supported:<dl>
     <dlentry>
      <dt>alarm</dt>
      <dd>
       <p>This generates a HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade alarm with a severity level corresponding
        to the sensor status level. For more about HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade alarms, see <xref href="jow1432045490465.xml"/>.</p>
       <p>For the status levels <codeph>Major</codeph> and
         <codeph>Critical</codeph>, it also sets the <codeph>Availability State</codeph> of the host to <codeph>Degraded</codeph>. For more about availability states, see <xref href="jow1404333790046.xml"/>.</p>
      </dd>
     </dlentry>
     <dlentry>
      <dt>ignore</dt>
      <dd>
       <p>The status is reported in the Sensor list, but no action is taken.</p>
      </dd>
     </dlentry>
    </dl>
   </p>
   <p>You can suppress the configured <codeph>Action</codeph> for individual sensors or groups of sensors. Suppressed sensors are still
    audited, and their status is reported in the <codeph>Sensors</codeph>
    list. For more information, see <xref href="jow1443819658894.xml"/>. </p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1004D_N10024_N10001">
   <title>Sensor Groups</title>
   <p>Sensors that perform the same type of monitoring are collected into
     <codeph>Sensor Groups</codeph>. You can configure audit intervals and
    alarm actions for each group. The configured values apply to all sensors in the group. For more
    information, see <xref href="jow1443819602961.xml"/>.</p>
   <p>The available Sensor Groups and their membership are predefined in Titanium
    Server.</p>
   <dl>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>server fans</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>Sensors that monitor the speed and health of CPU cooling fans.</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>power supply fans</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>Sensors that monitor the speed and health of power supply cooling fans.</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>server voltage</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>Sensors that monitor DC voltage levels supplied to components.</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>server temperature</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>Sensors that monitor component or ambient temperatures.</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry>
     <dt>server power</dt>
     <dd>
      <p>Sensors that monitor the operational status of power supplies.</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
   </dl>
  </section>
 </body>
</topic>