<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE map PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Map//EN" "map.dtd">

    <!-- Modification History

 -->
    <title id="1">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Overview</title>
    <shortdesc id="2">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is a high-performance, high-availability,
        cloud operating system that enables telecommunications operators to use
        Commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) hardware to manage Virtualized Network Functions (VNF)
        within a carrier grade Network Function Virtualization (NFV) architecture.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author id="254">Jim Owens</author>
        <author id="255">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p id="5">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade brings together the flexibility and scalability of the IT
            cloud, and the high-availability and performance demanded by the Telecommunications
            industry, into a unique carrier grade, industry-leading solution to deliver a
            price-performance ratio well above alternative solutions. HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is aligned
            with the ETSI-NFV architecture.</p>
        <section id="section_N10027_N1001C_N10001" id="6">
            <title id="7">Core HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Capabilities</title>
            <p id="8">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade leverages core Wind River virtualization and
                carrier-grade technologies, Intel DPDK high-performance packet processing, open
                architectures, and the OpenStack software suite. It extends the OpenStack software
                suite to implement a unique carrier-grade, high-availability architecture, on which
                high-performance production systems can be deployed.</p>
            <p id="9">Core capabilities unique to HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade include:</p>
            <dl>
                <!--<dlentry id="16">
                    <dt id="17"><nameliteral id="18">Supported Guest
                            OSs</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="19">
                        <p id="20">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is designed to work with any Linux
                            Distribution. Wind River Linux, Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, and
                            Ubuntu have been sanity tested as OSs in the Guest virtual machines.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>--><!-- 2014-12-18 moved to Release Notes -->
                <dlentry id="21">
                    <dt id="22"><nameliteral id="23">High-Performance
                            Networking</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="24">
                        <p id="25">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade provides significantly improved network
                            performance over the default open source OpenStack solution, up to 20
                            Gbps throughput through a guest application on a virtual machine.</p>
                        <p id="26">At the center of the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Networking is a
                            DPDK-Accelerated Virtual L2 Switch (AVS), running on the compute node
                            hosts. It provides connectivity between virtual machines on the same
                            compute node, and between virtual machines and external networks. AVS
                            supports a variety of network connectivity options with the hosted
                            virtual machines, as follows:</p>
                        <ul id="ul_mgc_xnp_nn">
                            <li id="27">
                                <p id="28">Unmodified guests can use Linux networking and
                                    virtio drivers. This provides a mechanism to bring existing
                                    applications into the production environment immediately.</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="29">
                                <p id="30">Guest applications can be modified to leverage
                                    the Accelerated Virtual Port (AVP) drivers provided with the
                                    HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. AVP ports provide increased throughput over
                                    plain virtio drivers when connected to the AVS.</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="31">
                                <p id="32">For the highest performance, guest applications
                                    can also be modified to make use of the Intel DPDK libraries and
                                    the AVP poll-mode drivers provided by the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade to
                                    connect with the AVS Switch.</p>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                        <p id="253">In addition to AVS, HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade incorporates DPDK-Accelerated Neutron
                            Virtual Router L3 Forwarding (AVR). Accelerated forwarding is used
                            between directly attached tenant networks and subnets, as well as for
                            gateway, SNAT, and floating IP functionality.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="33">
                    <dt id="34"><nameliteral id="35">High-Availability</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="36">
                        <p id="37">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade provides a number of extensions to
                            OpenStack to deliver highly available hosting of virtual machines,
                            including:</p>
                        <dl>
                            <dlentry id="38">
                                <dt id="39">1:1 OpenStack controller services</dt>
                                <dd id="40">
                                    <p id="41">Automatic configuration of the OpenStack
                                        controller services in 1:1 active/standby mode across two
                                        controller nodes. </p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="42">
                                <dt id="43">Fast detection of compute host failures</dt>
                                <dd id="44">
                                    <p id="45">Implemented by using a highly efficient and
                                        highly scalable heartbeat protocol between the controller
                                        and compute nodes.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="46">
                                <dt id="47">Fast recovery of virtual machines instances upon
                                    detection of a compute node failure</dt>
                                <dd id="48">
                                    <p id="49">Extensions to Nova services that
                                        automatically re-schedule impacted virtual machine instances
                                        to available alternative compute nodes in the cluster.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="50">
                                <dt id="51">Fast recovery of tenant network services upon
                                    detection of a compute node failure</dt>
                                <dd id="52">
                                    <p id="53">Extensions to Neutron that automatically
                                        re-schedule impacted network services such as DHCP, L3
                                        Routing, and User/Meta data server, for all affected tenant
                                        networks. This covers tenant networks spanning multiple
                                        compute nodes.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="54">
                                <dt id="55">Fast and enhanced detection of virtual machines
                                    failures</dt>
                                <dd id="56">
                                    <p id="57">Failure of any KVM/QEMU instance is
                                        automatically reported by the death process
                                        notification.</p>
                                    <p id="58">Additionally, modified guests can make use of
                                        the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Guest Heartbeat Library to register
                                        application-specific health check callbacks with the virtual
                                        machine. This registration allows Nova compute extensions on
                                        the host compute node to monitor the health of the guest
                                        application. The frequency of the health checks is
                                        determined at registration time. The semantics of the health
                                        check, that is, determining when the application is in a
                                        good or a bad state, is under the control of the application
                                        itself.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="59">
                                <dt id="60">Automatic recovery of failed virtual machine
                                    instances</dt>
                                <dd id="61">
                                    <p id="62">Extensions to Nova that automatically
                                        re-start a failed virtual machine on the same compute node.
                                        If the re-start operation fails, the virtual machine is
                                        re-scheduled to use an alternative compute node.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="63">
                                <dt id="64">Virtual machine server groups</dt>
                                <dd id="65">
                                    <p id="66">Named groups of virtual machines instances to
                                        which a common set of attributes are applied, including:</p>
                                    <ul id="ul_s5y_kbq_nn">
                                        <li id="237">
                                            <p id="239">compute node affinity or
                                                anti-affinity</p>
                                        </li>
                                        <li id="69">
                                            <p id="70">maximum number of virtual machine
                                                instances</p>
                                        </li>
                                        <li id="71">
                                            <p id="72">best effort or strict affinity
                                                policy</p>
                                        </li>
                                    </ul>
                                    <p id="256">Virtual machines in the same server group can use a server
                                        group messaging API for low-bandwidth communications.</p>
                                    <p id="73">In a typical use of a virtual machine server
                                        group, guest applications in active/standby pairs are
                                        deployed on different compute nodes to protect them from
                                        hardware failures.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="74">
                                <dt id="75">Live migration support with DPDK-accelerated
                                    networking</dt>
                                <dd id="76">
                                    <p id="77">Live migration support for virtual machines
                                        using the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade high-performance networking
                                        options.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="78">
                                <dt id="79">Graceful shutdown (and other operations) of
                                    virtual machines</dt>
                                <dd id="80">
                                    <p id="81">Nova extensions that turn the default
                                        shutdown operation of virtual machines into an ACPI
                                        shutdown. Guest applications can therefore register shutdown
                                        scripts using standard ACPI mechanisms to execute operations
                                        such as closing files, updating persistent databases, or
                                        cleanly disconnecting from subscribed services.</p>
                                    <p id="82">Optionally, guest applications can use the
                                        HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Guest Heartbeat Library to register to
                                        receive process management requests such as shutdown,
                                        live-migrate, pause, auto-scale, and others. The guest
                                        applications can then reject the requests based
                                        upon application-specific state directives, or prepare for a
                                        graceful execution.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="83">
                                <dt id="84">Link Aggregation (LAG) support</dt>
                                <dd id="85">
                                    <p id="86">Support for LAG, also known as Aggregate
                                        Ethernet, on controller and compute nodes for link
                                        protection.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                            <dlentry id="231">
                                <dt id="232">Protected HA Middleware</dt>
                                <dd id="233">
                                    <p id="234">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade HA
                                        middleware is protected by a process monitor that uses death
                                        process notification to detect and respawn critical HA
                                        processes.</p>
                                </dd>
                            </dlentry>
                        </dl>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="87">
                    <dt id="88"><nameliteral id="89">Virtual Machine
                            Performance</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="90">
                        <p id="91">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade provides an improved execution
                            environment for virtual machines that contributes to their overall
                            performance when deployed on the compute nodes. Enhancements to the
                            execution environment include:</p>
                        <ul id="ul_rx5_gfs_nn">
                            <li id="92">
                                <p id="93">Low-latency, bounded delivery of virtual
                                    interrupts, and availability of low-latency high resolution
                                    timers. </p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="94">
                                <p id="95">Option to allocate 2 MB or 1 GB huge memory pages
                                    to reduce swapping and TLB lookup misses.</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="96">
                                <p id="97">Improved resource tracking of VMs that use
                                    dedicated CPUs, to ensure successful migration and
                                    evacuation.</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="99">
                                <p id="100">Support for affining guest NUMA nodes to
                                    specific host NUMA nodes.</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="204">
                                <p id="205">Capability to specify specific CPU models to be used by a virtual
                                    machine in order to leverage advanced features of the CPU
                                    architecture.</p>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="247">
                    <dt id="248"><nameliteral id="252">Guest VLANs</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="249">
                        <p id="250">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade guests can make use of VLANs to
                            encapsulate IP traffic from a single or multiple IP subnets on a virtual
                            Ethernet interface. This capability facilitates the porting of current
                            user applications running on dedicated physical servers using VLANs to a
                            virtualized environment.</p>
                        <p id="251">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade tenants can define multiple IP subnets
                            on a single tenant network, get their traffic encapsulated on VLAN IDs
                            of their choice, and still benefit from the underlying functionality
                            provided by the AVS and the overall virtualized network
                            infrastructure.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="101">
                    <dt id="102"><nameliteral id="103">Inventory
                            Management</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="104">
                        <p id="105">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade provides complete inventory management
                            of hosts in the OpenStack cloud, allowing the system administrator to
                            install, configure, and maintain the individual servers. The inventory
                            service gives the system administrator the following capabilities:</p>
                        <ul id="ul_xyb_2bt_nn">
                            <li id="106">
                                <p id="107">Host management</p>
                                <ul id="ul_afq_fbt_nn">
                                    <li id="108">
                                        <p id="109">discovery of new hosts in the
                                            cluster</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="110">
                                        <p id="111">installation of the appropriate load,
                                            controller, compute, or storage images</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="112">
                                        <p id="113">configuration of the management, OAM,
                                            infrastructure, and provider network interfaces on each
                                            host</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="114">
                                        <p id="115">creation and use of data interface and
                                            CPU profiles to simplify host configuration</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="116">
                                        <p id="117">configuration of the number of CPUs
                                            allocated to the Accelerated Virtual Switch (AVS) on
                                            each compute node</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="245">
                                        <p id="246">configuration of huge memory page allocations for VM
                                            use</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li id="118">
                                <p id="119">Administrative operations</p>
                                <ul id="ul_px4_nms_nn">
                                    <li id="120">
                                        <p id="121">lock/unlock</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="122">
                                        <p id="123">switch active controller host or
                                            service</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="124">
                                        <p id="125">reboot and reset host</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="235">
                                        <p id="236">power-on and power-off</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="126">
                                        <p id="127">software re-installation</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li id="128">
                                <p id="129">Status reporting</p>
                                <ul id="ul_qgg_rms_nn">
                                    <li id="130">
                                        <p id="131">admin state</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="132">
                                        <p id="133">operational state</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="134">
                                        <p id="135">availability state</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="136">
                                        <p id="137">uptime</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="138">
                                        <p id="139">real-time command execution reports,
                                            such as booting and testing</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li id="140">
                                <p id="141">Host resources</p>
                                <ul id="ul_x3s_xms_nn">
                                    <li id="142">
                                        <p id="143">processor, sockets, cores</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="144">
                                        <p id="145">memory</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="146">
                                        <p id="147">disk</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="148">
                                        <p id="149">network interfaces</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="150">
                                        <p id="151">additional hardware devices, such as
                                            cryptographic and compression devices</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <!--<dlentry id="161"><dt id="162"><nameliteral id="163">Power Management</nameliteral></dt><dd id="164"><p id="165">A cloud orchestration service that monitors and manages the resource usage on the compute nodes to power down servers during periods of low usage. This service contributes to saving power and operational costs.</p><p id="166">By continuously monitoring the resource usage, the power management service can de-fragment the service cloud by live-migrating virtual machine instances onto a smaller set of compute nodes. Unused hosts can then be manually powered down.</p><p id="167">As the cloud usage levels rise, unused compute nodes can be manually powered on to host new virtual machine instances.</p></dd></dlentry>-->
                <dlentry id="168">
                    <dt id="169"><nameliteral id="170">Performance Management
                            Extensions</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="171">
                        <p id="172">The Ceilometer service in the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade features
                            improved performance, scalability, and usability. It has been extended
                            to support a CSV-formatted file backend that provides a more traditional
                            Telco Northbound interface for performance management.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="173">
                    <dt id="174"><nameliteral id="175">Improved Web Administration
                            Interface</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="176">
                        <p id="177">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade web administration interface is an
                            enhanced version of the Horizon web interface provided by OpenStack. The
                            enhancements include:</p>
                        <ul id="ul_xyt_r1t_nn">
                            <li id="178">
                                <p id="179">Automatic page refresh for immediate
                                    notification of status changes. This eliminates the need for
                                    manual reloading of web pages to access up-to-date information
                                    about the cloud</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="180">
                                <p id="181">Admin Overview page with charts and tables
                                    providing a high-level overview of cloud resources</p>
                                <ul id="ul_kcf_qbt_nn">
                                    <li id="182">
                                        <p id="183">avg/max/min compute vCPU usage</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="184">
                                        <p id="185">avg/max/min compute memory usage</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="186">
                                        <p id="187">avg/max/min compute disk usage</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="188">
                                        <p id="189">avg/max/min AVS CPU utilization</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="190">
                                        <p id="191">avg/max/min provider network port
                                            utilization</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="192">
                                        <p id="193">current host status (available,
                                            unavailable, locked, unlocked)</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li id="194">
                                <p id="195">Improved performance management resource usage
                                    web page</p>
                                <ul id="ul_cr2_kct_nn">
                                    <li id="196">
                                        <p id="197">optimized performance management sample
                                            DB queries for improved usability</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="198">
                                        <p id="199">capability to filter on fields in the
                                            performance management sample metadata</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="200">
                                        <p id="201">human-readable legends and chart labels
                                            using object names instead of long UUID text strings</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="202">
                                        <p id="203">performance management meters can be
                                            selected using their brief descriptions</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="206">
                                        <p id="207">meters for CPU, memory, and disk utilization</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="208">
                    <dt id="209"><nameliteral id="241">Heat Extensions</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="210">
                        <p id="211">The OpenStack Heat orchestration service is enhanced to include:</p>
                        <ul id="ul_n5s_kbh_tp">
                            <li id="212">
                                <p id="213">Support for several missing resource types in the public
                                    reference implementation</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="214">
                                <p id="215">Helpful example templates illustrating real reference
                                    scenarios</p>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="216">
                    <dt id="217"><nameliteral id="242">Backup and Restore</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="218">
                        <p id="219">Tools and procedures to backup and restore system data
                            and virtual machines.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="220">
                    <dt id="221"><nameliteral id="243">Patching</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="222">
                        <p id="223">Tools and procedures to patch system images to ensure they are always up
                            to date with the latest release and security fixes.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="224">
                    <dt id="225"><nameliteral id="244">Alarms Generation and
                        Reporting</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="226">
                        <ul id="ul_ltp_xch_tp">
                            <li id="227">
                                <p id="228">alarms on performance management thresholds and cloud-level
                                    services and equipment</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="229">
                                <p id="230">SNMPv2c support</p>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="10">
                    <dt id="11"><nameliteral id="12">Supported OpenStack
                            Services</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="13">
                        <p id="14">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade integrates the
                            following OpenStack services into its cloud solution: Nova, Neutron,
                            Keystone, Glance, Cinder, Horizon, Ceilometer, Heat and Swift.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="257">
                    <dt id="258"><nameliteral id="311">REST API</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="259">
                        <p id="260">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade supports the following external REST
                            APIs through its OAM floating IP address:</p>
                        <ul id="ul_ylk_dcv_ds">
                            <li id="331">
                                <p id="332">OpenStack REST APIs</p>
                                <ul id="ul_jry_kvz_cs">
                                    <li>
                                        <p>Object Storage API</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="333">
                                        <p id="338">Block Storage API (with HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                                            extensions)</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="334">
                                        <p id="339">Compute API  (with HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                                            extensions)</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="335">
                                        <p id="340">Identity API</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="336">
                                        <p id="341">Image Service API</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="263">
                                        <p id="264">Networking API  (with HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                                            extensions)</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="337">
                                        <p id="342">Orchestration API</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="265">
                                        <p id="266">Telemetry API (with HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                                            extensions)</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                            <li id="345">
                                <p id="346">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade REST APIs</p>
                                <ul id="ul_xgp_scv_ds">
                                    <li id="347">
                                        <p id="348">SysInv API</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li id="349">
                                        <p id="350">Patching API</p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                        <note id="note_N1053E_N104EC_N104E8_N104DF_N104D3_N10040_N1002C_N10024_N10001" id="343">
                            <p id="344">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade extensions use the OpenStack
                                Extension Mechanism to ensure compatibility with existing
                                clients.</p>
                        </note>
                        <p id="268">HTTP or HTTPS protocol can be supported for these
                            external REST APIs.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry id="269">
                    <dt id="270"><nameliteral id="312">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade SDK</nameliteral></dt>
                    <dd id="271">
                        <p id="272">The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Development Kit (SDK) provides drivers,
                            daemons, API libraries, and configuration files that you can include in
                            a guest image to leverage the extended capabilities of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade.
                            Available components include:</p>
                        <ul id="ul_zdh_d51_ds">
                            <li id="313">
                                <p id="314">Accelerated Kernel Network Drivers - Drivers for improved
                                    performance of kernel-based networking VNFs</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="315">
                                <p id="316">Accelerated DPDK Network Drivers - Drivers for
                                    high-performance DPDK-based networking VNFs</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="317">
                                <p id="318">VM Resource Scaling - A service for scaling the capacity of a
                                    guest server on demand</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="319">
                                <p id="320">Guest Heartbeat - A service for health monitoring of guest
                                    applications</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="321">
                                <p id="322">Server Group Messaging - A service for low-bandwidth peer
                                    messaging between servers in the same group</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="323">
                                <p id="324">SNMP MIB - Resources for system alarms management</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="325">
                                <p id="326">Sample Heat Orchestration Templates - Resources for deploying
                                    and managing stacks of applications or application services</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="327">
                                <p id="328">OpenStack REST API Documentation - Documentation
                                    for HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade REST APIs and HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade extensions to
                                    OpenStack REST APIs</p>
                            </li>
                            <li id="329">
                                <p id="330">Custom Branding - Resources for customizing the Horizon
                                    GUI</p>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                        <p id="309">For more information, see the <cite id="310">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Development Kit</cite>.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
        </section>
    </conbody>

