<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333744498" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">Quality of Service Policies</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Quality of Service (QoS) policies specify relative packet processing
        priorities applied by the AVS switch on each compute node to incoming tenant network's
        traffic during overload conditions.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author></author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="42">The QoS polices play no role under normal traffic loads, when no input traffic queues in
            the AVS are close to their overflow limits.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="4">QoS policies are created by the cluster administrator, and selected by the
            tenant users to apply on a per-tenant network basis. To create a new QoS policy, log in
            as administrator, select the option <option ixia_locid="5">Networks</option> from the
                <uicontrol ixia_locid="6">Admin</uicontrol> menu, and visit the <uicontrol ixia_locid="7">QoS Policies</uicontrol> tab on the <wintitle ixia_locid="8">Networks</wintitle> page, as illustrated below.</p>
        <fig id="fig_N10031_N1001A_N10001" ixia_locid="9">
            <image href="jow1404333740550.image" id="image_hyt_rrm_44" ixia_locid="10" placement="inline" width="5in"/>
        </fig>
        <p ixia_locid="11">Click the button <uicontrol ixia_locid="12">Create QoS Policy</uicontrol> to display the <wintitle ixia_locid="13">Create QoS
    Policy</wintitle> window.</p>
        <fig id="fig_N10049_N1001A_N10001" ixia_locid="14">
            <image href="jow1404333742007.image" id="image_mw1_1vm_44" ixia_locid="15" placement="inline"/>
        </fig>
        <p ixia_locid="16">The following fields are available:</p>
        <dl>
            <dlentry ixia_locid="17">
                <dt ixia_locid="18">Name</dt>
                <dd ixia_locid="19">
                    <p ixia_locid="20">The name of the new QoS policy. This is the name that the tenant user sees as available for
      use.</p>
                    <p ixia_locid="21">This field is mandatory.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry ixia_locid="22">
                <dt ixia_locid="23">Description</dt>
                <dd ixia_locid="24">
                    <p ixia_locid="25">A free form text for your reference.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry ixia_locid="26">
                <dt ixia_locid="27">Scheduler Weight</dt>
                <dd ixia_locid="28">
                    <p ixia_locid="29">The relative weight the AVS traffic scheduler uses on overload conditions, as compared with
      the scheduler weight of all other QoS policies.</p>
                    <p ixia_locid="30">The scheduler weight is a positive integer number associated
                        with each QoS policy. On overload, the AVS schedules traffic processing for
                        each tenant network according to its assigned QoS policy. By default, with
                        no specific QoS policies defined, traffic from all tenant networks is
                        processed in round-robin mode, one tenant network after another.
                        Effectively, the default behavior is similar to assigning a scheduler weight
                        of 1 to all tenant networks.</p>
                    <p ixia_locid="31">When a specific QoS policy with a scheduler weight greater
                        than 1 is applied to a tenant network, its traffic is scheduled with a
                        relative higher frequency. For example, if the scheduler weight for tenant
                        network A is 10, and the one for tenant network B is 100, then on overload,
                        tenant network B will see its queued traffic processed 10 times as often as
                        tenant network A.</p>
                    <p ixia_locid="32">The handling of the scheduler weight is implemented as a
                        per-packet token bucket for each tenant network. This means that each unit
                        in the scheduler weight counts as one packet to be processed in sequence. In
                        the previous example, the AVS processes 10 consecutive packets from tenant
                        network A, followed by 100 packets from tenant network B. This
                        implementation ensures a fair-share behavior that prevents any tenant
                        network from running into total bandwidth starvation, even if its scheduler
                        weight is relatively low.</p>
                    <p ixia_locid="33">The range of values for the scheduler weight is arbitrary. You must however ensure that the
      values assigned to the different policies make sense for the intended applications.</p>
                    <p ixia_locid="34">This field is mandatory.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry ixia_locid="35">
                <dt ixia_locid="36">Project</dt>
                <dd ixia_locid="37">
                    <p ixia_locid="38">A drop-down menu displaying the currently defined tenants (projects). The new QoS policy is
      available to only the selected tenant. If no tenant is selected, it is available to all
      tenants in the cluster.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
        </dl>
        <p ixia_locid="39">Tenant users can select available QoS policies when the tenant networks
            are created from the <wintitle ixia_locid="40">Create Network</wintitle> window. They
            can also apply a QoS policy to an already existing tenant network from the <wintitle ixia_locid="41">Edit Network</wintitle> window.</p>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>