<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="jow1432045421799" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Viewing Customer Logs</title>
    <shortdesc>You can use the web administration interface or the CLI to examine
        customer logs.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p>To view customer logs, you must be logged in with administrative
                privileges.</p>
        
        
            <p>You can use the command-line interface to view customer logs by
                acquiring Keystone credentials and using the <cmdname>system
                    log-list</cmdname> and <cmdname>system log-show</cmdname>
                commands. Alternatively, you can use the web administration interface using the
                steps given later in this section.</p>
            <ul id="ul_agw_zby_bs">
                <li>
                    <p>To acquire Keystone <codeph>admin</codeph> credentials, type the following command:</p>
                    <codeblock>$ source /etc/nova/openrc</codeblock>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>To list logs, use the following command:</p>
                    <codeblock>~(keystone_admin)$ system log-list [-q <varname>query</varname>] [-l <varname>limit</varname>]</codeblock>
                    <p>where</p>
                    <dl>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt><varname>query</varname></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>is a list of one or more key-value pairs with comparison
                                    operators, separated by semicolons.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                        <dlentry>
                            <dt><varname>limit</varname></dt>
                            <dd>
                                <p>is the maximum number of logs to return, beginning with the most
                                    recent.</p>
                            </dd>
                        </dlentry>
                    </dl>
                    <p>For example:</p>
                    <codeblock>~(keystone_admin)$ system log-list -q severity=critical -l 20</codeblock>
                    <p>returns the 20 most recent logs with <codeph>critical</codeph> severity.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>To view details for an individual log, use the following
                        command:</p>
                    <codeblock>~(keystone_admin)$ system log-show <varname>uuid</varname></codeblock>
                    <p>where <varname>uuid</varname> is the unique
                        identifier for the log (obtained using the <cmdname>system
                            log-list</cmdname> command).</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>In the main menu, select <menucascade>
                        <b>Admin</b>
                        <b>System</b>
                        <b>Fault Management</b>
                    </menucascade>.</li>
            
             
                <li>On the Fault Management page, select the <b>Customer Logs</b>
                    tab.</li>
                
                    <p>The logs are displayed in chronological order, beginning with
                        the most recent.</p>
                    
                        <image href="jow1432054510610.image" id="image_ixf_drx_bs" width="4in">
                            <alt>TiS Customer Logs</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                    <p>By default, 20 items are shown per page. To see older items,
                        scroll to the bottom of the list and click <b>Next</b>. You can change the number of items displayed per page
                        using the <b>Default Limit</b> drop-down
                        list.</p>
                    <p>You can also filter the items using the <b>Filter</b> text box. Type the filter string, and
                        then click the magnifying-glass icon. The results include only those logs
                        that contain the string in the Customer Log Detail.</p>
                
            
             
                <li>To see the Customer Log Detail, click the <b>Timestamp</b>
                    identifier for the log.</li>
                
                    
                        <image href="jow1432055065375.image" id="image_fq4_msx_bs" width="3in">
                            <alt>TiS Customer Log Detail</alt>
                        </image>
                    
                
            
        </ol>
    </body>
</topic>