<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic id="psa1414084582159" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Installing Patches Locally</title>
    <shortdesc>
        <draft-comment author="rstone">US62817 changed wrs-patch -&gt; sw-patch</draft-comment>
    </shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author></author>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        
            <p>When installing the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software on new hardware, it is
                recommended that you install the latest available patches on <codeph>controller-0</codeph> before running the
                    <cmdname>config_controller</cmdname> script, and before installing the software
                on other hosts. This ensures that:</p>
            <ul id="ul_gsq_1ht_vp">
                <li>
                    <p>The software on <codeph>controller-0</codeph>, and all other hosts, is up to date when the
                        cluster comes alive.</p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>You reduce installation time by avoiding patching the system
                        right after an out-of-date software installation is complete.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>This exercise assumes that the patches to install are available on a USB flash drive,
                or from a server reachable by <codeph>controller-0</codeph>.</p>
        
        <ol>
             
                <li>Initialize <codeph>controller-0</codeph>.
                
                    <p>Use the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade bootable ISO image to initialize
                            <codeph>controller-0</codeph>. See the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                            Software Installation Guide</cite> for details.</p>
                
                
                    <p>This step takes you to the point where you use the console
                        port to log in to <codeph>controller-0</codeph> as
                        user <codeph>wrsroot</codeph>.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Copy the patches to the local file system.
                
                    <p>If the patches are on a USB flash drive, copy them from the
                        appropriate mount point to some directory in the local file system. For
                        example:</p>
                
                
                    <codeblock>$ mkdir /tmp/patches $ cp /media/wrsroot/data/TITANIUM_CONTROLLER_14.10_PATCH_0001.patch /tmp/patches</codeblock>
                
                
                    <p>If the patches are available from a remote server, you need
                        to manually initialize a suitable Ethernet interface first, and then
                        transfer them to the local file system. For example:</p>
                    <codeblock>$ mkdir /tmp/patches $ sudo ifconfig eth3 192.168.1.100 netmask 255.255.255.0 up $ scp \
me@192.168.1.150:/usr/local/patches/TITANIUM_CONTROLLER_14.10_PATCH_0001.patch \
/tmp/patches</codeblock>
                
                
                    <p>All patches are now in the directory <filepath>/tmp/patches</filepath>.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Populate the patch storage area.
                
                    <p>Upload the patches using the command <cmdname>sw-patch upload</cmdname> or <cmdname>sw-patch
                            upload-dir</cmdname> as described in <xref href="psa1410446807133.xml"/>.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Apply the patches.
                
                    <p>Apply the patches using the command <cmdname>sw-patch apply --all</cmdname>.</p>
                
                
                    <p>The patches are now in the software updates repository, ready to be
                        installed.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Install the patches locally.
                
                    <codeblock>$ sudo sw-patch install-local Patch installation is complete.
Please reboot before continuing with configuration.</codeblock>
                
                
                    <p>This command installs all applied patches on <codeph>controller-0</codeph>.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Reboot <codeph>controller-0</codeph>.
                
                    <p>You must reboot the controller to ensure that it is running with the software
                        fully patched.</p>
                
                </li>
             
                <li>Continue the installation.
                
                    <p>Log in again as <codeph>wrsroot</codeph> and
                        continue with the software installation by running the <cmdname>config_controller</cmdname> script. See the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide</cite> for
                        further details and directions.</p>
                </li>
            
        </ol>
        
            <p>Once all hosts in the cluster are initialized, they are all running
                fully patched software. The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade cluster is up to date.</p>
        
    </body>
</topic>
