<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="rst1441822551049" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Specifying a Live Migration Timeout</title>
    <shortdesc>Live migrations can take a long time to complete for reasons such as
        high levels of guest activity, network latency, and so on. You can specify the number of
        seconds to wait for a live migration to complete. </shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author>Ron Stone</author>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <context id="context_N1001F_N1001C_N10001">
            <p><draft-comment author="rstone">Topic created for
                    US60539</draft-comment>If no value is set, the default is 800 seconds.</p>
            <p>If the value is exceeded, the migration is canceled and a customer
                log entry is created. The counter starts when the migration begins. The minimum
                timeout value is 120 seconds and the maximum is 800 seconds. <draft-comment author="rstone">Following sentence to be confirmed</draft-comment>Set this value
                to 0 to disable the live migration timeout feature. For more information, see <xref href="jow1404333655771.xml"/>. </p>
            <note id="note_N10044_N10029_N10026_N10001">
                <p>NOVA maintains an internal timer which guards a complete lack of
                    VM instance live migration progress for longer than 150 seconds. If this timer
                    expires, the live migration will be canceled; regardless of the value of the
                    live migration maximum timeout.</p>
            </note>
            <p>A live migration timeout can be configured as an extra spec on a
                flavor, such that any VM instance created with the flavor will inherit the specified
                timeout value. Alternatively, a live migration timeout can be configured as
                meta-data on an image, such that any VM instance created based on this Image will
                have the specified timeout value. If the timeout value is provisioned in both the
                flavor and the image, the smaller value is used.</p>
            <p>To set this option using the web administration interface:</p>
            <ul id="ul_xy2_v3y_lt">
                <li>
                    <p>As <term>admin</term>, use the <uicontrol>Live Migration Timeout</uicontrol> selection in the <uicontrol>Create Flavor Extra Spec</uicontrol> drop-down menu. To
                        access this menu, see <xref href="jow1429538642910.xml"/>.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>or</p>
            <ul id="ul_sbp_djy_lt">
                <li>
                    <p>As either <term>admin</term> or a tenant, select
                            <menucascade>
                            <uicontrol>System</uicontrol>
                            <uicontrol>Images</uicontrol>
                            <uicontrol>Edit Image</uicontrol>
                            <uicontrol>Update Metadata</uicontrol>
                        </menucascade> for the desired images and add an entry with:</p>
                    <codeblock>hw_wrs_live_migration_timeout=<varname>seconds</varname></codeblock>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </context>
        <ol>
            <step id="step_N10035_N10032_N1001C_N10001">
                <cmd>Set the timer from the command line:</cmd>
                
                    <p>The following examples set the timeout to 400 seconds.</p>
                
                <choices id="choices_iks_2wn_ht">
                    <choice>
                        <p>As <term>admin</term>, add an extra spec to a flavor
                            by:</p>
                        <codeblock><systemoutput>~(keystone)admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput>nova flavor-key <varname>flavorName</varname> set hw:wrs:live_migration_timeout=400</userinput></codeblock>
                    </choice>
                    <choice>
                        <p>As <term>admin</term> or a tenant, update the metadata
                            of an image by:</p>
                        <codeblock><systemoutput>~(keystone)admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput>glance image-update --property hw_wrs_live_migration_timeout=400 <varname>imageName</varname></userinput></codeblock>
                    </choice>
                </choices>
            </step>
        </ol>
    </body>
</task-wr>