<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE topic   PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic id="jow1413726916641" xml:lang="en-us"><!-- Modification History        -->    <title >Changing the OAM IP Configuration</title>    <shortdesc >You can change the External OAM subnet, floating IP address, controller addresses,        and default gateway at any time after installation.</shortdesc>    <prolog>        <author >Jim Owens</author>    </prolog>    <body>        <section id="section_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" >            <p >During software installation, the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is configured with                an OAM network subnet and related IP addresses. You can change these addresses using                the web administration interface or the CLI.</p>            <note id="note_N1002F_N1002B_N1001D_N10001"  type="caution">                <p >Access to the OAM network is interrupted during this procedure. When a swact is                    performed on the controllers, the newly active controller uses the changed OAM                    IP addresses. The existing OAM IP addresses are no longer valid, and you must                    use the new OAM IP addresses to reconnect to the controller. Changes to external                    OAM access routing settings may also be required. In addition, VNC console                    access to compute-node hosts is interrupted until the hosts are locked and                    unlocked.</p>            </note>        </section>        <section id="section_N1002B_N1001D_N10001" >            <p >Before changing the OAM IP configuration, review the Fault Management                page and ensure that any existing system alarms are cleared.</p>        </section>        <ol id="ol_xfh_24z_5p">            <li id="li_N1002B_N10028_N1001C_N10001" >                <p >In the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade web administration interface, open the                        <wintitle >System Configuration</wintitle> pane.</p>                                    <p >The <wintitle >System Configuration</wintitle>                        pane is available from the <uicontrol >System                            Panel</uicontrol> section of the <uicontrol >Admin</uicontrol> menu. </p>                            </li>            <li id="li_N1004A_N10028_N1001C_N10001" >                <p >Select the <wintitle >OAM IP</wintitle>                    tab.</p>                                    <p >The <wintitle >OAM IP</wintitle> page                        appears, showing the currently defined OAM network configuration.</p>                    <fig id="fig_t3s_4mz_5p" >                        <image href="jow1413850481192.image" id="image_qjr_p1d_vp"  width="6in">                            <alt >OAM IP page</alt>                        </image>                    </fig>                            </li>            <li id="li_N10070_N10028_N1001C_N10001" >                <p >Click <uicontrol >Edit OAM IP</uicontrol>.</p>                                    <p >The <wintitle >Edit OAM IP</wintitle> dialog                        box appears.</p>                    <fig id="fig_tmw_qnz_5p" >                        <image href="jow1413850497887.image" id="image_fp4_r1d_vp"  width="4in">                            <alt >Edit OAM IP dialog</alt>                        </image>                    </fig>                            </li>            <li id="li_N1009A_N10028_N1001C_N10001" >                <p >Replace the IP addresses with different ones as required.</p>            </li>            <li id="li_N100CE_N1003A_N1001D_N10001" >                <p >Click <uicontrol >Save</uicontrol>.</p>                                    <p >This raises major alarms against the controllers and                        services. You can view the alarms on the Fault Management page.</p>                            </li>            <li id="li_N100BF_N1002B_N1001D_N10001" >                <p >Lock and unlock the controllers to clear the alarms.</p>                                    <p >Open the <wintitle >Hosts</wintitle> list by                        clicking <uicontrol >Inventory</uicontrol> on the<wintitle > System Panel</wintitle> section of the <wintitle >Admin</wintitle> menu, and then selecting the <uicontrol >Hosts</uicontrol> tab. Hosts requiring attention are                        shown with the status <b >Config                            out-of-date</b>.</p>                    <p >To lock or unlock a host, click <uicontrol >More</uicontrol> for the host and then use the menu selections.</p>                                <ol id="ol_zyf_rsz_5p">                    <li >                        <p >Lock the standby controller. </p>                                                    <p >Wait for the lock operation to be completed.</p>                                            </li>                    <li >                        <p >Unlock the standby controller.</p>                                                    <p >Wait for the host to become available. It is updated                                with the new OAM configuration, and its error message is                                cleared.</p>                                            </li>                    <li >                        <p >Perform a swact on the active controller.</p>                                                    <p >Click <menucascade >                                    <uicontrol >More</uicontrol>                                    <uicontrol >Swact Host</uicontrol>                                    <uicontrol > </uicontrol>                                </menucascade> for the active controller.</p>                            <note id="note_N10181_N10164_N1015B_N1012F_N100F2_N1003F_N1001F_N10001" >                                <p >After the swact, the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade begins using the new OAM                                    network configuration. If you have changed the OAM subnet or the                                    OAM floating IP address, the current web session is terminated.                                    To continue using the web administration interface, you must                                    start a new session and log in using the new IP address. You may                                    also need to update router tables to establish a connection.                                </p>                            </note>                                            </li>                    <li >                        <p >Lock the original controller (now in standby                            mode).</p>                                                    <p >Wait for the lock operation to be completed.</p>                                            </li>                    <li >                        <p >Unlock the original controller.</p>                                                    <p >Wait for it to become available. It is updated with                                the new OAM configuration, and its error message is cleared.</p>                                            </li>                </ol>            </li>            <li id="li_N101BC_N1003F_N1001F_N10001" >                <p >Lock and unlock each compute node.</p>                                    <note id="note_N101C5_N101C2_N101BB_N1003F_N1001F_N10001"  type="caution">                        <p >Before locking a compute node, ensure that sufficient                            resources are available on other hosts to migrate any running                            instances.</p>                    </note>                            </li>            <li id="li_N1025E_N100B7_N1001F_N10001" >                <p >Ensure that the <b >250.001                        Configuration out-of-date</b> alarms are cleared for all                    hosts.</p>                                    <p >If any alarms are present, clear them by locking and                        unlocking the affected host. In most cases, the alarms are cleared within                        one minute. If other system configuration operations are pending for the                        host, allow more time for the alarms to be cleared.</p>                            </li>        </ol>    </body></topic>