<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1406727863674" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title 
 <shortdesc 
  reset, power-up, and power-down operations.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author 
  <author 
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p 
   management modules optionally installed in the hosts. These modules provide support for remote
   reset and power control of the hosts.</p>
  <p 
   externally using the OAM network, or only accessible internally to the hosts in the cluster. This
   choice is made at system installation, during the configuration controller script. For details,
   see the <cite 
    Configuration Script</cite>.</p>
  <section id="section_N10036_N10024_N10001" 
   <title 
   <p 
    controller configuration script (press <userinput 
   <p 
   <ul id="ul_kw4_qpp_ds">
    <li 
     <p 
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
      configuration has access to the board management network.</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1006F_N10024_N10001" 
   <title 
   <p 
    controller configuration script (press <userinput 
    and then specify a VLAN ID and a subnet). This configures a VLAN ID on the controller management
    interface for use with a board management network. To complete the VLAN, you must connect the
    modules to VLAN-tagged ports on an internal L2 switch. The modules are assigned IP addresses
    from the specified subnet.</p>
   <fig id="fig_lwg_xlp_ds" 
    <title 
    <image href="psa1408575952625.image" id="image_mwg_xlp_ds" 
     <alt 
    </image>
   </fig>
   <p 
    configured for internal access. Computenodes connect using iLO modules, while
    controller nodes use the management port in tagged mode. As indicated in the figure, the
    controller nodes can optionally attach using their own iLO modules, if available.</p>
   <ul id="ul_n5g_xlp_ds">
    <li 
     <p 
     <ul id="ul_x5g_xlp_ds">
      <li 
       <p 
      </li>
      <li 
       <p 
      </li>
      <li 
       <p 
        participant hosts are attached to it.</p>
      </li>
     </ul>
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
     <ul id="ul_y5g_xlp_ds">
      <li 
       <p 
        network.</p>
      </li>
      <li 
       <p 
      </li>
      <li 
       <p 
        network to the VLAN. You must ensure that these ports are tagged ports for this VLAN, that
        is, that outgoing board management traffic (toward the controllers) uses ﻿IEEE 802.1Q
        tagging. Other management traffic on this port is untagged.</p>
      </li>
     </ul>
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
    </li>
   </ul>
   <p 
    consult the user documentation supplied with the equipment.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="module_and_host_provisioning" 
   <title 
   <p 
    provisioning:</p>
   <ul id="ul_tmg_cmp_ds">
    <li 
     <p 
      access.</p>
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
      required so that the system can associate the module's assigned IP address with the correct
      host.</p>
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
      attached iLO module.</p>
    </li>
    <li 
     <p 
      module. This is required for controller access to the module.</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
   <p 
    equipment.</p>
   <p 
     Management</wintitle> tab on the <wintitle 
    the CLI. For more information, see the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide.</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>