<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE topic   PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic domains="(topic concept topic)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333732592" xml:lang="en-us">    <title >The Ethernet MTU</title>    <shortdesc >The Maximum Transmission Unit (MTU) of an Ethernet frame is a configurable attribute in  the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. Changing its default size must be done in coordination with other network  elements on the Ethernet link.</shortdesc>    <prolog>        <author >Jim Owens</author>        <author >Pedro Sanchez</author>    </prolog>    <body>        <p >In HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, the Maximum Transmission Unit (MTU) refers to the            largest possible payload on the Ethernet frame on a particular network link. The payload            is enclosed by the Ethernet header (14 bytes) and the CRC (4 bytes), resulting in an            Ethernet frame that is 18 bytes longer than the MTU size. </p>        <p >The original IEEE 802.3 specification defines a valid standard Ethernet            frame size to be from 64 to 1518 bytes, accommodating payloads ranging in size from 46            to 1500 bytes. Ethernet frames with a payload larger than 1500 bytes are considered to            be jumbo frames.</p>        <p >For a VLAN network, the frame also includes a 4-byte VLAN ID header,            resulting in a frame size 22 bytes longer than the MTU size.</p>        <p >For a VXLAN network, the frame is either 54 or 74 bytes longer, depending            on whether IPv4 or IPv6 protocol is used. This is because, in addition to the Ethernet            header and CRC, the payload is enclosed by an IP header (20 bytes for Ipv4 or 40 bytes            for IPv6), a UDP header (8 bytes), and a VXLAN header (8 bytes). </p>        <p >In the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, you can configure the MTU size for the following            interfaces and networks: </p>        <ul id="ul_qmn_yvn_m4">            <li >                <p >The management, OAM, and infrastructure network interfaces on the                    controller. The MTU size for these interfaces is set during initial                    installation. You can update the infrastructure interface MTU for the                    controller from the web administration interface or the                    CLI.<!-- JO Where can the user find more about this? --></p>            </li>            <li >                <p >Data interfaces on compute nodes. For more information, see the                        <cite >Compute Node</cite> entry in <xref href="jow1404333563170.xml" />.<!-- JO For future reference, a link to an id at the relevant element [e.g. <xref href="jow1404333563170.xml#jow1404333563170/compute-node-definition"] doesn't work for the PDF output (the page number is not included). --></p>            </li>            <li >                <p >Provider networks. For more information, see the <cite >Provider Networks</cite> entry in <xref href="jow1404333563170.xml" />.</p>            </li>        </ul>        <p >In all cases, the default MTU size is 1500. The minimum value is 576, and            the maximum is 9216.<!-- JO according to Allain. --></p>        <p >Since data interfaces are defined over physical interfaces connecting to            provider networks, it is important to consider the implications of modifying the default            MTU size:</p>        <ul id="ul_hsq_2f4_m4">            <li >                <p >The MTU sizes for a data interface and the corresponding Ethernet                    interface on the edge router or switch must be compatible. You must ensure that                    each side of the link is configured to accept the maximum frame size that can be                    delivered from the other side. For example, if the data interface is configured                    with a MTU size of 9216 bytes, the corresponding switch interface must be                    configured to accept a maximum frame size of 9238 bytes, assuming a VLAN tag is                    present.</p>                <p >The way switch interfaces are configured varies from one switch                    manufacturer to another. In some cases you configure the MTU size directly,                    while in some others you configure the maximum Ethernet frame size instead. In                    the latter case, it is often unclear whether the frame size includes VLAN                    headers or not. In any case, you must ensure that both sides are configured to                    accept the expected maximum frame sizes.</p>            </li>            <li >                <p >For a VXLAN network, the additional IP, UDP, and VXLAN headers                    are invisible to the data interface, which expects a frame only 18 bytes larger                    than the MTU. To accommodate the larger frames on a VXLAN network, you must                    specify a larger nominal MTU on the data interface. For simplicity, and to avoid                    issues with stacked VLAN tagging, some third party vendors recommend rounding up                    by an additional 100 bytes for calculation purposes. For example, to attach to a                    VXLAN provider network with an MTU of 1500, a data interface with an MTU of 1600                    is recommended.</p>            </li>            <li >                <p >A provider network can only be associated with a compute node data interface with an MTU of     equal or greater value. </p>            </li>            <li >                <p >The MTU size of a compute node data interface cannot be modified                    to be less than the MTU size of any of its associated provider networks.</p>            </li>            <li >                <p >The MTU size of a provider network can be modified only when there are no tenant networks     that depend on the provider network.</p>            </li>            <li >                <p >The MTU size of a provider network is automatically propagated up to any derived tenant     networks.</p>            </li>            <li >                <p >The Neutron L3 and DHCP agents automatically propagate the MTU size of their networks to     their Linux network interfaces.</p>            </li>            <li >                <p >The Neutron DHCP agent makes the option <option >interface-mtu</option> available to any DHCP     client request from a virtual machine. The request response from the server is the current     interface's MTU size, which can then be used by the client to adjust its own interface MTU     size. </p>            </li>            <li >                <p >The AVS prevents any AVP-Kernel or AVP-DPDK instances from setting a link MTU size that     exceeds the maximum allowed on the corresponding tenant network. No such verification is     available for virtio VM instances.</p>            </li>        </ul>        <p >You can configure the MTU size from the web management interface when creating or modifying   data interfaces and provider networks. On the CLI, use the option <option >--mtu</option> to   modify the MTU size. For example:</p>        <codeblock ><systemoutput >~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput >neutron providernet-create common-net --type vlan --mtu 9216</userinput></codeblock>        <p >This command creates a provider network named <b >common-net</b> with an MTU size of 9216 bytes.</p>    </body></topic>