<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1417711797967" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Licensing and Authentication Requirements</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">To install and use HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, you require a license from Wind River
  Systems. For secure HTTPS access, you also require a CA-signed certificate during the installation
  process.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <dl>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="5">
    <dt ixia_locid="6">Evaluation License</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="7">
     <p ixia_locid="8">You can use an evaluation license to try out HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. This is a fully functional,
      time-limited license, provided for evaluation purposes only.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="9">
    <dt ixia_locid="10">Product License</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="11">
     <p ixia_locid="12">You can use a product license to operate HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade for your business requirements.
     </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
  <p ixia_locid="13">For complete information about Wind River licenses and licensing terms, contact your Wind River
   sales representative.</p>
  <section id="section_N1004B_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="14">
   <title ixia_locid="15">Obtaining a License</title>
   <p ixia_locid="16">To obtain a license, contact your Wind River sales representative. The license is sent to the
    contact e-mail address you provide when you make a request or place an order. </p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N10058_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="17">
   <title ixia_locid="18">Installing a License </title>
   <p ixia_locid="32">To install a license initially, follow the procedure for installing and configuring the
    HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade system. During this procedure, you must copy the license file to a designated
    license directory on the controller host. The default designated directory is
     <filepath ixia_locid="34">/home/wrsroot</filepath>; you can specify a different one during installation.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N10069_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="21">
   <title ixia_locid="22">Updating a License </title>
   <p ixia_locid="36">After you have installed a license, you can update it by copying the new license file to the
    designated license directory on the active controller host, and then running the
     <cmdname ixia_locid="38">license-install</cmdname> utility as shown in the following example.</p>
   <codeblock ixia_locid="40"><systemoutput ixia_locid="42">$ </systemoutput><userinput ixia_locid="44">sudo /usr/sbin/license-install <varname ixia_locid="46">license_file</varname></userinput></codeblock>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1009D_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="29">
   <title ixia_locid="30">Enabling HTTPS Access (optional)</title>
   <p ixia_locid="31">To enable secure HTTPS access for REST API applications, a digital certificate is required
    during software installation. For evaluation purposes, you have the option to select a
    self-signed certificate included with HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. However, the use of a CA-signed
    certificate is strongly recommended.  You must obtain the certificate and copy it to the
    controller host before starting the controller configuration script. You can update the
    certificate at any time after installation.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N100AD_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="48">
   <title ixia_locid="49">Installing a digital certificate</title>
   <p ixia_locid="33">To install a CA-signed digital certificate, follow the procedure for
    installing and configuring the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade system. During this procedure, you must copy the
    certificate PEM file to a designated license directory on the controller host. The default
    designated directory is <filepath ixia_locid="35">/home/wrsroot</filepath>; you can specify a
    different one during installation.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N100C0_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="53">
   <title ixia_locid="55">Updating a digital certificate</title>
   <p ixia_locid="37">After you have installed a digital certificate, you can update it by copying
    the new certificate to the designated directory on the active controller host, and then running
    the <cmdname ixia_locid="39">restapi-certificate-install</cmdname> utility as shown in the
    following example.</p>
   <codeblock ixia_locid="41"><systemoutput ixia_locid="43">$ </systemoutput><userinput ixia_locid="45">sudo /usr/sbin/restapi-certificate-install <varname ixia_locid="47">pem_file</varname></userinput></codeblock>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>