<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_rbs_ysb_bt">
  <title>Connecting to a Microsoft SQL Server service</title>
  <body>
    <p><ph><i>Windows, .NET, SQL Server, and IIS are either registered trademarks or trademarks of Microsoft Corporation in the United States and/or other countries.</i></ph></p>
    <p>This document describes how to connect to a Microsoft SQL Server 2012 or 2014 service using the Helion client's <b>tunnel</b> command.</p>
    <note>This document will demonstrate how to connect to a Microsoft SQL Server 2012 instance; the procedure for connecting to a Microsoft SQL Server 2014 service is the same.</note>
    <p>This document contains the following sections:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><xref type="section" href="#topic_rbs_ysb_bt/requirements">System requirements</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="section" href="#topic_rbs_ysb_bt/create">Create a Microsoft SQL Server service instance</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="section" href="#topic_rbs_ysb_bt/deploy">Deploy a Helion tunneling application</xref></li>
      <li><xref type="section" href="#topic_rbs_ysb_bt/connect">Connect to the service instance</xref></li>
    </ul>
    <section id="requirements"><title>System Requirements</title>
    <p>This tutorial requires the following:</p>
      
      <ul><li>A Helion Openstack installation, or a Helion Public Cloud account</li>
        <li>An ALS cluster with an instance of SQL Server added. This cluster and service is created using the <xref href="../helion/CLI/1.2ALS_Client_Reference.html">ALS cluster management tool (cf-mgmt)</xref> with the following
          <xref href="../helion/CLI/1.2ALS_Client_Reference.html#topic13234__commands">commands</xref>:
          <ul><li><b>create-cluster</b></li>
            <li><b>add-service</b></li></ul>
          </li>
      </ul></section>
    <section id="create"><title>Create a Microsoft SQL Server service instance</title>
      <ol>
      <li><p>To create a Microsoft SQL Server service instance, use the <xref href="../helion/CLI/1.2ALS_Client_Downloads.html">Helion ALS Client</xref>. To create a service
        instance, first connect the Helion ALS client to your ALS cluster using 
        <xref type="section" href="../helion/user/reference/1.2client-ref-getting-started.html#topic2439__command-login">helion login</xref>
        and <xref type="section" href="../helion/user/reference/1.2client-ref-getting-started.html#topic2439__command-target">helion target</xref>.</p></li>
        <li><p>The following command creates an instance of a Microsoft SQL Server 2012 service called <b>MSSQL2012Service</b> (the command will request the service plan to use):</p>
    <codeblock>helion create-service mssql2012 MSSQL2012Service</codeblock></li>
    <li><p>The output from this command may look like the following (in this example, the Free service plan is selected):</p>
      <image placement="break" href="../../media/windows_sql_create.png"></image></li></ol></section>
      
    <section id="deploy"><title>Deploy a Helion tunneling application</title>
      
    <ol><li><p>Once the service instance is created, in order to connect to the instance, you must first run a tunneling application using the <b>helion tunnel</b> command.</p></li>
      <li><p>The following command creates a tunneling application to the <b>MSSQL2012Service</b> service in the connected cluster, binds the tunneling application to the requested service, 
        and returns the credentials <b>username</b>, <b>password</b>, <b>(database) name</b>, and <b>connectionString</b> required to connect to the service:</p>
      <codeblock>helion tunnel MSSQL2012Service</codeblock></li>
      <li><p>The output from this command may look like the following:</p>
      <image placement="break" href="../../media/helion_sql_tunnel.png"></image>
    <note>The tunnel is created on port 10000 by default. To change this, use the <codeph>--port</codeph> parameter.</note></li></ol>
    </section>
    <section id="connect"><title>Connect to the service instance</title>
     <ol> 
    <li><p>Once the tunneling application is running and bound to the service, you can connect to the service using SQL Server Management Studio.</p>
      <p>In the login dialog for SQL Management Studio, enter the hostname and port for the ALS cluster, and provide the login credentials from the previous section:</p>
      <image placement="break" href="../../media/windows_sql_connect_1.png"></image></li>
      <li><p>In the next dialog, provide the database name from the previous section: </p>
        <image placement="break" href="../../media/windows_sql_connect_2.png"></image></li>
      <li><p>When the connection is complete, you will be connected to the database service in SQL Management Studio:</p>
        <image placement="break" href="../../media/windows_sql_connect_3.png"></image></li></ol></section>
  </body>
</topic>
