<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic   PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >
<topic domains="(topic concept topic)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333787693" xml:lang="en-us">
    <!-- Modification History
   -->
    <title >Hardware Profiles</title>
    <shortdesc >A hardware profile is a named object that captures a particular host
        configuration. The profile can be applied to any other host with a similar hardware
        configuration.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author >Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <body>
        <p >The following types of hardware profiles are available from the <wintitle >Systems Inventory</wintitle> page, each presented on a separate
            tab:</p>
        <ul id="ul_lrp_w4q_l4">
            <li >
                <p >CPU profiles</p>
            </li>
            <li >
                <p >interface profiles</p>
            </li>
            <li >
                <p >storage profiles</p>
            </li>
            <li >
                <p >memory profiles</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p >Once a hardware profile is defined, it can be applied to any host where it makes sense to be
      applied to change its configuration.</p>
        <section id="cpu-profiles" >
            <title >CPU Profiles</title>
            <p >A CPU profile is a named assignment of processors and cores to one or more of the following
        types of processing threads:</p>
            <dl>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >Platform</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >System threads handling the core hosting functionality of
                            the host. Platform threads are always present on all types of hosts in
                            the cluster.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >vSwitch</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >AVS threads dedicated to handling network traffic and
                            packet processing tasks. They exists on the compute nodes only.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >Shared</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >Threads handling low-load or non-real-time virtual
                            machine tasks, implemented on a shared physical CPU in a compute
                            node.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >Virtual Machines</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >Threads handling virtual machines. They exists on the compute nodes only.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
            <p >On controller nodes, all processors and cores are automatically
                assigned to platform threads, as they are the only ones available. On compute nodes,
                which always run a number of threads of all types, a default CPU allocation is done
                automatically when the system software is initially installed.</p>
            <p >A list of the currently defined CPU profiles is available from the <uicontrol >CPU
          Profiles</uicontrol> tab on the <wintitle >System Inventory</wintitle> page, as illustrated
        below.</p>
            <fig id="fig_N1009C_N1004C_N10020_N10001" >
                <image href="jow1404333761616.image" id="image_a1p_t2r_l4"  width="6in"/>
            </fig>
            <p >This example lists one CPU profile, named <codeph >HP-360-C1</codeph>, with the
        following processor and core allocation:</p>
            <table frame="all" id="table_s32_fdr_l4">
                <title >CPU Allocation Example</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Thread Type</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >CPU Allocation</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Platform</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Processor 0, core 0</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry >
                                <p >vSwitch</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Processor 0, cores 1 and 2</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Virtual Machines</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Processor 0, cores 3 to 7</p>
                                <p >Processor 1, cores 8 to 15</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <p >CPU profiles can be deleted using the button <uicontrol >Delete CPU Profiles</uicontrol> on this page. When clicked, it
                deletes all check-marked profiles in the list. The delete operation does not affect
                CPU profiles already applied.</p>
            <p >See <xref href="jow1404333768530.xml" /> for more information of how to change
        the CPU allocation for a compute node, and on how to define  CPU profiles.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10137_N10020_N10001" >
            <title >Interface Profiles</title>
            <p >An interface profile is a named configuration of Ethernet ports and
                interfaces on a host, as follows:</p>
            <dl>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >Ethernet Ports</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >The list of physical Ethernet ports that have been allocated to connect to a
              network.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >Interfaces</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >Logical L2 interfaces defined on top of physical Ethernet ports.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
            <p >A list of the currently defined interface profiles is available from the
          <uicontrol >Interface Profiles</uicontrol> tab on the <wintitle >System Inventory</wintitle>
        page, as illustrated below.</p>
            <fig id="fig_N10174_N10138_N10020_N10001" >
                <image href="jow1404333769085.image" id="image_svc_jgr_l4"  width="6in"/>
            </fig>
            <p >This example lists two interface profiles, as follows:</p>
            <table frame="all" id="table_gxd_hmr_l4">
                <title >Interface Profiles</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Profile Name</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Ports</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >Interfaces</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry >
                                <p >HP-360-cmpt-iface-profile</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >eth1, eth4, eth6</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >eth1 on internal management network</p>
                                <p >data0 (eth6 on physnet0)</p>
                                <p >data1 (eth4 on physnet1)</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry >
                                <p >HP-360-ctrl-iface-profile</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >eth0, eth1</p>
                            </entry>
                            <entry >
                                <p >eth0 on OAM network</p>
                                <p >eth1 on internal management network</p>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <p >The interface profile <codeph >HP-360-cmpt-iface-profile</codeph> belongs to a
        compute node. It lists three physical ports, eth1, eth4, and eth6, allocated to connect to a
        network. It also lists three logical L2 interfaces:</p>
            <ul id="ul_evb_d4r_l4">
                <li >
                    <p >eth1, allocated to connect to the internal management network</p>
                </li>
                <li >
                    <p >data0, a data interface associating physical port eth6 with the provider network
            physnet0.</p>
                </li>
                <li >
                    <p >data1, a data interface associating physical port eth4 with the provider network
            physnet1.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p >The interface profile <codeph >HP-360-ctrl-iface-profile</codeph> belongs to a
        controller node. It lists two physical ports, eth0, and eth1, and two logical L2 interfaces
        connecting these ports to the OAM and internal management networks.</p>
            <p >Interface profiles can be deleted using the button <uicontrol >Delete Interface Profiles</uicontrol> on this page. When
                clicked, it deletes all check-marked profiles in the list.  The delete operation
                does not affect interface profiles already applied.</p>
            <p >See <xref href="jow1404333777760.xml" /> for more
                information on how to create interface profiles.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10249_N10020_N10001" >
            <title >Storage Profiles</title>
            <p >A storage profile is a named configuration for a list of storage
                resources on a computing node. Each storage resource consists of the following
                elements:</p>
            <dl>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >Disks</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >A Linux block storage device, such as <filepath >/dev/sdd</filepath>, identifying an
              entire hard drive.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry >
                    <dt >Storage Volumes</dt>
                    <dd >
                        <p >A storage volume consisting of a name and a storage
                            function. The name is used as a human-readable version of the native
                            storage device UUID. The storage function indicates the type of storage
                            backend, such as <codeph >OSD</codeph> for a
                            storage system.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
            <p >A list of the currently defined storage profiles is available from the <uicontrol >Storage
          Profiles</uicontrol> tab on the <wintitle >System Inventory</wintitle> page, as illustrated
        below.</p>
            <fig id="fig_N1028F_N1024B_N10020_N10001" >
                <image href="jow1404333778322.image" id="image_bny_1vg_m4"  width="6in"/>
            </fig>
            <p >This example lists one storage profile named <codeph >storprofile-1</codeph> with
        three storage resources on the hard drives <filepath >/dev/sdc</filepath>,
          <filepath >/dev/sdd</filepath>, and <filepath >/dev/sde</filepath>. All storage resources
        are of the <codeph >OSD</codeph> type.</p>
            <p >See <xref href="jow1404333787180.xml" /> for more
                information on how to create storage profiles.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10363_N1001F_N10001" >
            <title >Memory Profiles</title>
            <p >A memory profile is a named assignment of huge pages for use as VM
                memory. For more information, see <xref href="jow1429811350849.xml" />.</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>