<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<!DOCTYPE topic   PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >


<topic id="jow1404333563170" xml:lang="en-us">


    <!-- Modification History





 -->


    <title >Reference Logical Architecture</title>


    <shortdesc >The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade architecture supports various types of host,


        networks, and networking hardware in different configurations. In this documentation, a


        reference configuration is used for discussion.</shortdesc>


    <prolog>


        <author >Pedro Sanchez</author>


        <author >Jim Owens</author>


    </prolog>


    <body>


        <!-- note id="note_N10027_N10024_N10001" >


            <p >The reference configuration assumes that the controller and compute


                functions are implemented on different hosts. HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade also supports a


                minimal two-server configuration in which these functions are implemented on the


                same host. For more information, see the <cite >HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade


                    Software Installation Guide: Minimal Two-server Configuration</cite>. </p>


        </note> -->


        <p >The following components are used in HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade.


            For specific details on the deployment and network architectures, refer to the <xref


                href="http://docs.hpcloud.com/#CarrierGrade/Installation/carrier-grade-technical-overview.html"


                format="html" scope="external">Technical Overview</xref>.</p>


        <dl>


            <dlentry><dt>HLM</dt> 


            <dd><p>Helion Lifecycle Management deploys and manages the non-KVM Region controllers. HLM provides


                        input files to deploy the KVM region of the cloud. HLM provisions the node


                        on PXE-1 network and configures nodes on CLM network.</p></dd>


            </dlentry></dl>     


        


        <dl>


        <dlentry>


            <dt>Non-KVM Region Controller</dt>


            <dd><p>The Runs the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade services needed to manage the cloud


                        infrastructure: Keystone with LDAP backend, Glance with Swift backend, and


                        Cinder with 3Par as storage backend. Some of these services are shared with


                        KVM Region of the cloud. Controller nodes run the services in carrier grade


                        mode, that is, as a high-availability cluster. The controller manages other


                        hosts on CLM network, and provides API interfaces to clients over CAN


                        (Consumer Access Network) or OAM (Operations, Administration and Management)


                        network.</p></dd>


        </dlentry>


        


        <dlentry>


                <dt>KVM Region Controller</dt>


                <dd>


                    <p>The KVM region controller is a real-time control plane for the HP Compute


                        (nova) service and HP Network Operation (Neutron) service. The controller


                        nodes run the services in carrier grade mode, that is, as a


                        high-availability cluster.</p>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


        <dlentry>


            <dt>Compute</dt>


            <dd><p>The real-time compute nodes are based on Wind River Linux(WR) with Accelerated Virtual Switch


                        (AVS) networking components. The nodes run HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade


                        compute services and host the virtual machines. A compute node connects to


                        the controller nodes over CLM network, and to the provider networks using


                        its data interfaces. Compute nodes also have connectivity to BLS enabling


                        attaching a Cinder volume to the VM guest.</p></dd> 


        </dlentry>


        <dlentry>  


            <dt>Infratructure Services</dt>   


            <dd><p>A block of servers provide NTP, SMTP, LDAP and other infrastructure services to the Cloud.</p></dd>       


        </dlentry>


        


            <dlentry id="provider-networks-definition" >


                <dt >Provider Network</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >A Layer 2 virtual network used to provide the underlying


                        network connectivity needed to instantiate the tenant networks. Multiple


                        provider networks may be configured as required, and realized over the same


                        or different physical networks. Access to external networks is typically


                        granted to the compute nodes via the provider network. The extent of this


                        connectivity, including access to the open Internet, is application


                        dependent.</p>


                    <p >Provider networks are created by the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade administrator to make use of an


            underlying set of resources on a physical network. They can be created as being of one


            of the following types:</p>


                    <dl>


                        <dlentry >


                            <dt >flat</dt>


                            <dd >


                                <p >A provider network mapped entirely over the


                                    physical network. The physical network is used as a single Layer


                                    2 broadcast domain. Each physical network can realize at most


                                    one flat provider network.</p>


                                <p >A provider network of this type supports at most


                                    one tenant network, even if its corresponding shared flag is


                                    enabled.</p>


                            </dd>


                        </dlentry>


                        <dlentry >


                            <dt >VLAN</dt>


                            <dd >


                                <p >A provider network implemented over a range of IEEE 802.1Q VLAN identifiers


                  supported by the physical network. This allows for multiple provider networks to


                  be defined over the same physical network, all operating over non-overlapping sets


                  of VLAN IDs.</p>


                                <p >A set of consecutive VLAN IDs over which the


                                    provider network is defined is referred to as a network's


                                        <b >segmentation


                                        range</b>. A provider network can have more than


                                    one segmentation range. Each VLAN ID in a segmentation range is


                                    used to support the implementation of a single tenant


                                    network.</p>


                                <p >A segmentation range can be shared by multiple


                                    tenants if its <b >shared</b> flag is set.


                                    Otherwise, the segmentation range supports tenant networks


                                    belonging to a single specified tenant.</p>


                            </dd>


                        </dlentry>


                        <dlentry >


                            <dt >VXLAN</dt>


                            <dd >


                                <p >A provider network implemented over a range of


                                    VXLAN Network Identifiers (VNIs.) This is similar to the VLAN


                                    option, in that it allows multiple provider networks to be


                                    defined over the same physical network using unique VNIs defined


                                    in segmentation ranges. In addition, VXLAN provides a Layer 2


                                    overlay scheme on Layer 3 networks, enabling connectivity


                                    between Layer 2 segments separated by one or more Layer 3


                                    routers.</p>


                            </dd>


                        </dlentry>


                    </dl>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


            <dlentry >


                <dt >Tenant Network</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >A virtual network associated with a tenant. A tenant network


                        is instantiated on a compute node, and makes use of a provider network,


                        either directly over a flat network, or using technologies such as VLAN and


                        VXLAN.</p>


                    <p >Tenant networks use the high-performance virtual L2 switching capabilities built into


            the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software stack of the compute node. They provide switching


            facilities to the virtual service instances, to communicate with external resources and


            with other virtual service instances running on the same or different compute nodes.</p>


                    <p >When instantiated over a provider network of the VLAN or


                        VXLAN type, the VLAN ID or VNI  for the tenant network is assigned


                        automatically. The allocation algorithm selects the lowest available ID from


                        any segmentation range owned by the tenant. If no such ID is available, it


                        selects the lowest available ID from any shared segmentation range. The


                        system reports an error when no available ID is found.</p>


                    <p >Tenant networks created by the administration can also be


                        configured to use a pre-selected VLAN ID or VNI. This can be used to extend


                        connectivity to external networks.</p>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


            <dlentry >


                <dt >Controller Floating IP Address</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >A unique IP address shared by the cluster of controller nodes. Only the master


            controller node is active on this address at any time. The IP address is floating in the


            sense that it is automatically transferred from one controller node to the other, as


            dictated by the high-availability directives of the cluster.</p>


                    <p >The controller cluster has two floating IP addresses, one


                        facing the OAM network, only seen by the web interface SSH administration


                        clients and REST APIs, and another facing the internal management network,


                        only seen by the compute nodes.</p>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


            <dlentry >


                <dt >Link Aggregation (LAG) or Aggregated Ethernet (AE)</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >A mechanism that allows multiple parallel Ethernet network


                        connections between two hosts to be used as a single logical connection. The


                        HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade supports LAG connections on all its


                        Ethernet connections for the purpose of protection (fault-tolerance) only.


                        Different modes of operation are supported. For details, see <xref


                            href="http://docs-staging.hpcloud.com/DRAFT/#CarrierGrade/Installation/carrier-grade-install-pb-overview.html"


                            format="html" scope="external">Installing HP Helion OpenStack Carrier


                            Grade</xref>.</p>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


            <dlentry >


                <dt >OAM Network L2 Switch(es)</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >One or more switches used to provide an entry point into the


                        OAM network.</p>


                    <note id="note_N101AD_N101A6_N1019F_N10033_N1001C_N10001" >


                        <p >The OAM ports on the controller do not support VLAN


                            tagging. If needed, port- or MAC-based VLANs defined on the L2 switch


                            can be used to steer OAM traffic appropriately.</p>


                    </note>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


            <dlentry >


                <dt >Provider Network L2 Switches</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >Provide the entry point into the provider networks. It is through these L2 switches


            that the compute nodes get integrated as active end points into each of the provider


            networks.</p>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


            <dlentry >


                <dt >Edge Router</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >Provides connectivity to external networks as needed by controller and compute


            nodes.</p>


                    <p >Reachability to the open Internet is not mandatory, but strictly application-dependent.


            Guest applications running on the compute nodes may need to access, or be reachable


            from, the Internet. Additionally, access to the OAM Network from external networks might


            be desirable.</p>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


            <dlentry >


                <dt >Web Administration Interface</dt>


                <dd >


                    <p >Provides the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade main management interface. It is available using any W3C


            standards-compliant web browser, from any point within the OAM Network where the


            OAM floating IP address is reachable.</p>


                </dd>


            </dlentry>


        </dl>


        <section id="section_N101EC_N1001C_N10001" >


            <title >About Tenants (Projects) and Users</title>


            <p >Tenants and users are system resources managed by the OpenStack


                Keystone service.</p>


            <p >Tenants are the core resource structure on which all end user services are managed. They


        are isolated resource containers consisting of networks, storage volumes, images, virtual


        machines, authentication keys, and users.</p>


            <p >When the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is deployed, two default tenants are


                created: <b >admin</b> and <b >services</b>. They are used to group resources to be


                associated with the user <b >admin</b> and the


                cloud services, respectively.</p>


            <note id="note_N10211_N101ED_N1001C_N10001" >


                <p >Earlier versions of OpenStack used the term <term >project</term>


                    instead of <term >tenant</term>. Because of this legacy terminology, the web


                    administration interface uses both terms, and some command-line tools use


                        <b >--project_id</b> when a tenant ID is


                    expected.</p>


            </note>


            <p >Users are system resources that can operate on one or more tenants, within the constraints


        of a particular role. For each user, the Keystone service maintains a list of (tenant, role)


        tuples, which are used to determine the tenants the user can operate on, and the role the


        user should play on each of them.</p>


            <p >In the default installation of the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade, several users are already defined. Each


        of the OpenStack services, such as Nova and Neutron, exist as system users. They all operate


        on the default tenant <b >services</b>.</p>


            <p >The Keystone <b >admin</b> user


                is associated with the <b >admin</b> tenant.


                This user has administrator privileges for creating, modifying, and deleting


                OpenStack resources, including creating other tenants and users.</p>


            <p ><b>Note:</b> In this document, after this point, all references to


                contoller-0 and controller-1 are specific to the KVM region only. </p>


        </section>


    </body>


</topic>


