<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="jow1432240580490" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title ixia_locid="370">Enabling Server Group Messaging for a VM</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="371">You can enable a messaging API for a VM, for use with other VMs in
        the same server group.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="372">Jim Owens</author>
    </prolog>
    <taskbody>
        <context id="context_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="373">
            <p ixia_locid="374">Server Group Messaging is a service that provides simple low-bandwidth datagram
                messaging and notifications for virtual machines that belong to the same server
                group. This message channel is available regardless of whether IP networking is
                functional within the server, and requires no knowledge about the other members in
                the group.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="375">Guest applications can access this service if the Server Group
                Messaging API is enabled for the VM. To enable the API, select this option. For more
                information about the Server Group Messaging API, refer to the <cite ixia_locid="376">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Development Kit</cite>.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="377">The service provides three types of messaging:</p>
            <ul id="ul_dtr_pkn_cs">
                <li ixia_locid="378">
                    <p ixia_locid="379"><nameliteral ixia_locid="380">Broadcast</nameliteral>—allows the server to send a
                        datagram of up to 3050 bytes to all other servers in the server group.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="381">
                    <p ixia_locid="382"><nameliteral ixia_locid="383">Notification</nameliteral>—provides servers with
                        information about changes to the state of other servers in the server
                        group.</p>
                </li>
                <li ixia_locid="384">
                    <p ixia_locid="385"><nameliteral ixia_locid="386">Status</nameliteral>—allows
                        the server to query the current state of all servers in the group (including
                        the originating server).</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <note id="note_N10059_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="387" type="caution">
                <p ixia_locid="388">This service is not intended for high-bandwidth or low-latency
                    operations. If reliability is an important consideration, use acknowledgements
                    and retries.</p>
            </note>
            <p ixia_locid="389">To add this extra spec to a flavor using the web administration interface, use the
                    <uicontrol ixia_locid="390">Server Group Messaging</uicontrol> selection in the <uicontrol ixia_locid="391">Create
                    Flavor Extra Spec</uicontrol> drop-down menu. To access this menu, see <xref href="jow1429538642910.xml" ixia_locid="392"/>.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="393">To enable the Server Group Messaging API using the CLI, use the following
                command:</p>
            <codeblock ixia_locid="319"><systemoutput ixia_locid="326">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput ixia_locid="333">nova flavor-key <varname ixia_locid="340">flavor_name</varname> set sw:wrs:srv_grp_messaging=<varname ixia_locid="351">value</varname></userinput></codeblock>
            <p ixia_locid="368">where <varname ixia_locid="369">value</varname> is either
                    <option ixia_locid="394">False</option> or <option ixia_locid="395">True</option>.</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task-wr>