<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1413726817770" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Host Status and Alarms During System Configuration Changes</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">For all types of configuration changes, alarms and status messages appear
  while the system is in transition. You can use the information provided by these messages to help
  guide the transition successfully.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="21">Configuration changes require multiple hosts to be reconfigured, during which
   the settings across the cluster are not consistent. This causes alarms to be raised for the
   system.</p>
  <ul id="ul_uyz_tt5_4q">
   <li ixia_locid="24">
    <p ixia_locid="22">Changes to the DNS server configuration cause transitory alarms. These alarms
     are cleared automatically when the configuration change is applied.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="25">
    <p ixia_locid="23">Changes to the External OAM network IP addresses or NTP server addresses, and
     in particular to the controller storage allotments, cause persistent alarms. These alarms must
     be cleared manually, by locking and unlocking the affected hosts or performing other
     administrative actions.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="5">Alarms appear on the <wintitle ixia_locid="18">Fault Management</wintitle> pane, and related
   status messages appear on the <wintitle ixia_locid="19">Hosts</wintitle> tab on the
    <wintitle ixia_locid="20">Inventory</wintitle> pane. A variety of alarms may be reported on the Fault Management
   page, depending on the configuration change.</p>
  <note id="note_N1002C_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="16" type="caution">
   <p ixia_locid="17">To help identify alarms raised during a configuration change, ensure that any existing system
    alarms are cleared before you begin. </p>
  </note>
  <p ixia_locid="14">On the <wintitle ixia_locid="8">Hosts</wintitle> tab of the <wintitle ixia_locid="9">System Inventory</wintitle> pane, the status <nameliteral ixia_locid="15">Config
    out-of-date</nameliteral> is shown for hosts affected by the change.  Each host with this status
   must be locked and then unlocked to update its configuration and clear the alarm.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>