<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<!DOCTYPE topic   PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >


<topic domains="(topic concept topic)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333749994" xml:lang="en-us">


    <!-- Modification Historyjow1404333749994.xml





 -->


    <title >Storage Planning</title>


    <shortdesc >Storage resources on the controller are used to maintain internal


        databases, and to provide storage for virtual machines. For VMs, it is highly recommended to


        use storage provided through volumes (Cinder service backed by 3PAR). There might not be


        enough storage on compute nodes (especially blades). </shortdesc>


    <prolog>


        <author >Jim Owens</author>


        <author >Pedro Sanchez</author>


    </prolog>


    <body>


        <p >During HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software installation, the controller configuration


            script gives you the options to allocate space on the controller for the internal


            database, and for general storage volumes (images and disk space for the virtual


            machines).</p>


        <p >The size of the database grows with the number system resources created by


            the system administrator and the tenants. This includes objects of all kinds such as


            compute nodes, provider networks, images, flavors, tenant networks, subnets, virtual


            machine instances and NICs. As a reference point, consider the following deployment


            scenario:</p>


        <ul id="ul_drv_fjf_4n">


            <li >


                <p >two controllers</p>


            </li>


            <li >


                <p >four compute nodes with dual Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-2670 v2 @ 2.50GHz each.</p>


            </li>


            <li >


                <p >40 virtual machine instances</p>


            </li>


            <li >


                <p >120 tenant networks</p>


            </li>


            <li >


                <p >steady collection of power management statistics</p>


            </li>


        </ul>


        <p >The size of the database in this case is approximately 9 GB. With a


            suggested default of 20 GB, there is still plenty of room to grow. However, you should


            periodically monitor the size of the database to ensure that it does not become a


            bottleneck when delivering new services.</p>


        <p >For general storage, the default settings suggested during the controller


            configuration script are recommended to utilize the maximum available space on the


            storage media.</p>


        <section id="section_N1005C_N1001C_N10001" >


            <title >Storage for Virtual Machines</title>


            <p >For VMs, you can use remote Cinder storage or local storage.</p>


            <p >Persistent block storage for virtual machines is allocated by the


                Cinder service using 3PAR.</p>


            <dl>


                <dlentry >


                    <dt >LVM/iSCSI</dt>


                    <dd >


                        <p >This backend provides block storage managed by the Linux


                            Logical Volume Manager (LVM) exposed as iSCSI targets. In the HP Helion


                            OpenStack Carrier Grade implementation: </p>


                        <ul id="ul_czg_wxt_44">


                            <li >


                                <p >Storage space is allocated on the active


                                    controller and automatically mounted over iSCSI by the virtual


                                    machines running on the compute nodes. No storage space is


                                    allocated on the compute nodes. </p>


                            </li>


                            <li >


                                <p >The two controllers always maintain their storage


                                    partitions in sync for carrier-grade reliability.</p>


                            </li><!--                              <li >


                                <p >This backend does not support storage nodes.</p>


                            </li>-->





                        </ul>


                    </dd>


                </dlentry><!--


                <dlentry >


                    <dt >Ceph</dt>


                    <dd >


                        <p >This backend provides block storage using Ceph, a


                            distributed storage system. In the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade implementation:</p>


                        <ul id="ul_vc5_bpc_qp">


                            <li >


                                <p >Storage space is allocated on the storage nodes


                                    exclusively. No persistent block storage space is allocated on


                                    the compute nodes or the controllers.</p>


                            </li>


                            <li >


                                <p >Two storage nodes are used to provide a scalable and fully


                                    HA-protected storage solution. For details on hardware


                                    requirements and software installation procedures for storage


                                    nodes, refer to the <cite >HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade


                                        Software Installation Guide</cite>. </p>


                            </li>


                        </ul>


                        <note id="note_N100F5_N100CE_N100C5_N1008B_N10077_N1001F_N10001" >


                            <p >For Ceph storage, an infrastructure network is required.</p>


                        </note>


                    </dd>


                </dlentry> -->


            </dl><!--


            <p >The LVM/iSCSCI and Ceph-based storage backend options are exclusive.


                You select one or another when configuring <codeph >controller-0</codeph> by selecting the appropriate storage option. Select


                    <uicontrol >lvm</uicontrol> for the LVM/iSCSCI backend, or


                    <uicontrol >ceph</uicontrol> for the Ceph backend. See the <cite >HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Installation Guide</cite> for


                details.</p>   -->


            <p >As an alternative to persistent storage provided by the Cinder


                service, you can implement ephemeral local storage on the compute nodes where the


                VMs are instantiated. This is useful for VMs requiring local disk access for


                performance optimization. You can use a pre-allocated partition on the root disk, as


                well as additional disks optionally installed in the compute nodes. For more


                information, see <xref href="jow1426183480976.xml" />. </p>


            <note conref="jow1426942555025.xml#jow1426942555025/note_local_storage_ephemeral" id="note_N10130_N1007C_N10024_N10001" />


            <p >To instantiate VMs on compute nodes configured for local storage, see


                    <xref href="jow1426181040008.xml" />.</p>


        </section>


    </body>


</topic>