<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<!DOCTYPE topic   PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" >


<topic domains="(topic task topic)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="psa1413402160578" xml:lang="en-us">


<!-- Modification History


        


-->


    <title >PCI Passthrough Ethernet Interfaces</title>


    <shortdesc >A <term >passthrough</term> Ethernet interface is a physical PCI Ethernet NIC on a


        compute node to which a virtual machine is granted direct access. This minimizes packet


        processing delays but at the same time demands special operational


        considerations.</shortdesc>


    <prolog>


        <author >Pedro Sanchez</author>


    </prolog>


    <body>


        <section id="section_N10023_N10020_N10001" >


            <p >For all purposes, a PCI passthrough interface behaves as if it were


                physically attached to the virtual machine. Therefore any potential throughput


                limitations coming from the virtualized environment, such as the ones introduced by


                internal copying of data buffers, are eliminated. However, by bypassing the


                virtualized environment, the use of PCI passthrough Ethernet devices introduces


                several restrictions that must be taken into consideration. They include:</p>


            <ul id="ul_mjs_m52_tp">


                <li >


                    <p >no support for LAG, QoS, ACL, or host interface monitoring</p>


                </li>


                <li >


                    <p >no support for live migration</p>


                </li>


                <li >


                    <p >no access the compute node's AVS switch</p>


                </li>


            </ul>


            <p >A passthrough interface bypasses the compute node's AVS switch


                completely, and is attached instead directly to the provider network's access


                switch. Therefore, proper routing of traffic to connect the passthrough interface to


                a particular tenant network depends entirely on the VLAN tagging options configured


                on both the passthrough interface and the access port on the switch.</p>


            <p >The access switch routes incoming traffic based on a VLAN ID, which ultimately


                determines the tenant network to which the traffic belongs. The VLAN ID is either


                explicit, as found in incoming tagged packets, or implicit, as defined by the access


                port's default VLAN ID when the incoming packets are untagged. In both cases the


                access switch must be configured to process the proper VLAN ID, which therefore has


                to be known in advance.</p>


            <p >In the following example a new virtual machine is launched by user


                    <b >user1</b> on tenant <b >tenant1</b>, with a passthrough interface connected to


                the tenant network <b >net0</b> identified with


                VLAN ID 10.</p>


        </section>


        <section id="section_N10065_N10020_N10001" >


            <p >The exercise assumes that the underlying provider network


                    <b >group0-data0</b> exists already, and that VLAN ID 10 is a


                valid segmentation ID assigned to <b >tenant1</b>.</p>


        </section>


        <ol>


            <li id="li_N10079_N10076_N10020_N10001" >


                <p >Log in as the <b >admin</b> user to the web management


                    interface.</p>


            </li>


            <li id="li_N1009B_N10088_N10024_N10001" >


                <p >Lock the compute node you want to configure.</p>


            </li>


            <li id="li_N10086_N10076_N10020_N10001" >


                <p >Configure the Ethernet interface to be used as a PCI


                    passthrough interface.</p>


                


                    <p >Select the <wintitle >System


                            Inventory</wintitle> window from the <uicontrol >Admin</uicontrol> panel, click the <uicontrol >Hosts</uicontrol> tab, click the name of the compute node where the PCI


                        interface is available, click the <uicontrol >Interfaces</uicontrol> tab, and finally click the <uicontrol >Edit Interface</uicontrol> button associated with the


                        interface you want to configure. Fill in the window as illustrated


                        below:</p>


                    <fig id="fig_hfk_cfh_rr" >


                        <image href="psa1428772332800.image" id="image_whc_5kh_rr"  width="4in">


                            <alt >Edit PCI Passthrough Interface</alt>


                        </image>


                    </fig>


                    <p >In this example, Ethernet interface <b >eth8</b> is assigned the network type <term >pci-passthrough</term>, and configured as connected to provider network


                            <b >group0-data0</b>. Click the


                            <uicontrol >Save</uicontrol> button to proceed.</p>


                    <p >The interface can also be configured from the CLI as


                        illustrated below:</p>


                    <codeblock ><systemoutput >~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput >system host-if-modify \


-nt pci-passthrough -p group0-data0 compute-0 eth8</userinput></codeblock>


                


            </li>


            <li id="li_N100E9_N10076_N10020_N10001" >


                <p >Create the <b >net0</b>


                    tenant network</p>


                


                    <p >Select the <wintitle >Networks</wintitle>


                        window from the <uicontrol >Admin</uicontrol> panel, click


                        the <uicontrol >Networks</uicontrol> tab, and then click the


                            <uicontrol >Create Network</uicontrol> button. Fill in


                        the <wintitle >Create Network</wintitle> window as


                        illustrated below. You must ensure that:</p>


                    <ul id="ul_pcn_vb4_tp">


                        <li >


                            <p >The <b >tenant1</b> tenant has access to the tenant network,


                                either assigning it as the owner, as in the illustration (using


                                    <uicontrol >Project</uicontrol>), or by enabling the shared


                                flag.</p>


                        </li>


                        <li >


                            <p >The segmentation ID is set to 10. </p>


                        </li>


                    </ul>


                    <fig id="fig_kwr_hd4_tp" >


                        <image href="psa1413406273455.image" id="image_ofd_kd4_tp"  placement="inline" width="4in">


                            <alt >Creating a tenant network for use with PCI


                                passthrough devices</alt>


                        </image>


                    </fig>


                    <p >Click the <uicontrol >Create Network</uicontrol> button to proceed.</p>


                


            </li>


            <li id="li_N10144_N10076_N10020_N10001" >


                <p >Configure the access switch.</p>


                


                    <p >Configure the physical port on the access switch used to


                        connect to Ethernet interface <b >eth8</b> as an access port with default VLAN ID of 10.


                        Traffic across the connection is therefore untagged, and effectively


                        integrated into the targeted tenant network.</p>


                    <p >You can also use a trunk port on the access switch so that it


                        handles tagged packets as well. However, this opens the possibility for


                        guest applications to join other tenant networks using tagged packets with


                        different VLAN IDs, which might compromise the security of the system. See


                            <xref href="jow1404333739778.xml" /> for other details regarding the


                        configuration of the access switch.</p>


                


            </li>


            <li id="li_N101A0_N10088_N10024_N10001" >


                <p >Unlock the compute node.</p>


            </li>


            <li id="li_N1015D_N10076_N10020_N10001" >


                <p >Launch the virtual machine.</p>


                <ol id="ol_snp_klt_tp">


                    <li >


                        <p >Log in as user <b >user1</b> to the web management


                            interface.</p>


                    </li>


                    <li >


                        <p >Configure the network interfaces for the new virtual machine.</p>


                        


                            <p >Open the <wintitle >Launch


                                    Instance</wintitle> dialog by clicking the <uicontrol >Launch Interface</uicontrol> button on the


                                    <wintitle >Instances</wintitle> window. Configure


                                the necessary options for the new virtual machine. In particular,


                                click the <uicontrol >Networking</uicontrol> tab and


                                add a PCI passthrough interface on the tenant network <b >net0</b>, as illustrated below. Add


                                other network interfaces as needed.</p>


                            <fig id="fig_yxy_t1g_tp" >


                                <image href="psa1413311389905.image" id="image_dbb_4dg_tp"  placement="inline" width="5.5in">


                                    <alt >Assigning Passthrough PCI Ethernet


                                        Devices</alt>


                                </image>


                            </fig>


                            <p >Click the <uicontrol >Launch</uicontrol> button to proceed.</p>


                            <p >Passthrough interfaces can be attached from the CLI when booting a


                                new virtual machine, as illustrated below:</p>


                            <codeblock ><systemoutput >~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput >nova boot \


--nic net-id=704e9f3b,vif-model=pci-passthrough my-new-vm</userinput></codeblock>


                        


                    </li>


                </ol>


            </li>


        </ol>


       


            <p >The new virtual machine instance is up now. It has a PCI passthrough


                connection to the <b >net0</b> tenant network


                identified with VLAN ID 10.</p>


        


        <section id="section_N1023B_N10024_N10001" >


            <p >Access switches must be properly configured to ensure that virtual


                machines using PCI-passthrough or SR-IOV Ethernet interfaces (the latter discussed


                in <xref href="psa1428687672712.xml" />) have the expected


                connectivity. In a common scenario, the virtual machine using these interfaces


                connects to external end points only, that is, it does not connect to other virtual


                machines in the same cluster. In this case:</p>


            <ul id="ul_pz2_w4w_rr">


                <li >


                    <p >Traffic between the virtual machine and the access switch


                        can be tagged or untagged.</p>


                </li>


                <li >


                    <p >The connecting port on the access switch is part of a


                        port-based VLAN.</p>


                </li>


                <li >


                    <p >If the port is tagged, the allowed VLAN ID range must not


                        overlap with VLAN ID ranges used by the AVS ports. </p>


                </li>


                <li >


                    <p >The port-based VLAN provides the required connectivity to external switching


                        and routing equipment needed by guest applications to establish connections


                        to the intended end points.</p>


                </li>


            </ul>


            <p >For connectivity to other virtual machines in the cluster the


                following configuration is also required:</p>


            <ul id="ul_ngs_nvw_rr">


                <li >


                    <p >The VLAN ID used for the tenant network, 10 in this example, and the default


                        port VLAN ID of the access port on the switch are the same. This ensures


                        that incoming traffic from the virtual machine is tagged internally by the


                        switch as belonging to VLAN ID 10, and switched to the appropriate exit


                        ports.</p>


                </li>


                <li >


                    <p >The target virtual machines are reachable through another port on the compute


                        node, which is managed by the AVS.</p>


                </li>


                <li >


                    <p >That other port is configured as usual, as a VLAN trunk


                        port, and the tenant network's VLAN ID (10) is included in the tagged range.


                        This ensures that VLAN 10 is common to both the passthrough/SR-IOV interface


                        and the AVS port.</p>


                </li>


            </ul>


        </section>


    </body>


</topic>