<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic7707">
<title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> 1.1: FAQ</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="All"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="JaymeP"/>
<othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--UNDER REVISION-->
 <!--./commercial/GA1/1.1commercial.faq.md-->
 <!--permalink: /helion/openstack/1.1/faq/--></p>
<p>

</p>
<p>This page answers many common questions about what HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> is, how it works, and what it can do for your enterprise.</p>
<section id="about-hp-helion-openstack2"> <title>About HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm></title>
<ul>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatHelion">What is HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm></xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/TripleO">What is TripleO?</xref>

<ul>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatisseed">What is a seed?</xref>  </li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatisundercloud">What is the undercloud?</xref> </li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatisovercloud">What is the overcloud?</xref> </li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/hybridorpubliccloud">Does HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> work with hybrid or public cloud projects?</xref>
</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="specifications2"> <title>Specifications</title>
<ul>
<li>
<xref href="../../commercial/GA1/1.1commercial.whatsnew.dita" >What's new in this release?</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/nodes">How many nodes and virtual machines does it support?</xref>  </li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/softwareupdate">How can I update to the latest version?</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/includeOS">Does it include an Operating System (OS)?</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/releaseversion">What <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> release does this distribution include?</xref> </li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/nonhphardware">Can HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> run on non-HP hardware?</xref>
</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="more-information"> <title>More Information</title>
<ul>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/MoreInfo">Where can I find more information?</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/community">Is there an alternative to the full version?</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/developer">What developer resources are available?</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/reportissues">Where can I report issues with HP <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Helion?</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic7707/localized">Is this release localized for non-English speaking markets?</xref> </li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="about-hp-helion-openstack3"> <title>About HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm></title>
</section>
<section id="whatHelion"> <title>What is HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm></title>
<p>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> is a commercial-grade distribution of <xref href="http://www.openstack.org" scope="external" format="html" ><tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm></xref>, the leading open source cloud computing platform. This distribution, backed by HP, enables customers to more easily build, manage, and use open-source based hybrid clouds in a resilient, maintainable platform.</p>
<p>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> enables cost-effective scalability of IT services and increased business agility. Best of all, as part of the HP Helion portfolio, it is backed by a wide range of related cloud products, services, and professional support.</p>
<p>To get a better idea of what's inside the box, explore the individual components and how they work together <xref href="http://docs.hpcloud.com/content/documentation/commercial/GA1/ServicesFlow/index.html" scope="external" format="html" >under the hood</xref>.</p>
</section>
<section id="TripleO"> <title>What is TripleO?</title>
<p><tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm>-on-<tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> or TripleO, is an official  <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> project for deployment of <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> systems. It builds on the core resource-provisioning strengths of <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> technology. It enables you to administer your cloud or deploy and maintain virtual and baremetal installations of <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> using the same APIs you are familiar with for deploying workloads on an <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> cloud. A template-based deployment engine (using <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Heat) allows for rigorous testing and reliable, repeatable deployments of known configurations.</p>
<p>A TripleO installation includes a <xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatisseed">seed</xref>, the <xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatisundercloud">undercloud</xref> and the <xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatisovercloud">overcloud</xref>.</p>
</section>
<section id="whatisseed"> <title>What is a seed?</title>
<p>A seed VM is a bootable KVM VM image provided as part of HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> and is deployed in a VM instance. This instance provisions physical hardware and deploys the undercloud. It also contains the minimum services required for <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> to function: Nova, Neutron, Glance, Keystone, Ironic &amp; Heat.</p>
<p>This is the first phase of the HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> installation.</p>
</section>
<section id="whatisundercloud"> <title>What is the undercloud?</title>
<p>The undercloud server is a basic single-node <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> installation running on a single physical server used to deploy, test, manage, and update the overcloud servers. There is no HA configuration for the undercloud.</p>
<p>The undercloud contains a strictly limited sub-set of services; just enough to interact with the overcloud. The services running on the undercloud are Nova, Neutron, Glance, Keystone, Ironic, Heat, Horizon &amp; Ceilometer. This server also contains the HP Helion content distribution catalog service, which provides a mechanism for downloading and installing content and updates for the overcloud.</p>
<p>The undercloud also hosts images for various server types which will form the functional cloud environment - the <xref type="section" href="#topic7707/whatisovercloud">overcloud</xref>. These images are overcloud Controller, overcloud Compute, overcloud Swift &amp; overcloud Compute Proxy (required for clouds that support VMWare ESX as a hypervisor).</p>
<p>Creating the undercloud is the second phase of the HP Helion installation process.</p>
</section>
<section id="whatisovercloud"> <title>What is the overcloud?</title>
<p>The overcloud is the functional cloud available to run guest virtual machines and workloads. It offers access to the Nova, Neutron, Glance, Keystone, Cinder, Swift, Ironic, Heat, Horizon, and Ceilometer services.</p>
<p>Creating and configuring the overcloud completes the overall Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> installation process.</p>
</section>
<section id="hybridorpubliccloud"> <title>Does HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> work with hybrid or public cloud projects?</title>
<p>Absolutely. HP Helion provides a proven hybrid IT strategy that enables migration of existing traditional IT workloads to appropriate cloud environments at the pace and volume that makes sense for your enterprise.</p>
</section>
<section id="specifications"> <title>Specifications</title>
</section>
<section id="whats-new-in-this-release"> <title>What's New in this Release?</title>
<p>See the whole list of <xref href="../../commercial/GA1/1.1commercial.whatsnew.dita" >what's new</xref> in this release.</p>
</section>
<section id="nodes"> <title>How many nodes and virtual machines does it support?</title>
<p>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> will currently support up to 100 nodes with up to 40 virtual machines per node, subject to the capacity of the hardware.</p>
</section>
<section id="softwareupdate"> <title>How can I update to the latest version?</title>
<p>HP <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Helion does not support an update utility to update from previous releases. For help with updating, visit the <xref href="http://www.hpcloud.com/about/contact" scope="external" format="html" >HP Customer Support</xref> page and choose your preferred method of contact.</p>
</section>
<section id="includeOS"> <title>Does HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> include an Operating System (OS)?</title>
<p>Yes. It includes an integrated <tm tmtype="reg">Linux</tm> host OS hardened and tested for this distribution. All supported hardware and software configurations are laid out in the <xref href="../../commercial/GA1/1.1commercial.install-GA-supportmatrix.dita" >Support Matrix</xref>.</p>
</section>
<section id="releaseversion"> <title>Which <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> release does this distribution include?</title>
<p>All of the <xref href="../../commercial/GA1/1.1commerical.services-overview.dita#<tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm>" >HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> services</xref> have been updated to <xref href="http://www.openstack.org/software/juno/" scope="external" format="html" ><tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Juno</xref>. <xref href="http://www.hpcloud.com/learning-center" scope="external" format="html" >Learn more</xref> about HP's commitment to <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> and how we're making it even better.</p>
</section>
<section id="nonhphardware"> <title>Can HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> run on non-HP hardware?</title>
<p>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> does not require HP-branded hardware. All supported hardware and software configurations are laid out in the <xref href="../../commercial/GA1/1.1commercial.install-GA-supportmatrix.dita" >Support Matrix</xref>.</p>
</section>
<section id="more-information2"> <title>More Information</title>
</section>
<section id="MoreInfo"> <title>Where can I find more information?</title>
<ul>
<li>
<xref href="https://docs.hpcloud.com/helion/openstack/1.1/" scope="external" format="html" >HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Documentation</xref> </li>
<li>
<xref href="http://www8.hp.com/us/en/cloud/hphelion-openstack.html" scope="external" format="html" >HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Portal</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref href="http://www.hpcloud.com/about/contact" scope="external" format="html" >HP Customer Support</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref href="http://go.hpcloud.com/Consultation" scope="external" format="html" >Consult with a Cloud Specialist</xref>
</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="community"> <title>Is there an alternative to the full version?</title>
<p>The <xref href="../../community/community.index.dita" >HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Community edition</xref> is a free-to-license distribution that speeds deployment and simplifies management of small-scale open cloud environments and infrastructure services. It supports up to 30 physical nodes and 600 virtual nodes making it ideal for small-scale, evaluation, and proof of concept deployments.</p>
</section>
<section id="developer"> <title>What application developer resources are available?</title>
<p>The <xref href="../../devplatform/1.1devplatform.index.dita" >HP Helion Development Platform</xref> provides developers and IT professionals with an open development platform designed for agility.</p>
</section>
<section id="reportissues"> <title>Where can I report issues with HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm></title>
<p>To report issues with HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> contact <xref href="http://www.hpcloud.com/about/contact" scope="external" format="html" >HP Customer Support</xref>.</p>
</section>
<section id="localized"> <title>Is this release localized for non-English speaking markets?</title>
<p>No. The current release is available in English only.</p>
<p>
  <xref type="section" href="#topic7707"> Return to Top </xref>
</p>
</section>
</body>
</topic>
