<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_tq1_xt5_dt">
  <title>Allocating Object Servers</title>
  <body>
    <p>A Swift object server is a node that runs the swift-object service (<b>only</b>) and used to
      store object data. It does not run the swift-proxy, swift-account or swift-container services.
      <!--The Swift object server type is used to store object data.--></p>
    <p>This section describes the procedure to allocate Swift Object Server during the
        <b>initial</b> deployment of the system. </p>
    <p>This page contains the following topics:<ul id="ul_gfp_rwc_jt">
        <li><xref href="#topic_tq1_xt5_dt/procedure" format="dita">Procedure to Allocate Swift
            Object Server</xref></li>
        <li><xref href="#topic_tq1_xt5_dt/create-server-role" format="dita">Creating Server Role for
            Swift Object Servers</xref></li>
        <li><xref href="#topic_tq1_xt5_dt/swift-network" format="dita">Swift Network and Service
            Requirement</xref></li>
      </ul></p>
    <section id="procedure">
      <title>Procedure to Allocate Swift Object Server</title>
    </section>
    <p>Perform the following steps to allocate Swift Object Servers:</p>
    <p>
      <ul id="ul_sm4_2pb_jt">
        <li>Verify if the example input model already contains a suitable server role. The server
          roles are usually described in <codeph>data/server_roles.yml</codeph> file. If the server
          role is not described, you must add a suitable server role as described in <i><xref
              href="creating_roles_swift_nodes.dita#topic_uh2_td1_kt">Creating  Role for Swift
              Nodes</xref></i>. While adding a server role for the Swift object server, you will
          also allocate drives to store object data as described in <i><xref
              href="allocating_disk_drives.dita#allocating-disk-drives">Allocating Disk
              Drives.</xref></i></li>
        <li>Verify if the example input model has a resource group assigned to Swift object servers.
          The resource group are usually assigned in <codeph>data/control_plane.yml</codeph> file.
          If it is not assigned, you must add a suitable resource group as described in <xref
            href="creating-object-server-resource.dita#topic_jzk_q1c_jt"><i>Creating an Object Sever
              Resource Group</i></xref></li>
        <li>Identity the physical servers and their IP address and other detailed information. Add
          the servers details in either of the following YAML file and verify the server-groups information:<simpletable>
            <strow>
              <stentry><codeph>data/baremetalConfig.yml</codeph></stentry>
              <stentry>If you use Cobbler, add these details in the baremetal-servers
                list.</stentry>
            </strow>
            <strow>
              <stentry><codeph>data/server.yml</codeph></stentry>
              <stentry>If you do not use Cobbler, add these details to servers list. </stentry>
            </strow>
            <strow>
              <stentry><codeph>data/server_groups.yml</codeph></stentry>
              <stentry>Verify and/or modify the server-groups information with all
                servers.</stentry>
            </strow>
          </simpletable></li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>
    <p><?oxy_custom_end?>The only part of this process that is unique to Swift is the allocation of
      disk drives for use by the object ring as described in <i>Allocating Disk Drives for use by
        Swift.</i></p>
  </body>
</topic>
