<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_qkg_l4v_bt">
  <title>Cloud Model</title>
  <body>
    <p>This section describes the configuration of the Swift services in the cloud model. <ul
                id="ul_c5c_gjm_dt">
                <li><xref href="#topic_qkg_l4v_bt/node-type" format="dita">Node Type</xref></li>
                <li><xref href="#topic_qkg_l4v_bt/config-swift-services" format="dita">Configuration
                        of Swift Services in the entry-scale-with-vsa</xref></li>
                <li><xref href="#topic_qkg_l4v_bt/allocating-disk-drives" format="dita">Allocating
                        Disk Drives</xref></li>
                <li><xref href="#topic_qkg_l4v_bt/allocation-network" format="dita">Allocating
                        Network</xref></li>
                <li><xref href="#topic_qkg_l4v_bt/ring-specification" format="dita">Ring
                        Specifications</xref></li>
            </ul></p>
    <section id="node-type"><b>Node Types</b></section>
    <p>Following are the node types associated with Swift services:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><b>Proxy, Container, Account, Object (PACO) Node</b>: This node runs the Swift-proxy,
                Swift-account, Swift-container, and Swift-object services. These services run on the
                same  (PACO) node type in the control plane. This is used for smaller clouds or
                where Swift is a minor element in a larger cloud.</li>
            <li><b>Proxy, Container,  and Account (PAC) Node</b>: This node runs Swift-proxy,
                Swift-account, and Swift-container services. These services run on one (PAC) node
                type in a control plane. This is used for in larger clouds or where a larger Swift
                system is in use or planned.</li>
      <li><b>Object (OBJ) Node</b>: This node runs the Swift-object service. This service runs on
                another (OBJ) node type in a resource pool. This is used for in larger clouds or
                where a larger Swift system is in use or planned.</li>
    </ul>
    <section id="config-swift-services"><b>Configuration of Swift Services in the
                entry-scale-with-vsa</b><p>The following <codeph>yml</codeph> files are configured
                for <b>entry-scale-with-vsa</b> model:</p></section>
    <ul>
      <li><codeph>data/control_plane.yml</codeph><p/></li>
            <li><codeph>data/disk_controller.yml</codeph><p>This <codeph>yml</codeph> file contains
          the Swift information (swiftobj disk-group). This describes what disks on each of the
          servers are assigned to Swift and the rings that uses those drives.</p></li>
      <li><codeph>config/swift/rings.yml</codeph><p>Swift account, container, and object storage are
                    managed by Swift using a data structure known as a <i>ring</i>. This
                        <codeph>yml</codeph> file provides the specification of the rings. For more
                    information on ring specification, refer to <xref
                        href="#topic_qkg_l4v_bt/ring-specification" format="dita">ring
                        specification.</xref></p></li>
      <li>
        <p>
                    <codeph>data/network_groups.yml</codeph></p>
        <p>This <codeph>yml</codeph> file specifies the MGMT and Swift networks. The Swift-proxy
          service uses the Swift network to communicate with the other Swift services and among
          themselves.</p>
      </li>
      <li> The Swift-proxy service uses other cloud services as follows. Both of these are
        configured in the example to run on the <b>core</b> cluster:<ul>
          <li>Swift validates token by making requests to the Keystone service</li>
          <li>Swift caches tokens and other data using the memcached service</li>
        </ul></li>
    </ul>
    <section id="allocation-network"><b>Allocating Network</b><p>Do not change the network
                configurations.</p></section>
  </body>
</topic>

