<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_sl2_nht_dt">
  <title>Swift- Troubleshooting </title>
  <body>
    <section><b>Interpreting _swift-validate-input-model.yml Errors</b></section>
    <p>When you execute the <codeph>_swift-validate-input-model.yml</codeph> playbook it can be hard
      to pick out the errors being reported. If so, you view the error messages as follows:<ol
        id="ol_szd_tht_dt">
        <li>Log onto the first node in the system that is running the swift-proxy-server process.
            <note> You must run the <codeph>_swift-validate-input-model.yml</codeph> playbook as
            mentioned in step <b>2</b> in <xref
              href="../installation.dita#topic_flx_j2b_ws/CloudDeploy"/> otherwise the files needed
            to run the <codeph>swiftlm-ring-supervisor</codeph> will not be in place on the node.
          </note></li>
        <li>Execute the following
            command:<codeblock>sudo swiftlm-ring-supervisor --make-delta --report </codeblock><p>
            The command will report any errors or problems (see List of errors) with the input
            model. It also prints a summary of the ring create actions that are planned (i.e., that
            will occur) for the deploy phase of the process.</p><p><b>List of errors</b></p><p>You
            can see the list of errors and the resolution as follows:</p><p><note>To resolve an
              error by changing the input, you <b>must</b></note>must re-run the configuration
            processor as describe in “Run the Configuration Processor” (in <xref
              href="http://docs-staging.hpcloud.com/hos2.0beta1/#helion/installation.html"
              format="html" scope="external"
              >http://docs-staging.hpcloud.com/hos2.0beta1/#helion/installation.html</xref>) and
            continue with the deploy.</p><p> </p><p>Example Message:<b> Model Missmatch: Cannot find
              drive /dev/sdt on padawan-ccp-c1-m2 (192.168.245.3)</b></p><p>Description:</p><p>The
            disk model used for node padawan-ccp-c1-m2 has drive /dev/sdt listed in the devices list
            of a device-group where Swift is the consumer. However, the dev/sdt device does not
            exist on that node.</p><p>Resolution:</p><p>If a drive or controller is failed on a
            node, the drive may not be seen by the operating system and hence the corresponding
            block device might not exist. Sometimes this is transitory and a reboot may resolve the
            problem. The problem might not be with /dev/sdt, but with another drive. For example, if
            /dev/sds is failed, when you boot the node, the drive that you expect to be called
            /dev/sdt is actually called /dev/sds. Alternatively, you may simply not have enough
            drives installed in the server. You can add drives. Another option is to remove /dev/sdt
            from the appropriate disk model. However, this removes the drive for all servers using
            the disk model .</p><p> </p><p>Example message: Model Missmatch: Cannot find drive
            /dev/sdd2 on padawan-ccp-c1-m2 (192.168.245.3)</p><p>Description:</p><p>The disk model
            used for node padawan-ccp-c1-m2 has drive /dev/sdt listed in the devices list of a
            device-group where Swift is the consumer. However, the partition number (2) has been
            specified in the model. This is not supported – only specify the block device name (for
            example /dev/sdd), not partition names in disk models.</p><p>Resolution:</p><p>Remove
            the partition number from the disk model.</p><p> </p><p>Example message: Cannot find ip
            address of padawan-ccp-c1-m3-swift for ring: account host:
            padawan-ccp-c1-m3-mgmt</p><p>Description:</p><p>The service (in this example,
            swift-account) is running on the node padawan-ccp-c1-m3. However, this node does not
            have a</p><p>Connection to the network designated for the swift-account service (i.e.,
            the SWIFT network.</p><p>Resolution:</p><p>Check the input model for which networks are
            configured for each node type.</p><p/><p>Example message: Ring:object-2 has specified
            replication-policy erasure-coding-policy. Only may be
            specified.</p><p>Description:</p><p>Only one of replication-policy or
            erasure-coding-policy may be used in a
            ring-specification.</p><p>Resolution:</p><p>Remove one of the policy types.</p><p
            > </p><p>Example message: Ring: object-3 is missing a policy type (replication-policy
            erasure-coding-policy)</p><p>Description:</p><p>There is no replication-policy or
            erasure-coding-policy section in the ring-specifications for the object-0
            ring.</p><p>Resolution:</p><p>Add a policy type to the input model file. </p></li>
      </ol></p>
  </body>
</topic>
