<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic6367">
<title>HP Helion 1.2 Development Platform: The Marketplace (Beta)</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Development Platform"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Development Platform 1.2"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Systems Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="System Engineer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Cloud Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Network Administrator"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Application Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="ISV Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Service Developer"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Jayme P"/>
<othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Development Platform"/>
<othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Development Platform 1.2"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--PUBLISHED-->
 <!--./devplatform/1.2/1.2devplatform.marketplace.install.md-->
 <!--permalink: /helion/devplatform/1.2/marketplace/--></p>
<p>The Marketplace, currently in beta, is a repository where teams can download the latest services they need to accelerate development of their applications. In its beta incarnation, the Marketplace has a single application: the Vertica 7 Community Edition.</p>
<p>The following topics explain how to install and deploy an instance of Vertica 7 Community Edition:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic6367/concepts">Marketplace concepts</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic6367/prereq">Prerequisites</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic6367/install">Installing a package</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic6367/create">Deploying an environment</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic6367/deploy">Creating a Deployed Instance of an Application</xref>
</li>
<li>
<xref type="section" href="#topic6367/notes">Deployment Notes</xref>
</li>
</ul>
<section id="marketplace-concepts"> <title>Marketplace Concepts</title>
<p>The Marketplace deploys packages of services and applications to specified environments.</p>
<ul>
<li>The term <b>Application</b> covers both applications and services that can reside in the Marketplace. For the purposes of this documentation, we will use the term Application even though we are deploying a database, which is a service. </li>
<li>
<b>Packages</b> are zip files that contain instructions for Application deployment.</li>
<li>
<b>Environments</b> are groups of Applications managed by a single tenant. Applications within a single Environment <i>may</i> be logically related to one another, but do not have to be.  Applications in different Environments are always independent from one another. </li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="prerequisites"> <title>Prerequisites</title>
<p>Install the Marketplace component of the <xref href="../../devplatform/1.2/1.2devplatform_commercial_install.dita" >HP Helion Development Platform</xref> during the Development Platform install process.</p>
</section>
<section id="installing-a-package"> <title>Installing a Package</title>
<p>In this example, the package being installed is the Vertica 7 Community Edition package.</p>
<p>Note that you must log out of the Horizon dashboard and then log back in at least once after Marketplace installation before installing any Marketplace packages. This will ensure that Horizon has properly loaded all Marketplace services prior to package installation.</p>
</section>
<section id="create-a-target-environment"> <title>Create a Target Environment</title>
<ol>
<li> Log into Horizon and open the <b>Marketplace</b> panel under your Project. Click on
            <b>Application Catalog</b>, and then click on the Environments tab.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace1.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> Click <b>Create Environment</b>.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace2.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> After the environment has been created, your view should look like this:<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace3.png"/>
          </p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="create-a-deployed-instance-of-an-application"> <title>Create a Deployed Instance of an Application</title>
<p>The following section will show how to create an instance of Vertica 7 Community Edition in the environment created above.</p>
<ol>
<li> Log in to the Horizon console and open the <b>Marketplace</b> panel under your Project. </li>
        <li> Click on <b>Application Catalog</b> and then click on the <b>Applications</b> tab. You
          will see the Vertica 7 Community Edition package.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace4.png" id="image_cxz_v3d_ks"/>
          </p></li>
<li> Click <b>Add to Env </b> from within the Vertica 7 Community Edition section. You will see an
            <b>Add Application to &lt;selected environment name&gt;</b> dialog. For this example,
          set the Environment Name to <b>Test1</b>. Agree to the Terms and Conditions, then scroll
          down to the bottom of the dialog and click <b>Next</b>.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace5.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li>The <b>Add Application to &lt;selected environment&gt;</b> dialog will come up. Fill out<ul>
            <li>
              <p>
                <b>Application name</b> - can be anything</p>
            </li>
            <li>
              <p>
                <b>Flavor</b> for instances, can be:</p>
              <ul>
                <li>m1.medium</li>
                <li>m1.large</li>
                <li>m1.xlarge</li>
              </ul>
            </li>
          </ul><ol>
            <li>Select the <b>image</b> to use. In this case there is only one image, the Vertica 7
              Community Edition (Debian) image. </li>
            <li>Add a keypair if you don't have one already, by selecting the <b>+</b> link. If you
              are adding a keypair, you will be prompted to supply a name and a public key. You can
              generate a public key in *nix using <xref href="http://linux.die.net/man/1/ssh-keygen"
                scope="external" format="html">ssh-keygen</xref> or Windows(R) using <xref
                href="http://the.earth.li/~sgtatham/putty/0.63/htmldoc/Chapter8.html#pubkey-puttygen"
                scope="external" format="html">puTTYgen</xref>. Insert public key text and click the
                <b>Import Key Pair</b> button.</li>
          </ol><p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace6.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> Supply a database name and a password, complying with the on-page instructions. Click
            <b>Next</b>.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace7new.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> You will be prompted to add the Application you have created to the environment you selected.
          Click <b>Create</b> to continue.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace8.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> You will see that Vertica 7 Community Edition has been installed in the test1 environment. Note
          that the Environment has <b>not</b> been deployed yet. That is the next step.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace9.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> To deploy the environment, click <b>Deploy This Environment</b>. <note>Expect deployment to
            take between 5 and 10 minutes.</note><p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace10.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> When this process has completed, you will see that the Vertica 7 Community Edition is available
          for consumption. Connection information is given in the <b>last operation</b> column.<p>
            <image href="../../media/marketplace11.png"/>
          </p></li>
<li> You can also implement additional security by modifying the access rules for the security group
          associated with the environment that the Vertica instance was deployed into. In the
          example, the environment name is <b>Test1</b>. The associated security group can be
          accessed from the Horizon panel as follows:<ol>
            <li>In the Horizon console under <b>Compute</b> -&gt; <b>Access &amp; Security</b>, go
              to the <b>Security Groups</b> tab.</li>
            <li>Search for a group with the <b>Test1</b> string in the group name. Group names are
              auto-generated to ensure that they are unique.</li>
            <li>Click <b>Manage Rules</b>. <ul>
                <li>To change the access rules for SSH, add a new security group allowing access on
                  port 22 from the IP range you wish to grant access to.</li>
                <li>To allow access to Vertica, add a new rule on port 5433 that specifies the IP
                  range you wish to grant access to. You can then remove the corresponding default
                  rule.</li>
              </ul></li>
          </ol></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="deployment-notes"> <title>Deployment Notes</title>
<p>This section discusses some of the details of deployment that you may encounter.</p>
<ol>
<li>Environments cannot be deployed unless there is at least one Application in the Environment. </li>
<li>Deploying an Application to an Environment that has already been deployed follows the same flow
          as above. <ul>
            <li>In order to instantiate a newly-configured application, re-deploy its
              Environment.</li>
            <li>When an Environment is re-deployed, all applications it contains will be
              re-deployed. </li>
          </ul></li>
<li> If a Vertica instance is restarted or power cycled, the Vertica database must be restarted
          manually once the instance is reachable. This is by design to avoid potential database
          corruption in the event of a power event. Note that <b>all</b> VMs are shut down and then
          restarted during the Helion upgrade process.<ol>
            <li> SSH into your instance</li>
            <li> Become the dbadmin user:<codeblock>sudo su - dbadmin</codeblock></li>
            <li> Run the following
              command:<codeblock>admintools -t stop_db --database=DB_NAME --password=DB_PASSWORD</codeblock></li>
          </ol></li>
<li>If the deployment of an environment stalls, you must wait until the state of the environment is either shown as Complete or Failed in the dashboard. If you attempt to clean up any Heat stacks generated by the Marketplace while the status is still shown as Deploying, the engine may be put in a state where it will be unable to process future requests (such as environment deletes or other environment deployments).</li>
</ol>
</section>
</body>
</topic>
