<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_m43_2j3_bt">
  <title>Updating Keystone</title>
  <body>

    <section><title>Updating Keystone </title>HP Helion OpenStack&#174; allows you to perform
      updates on the following parts of the Identity service configuration: <ul>
        <li>The main Keystone configuration file: <b>/etc/keystone/keystone.conf</b> Here you can
          manipulate Keystone configuration parameters and enable experimental features, such as
          Fernet Tokens.</li>
        <li>Domain-specific configuration files:
            <b>/etc/keystone/domains/keystone.&lt;domain_name&gt;.conf</b>. Here you can integrate
          Keystone with one or more external authentication sources, such as an LDAP server. </li>
        <li>Certain content in the logging configuration file: <b>/etc/keystone/logging.conf</b>. In
          this file you can adjust the verbosity of the output written to Keystone log files. </li>
        <li> The Apache2 WSGI module configuration file:
            <b>/etc/apache2/sites-enabled/keystone-modwsgi.conf</b>. In this file you can adjust
          certain WSGI module parameters (such as process counts). </li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Updating the main Keystone configuration file</title> The main Keystone configuration
      file (<b>/etc/keystone/keystone.conf</b>) is generated from the following template file:
        <b>roles/KEY-API/templates/keystone.conf.j2</b>
      <ol>
        <li>Modify this template file as appropriate. Please refer to the Keystone Kilo
          documentation for full descriptions of all settings in the <xref
            href="http://docs.openstack.org/kilo/config-reference/content/keystone-configuration-file.html"
            scope="external" format="html">Keystone docs at OpenStack.org</xref>
          <note>This is a Jinja2 template, which expects certain template variables to be set. Do
            not change values inside double curly braces (i.e. {{ }}). </note></li>
        <li>Once the template is modified, run reconfiguration playbook:
          <codeblock>ansible-playbook -i hosts/verb_hosts keystone-reconfigure.yml</codeblock></li>
      </ol></section>

    <section><title>Adjusting WSGI and logging parameters</title> To modify Web Server Gateway
      Interface (WSGI) parameters (such as process counts for public and admin Keystone interfaces)
      and log levels: <ol>
        <li>Adjust respective parameters in
          <b>roles/keystone-common/vars/keystone_deploy_config.yml</b>.</li>
        <li>Run reconfiguration playbook:
          <codeblock>ansible-playbook -i hosts/verb_hosts keystone-reconfigure.yml</codeblock>
        </li>
      </ol>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
