<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic6719">
<title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Carrier Grade (Beta): Deploying the Bridging Scenario</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="All"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="Paul F"/>
<othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--UNDER REVISION-->
 <!--./CarrierGrade/DeploymentScenarios/carrier-grade-deployment-bridging-deploy.md-->
 <!--permalink: /helion/openstack/carrier/deploy/bridging/deploy/--></p>
<p>The bridging scenarios use two virtual machines, each configured to bridge traffic between two network interfaces.</p>
<!-- ===================== horizontal rule ===================== -->
<p>
<b>Note:</b> This feature applies only to servers in the VNF Region.</p>
<!-- ===================== horizontal rule ===================== -->
<p>To complete the configuration of the deployment scenarios, you must perform the tasks in this section while logged in as user1, and then perform the same tasks while logged in as user2, substituting appropriate strings for instance names, keypairs, tenant networks, or other resources.</p>
<p>Each user must configure a virtual machine and launch an instance of a Layer 2 bridge. The bridge connects two VM interfaces; one is attached to the private tenant network used for test equipment access (tenant1-net or tenant2-net), and the other is attached to internal-net to complete the test path.</p>
<p>Instructions for launching either a Linux bridge or a DPDK-accelerated bridge are provided. You can use them in different combinations to evaluate the effect on latency and throughput.</p>
<p>
<b>Note:</b> For a Layer-2 DPDK bridge, the bridged ports must be configured for AVP. For a Linux bridge, they can be configured for virtio or AVP.</p>
<p>Before deploying this scenario, disable Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) on the switches connected to the networks or the tenant network VLANs.</p>
<ol>
<li>
        <xref href="../../CarrierGrade/AdminGuideNew/Dashboard/carrier-grade.dashboard.launch.dita"
          >Launch the HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">Openstack</tm> Horizon Dashboard</xref> as the appropriate user (user1
        or user2).</li>
<li>Click the <b>Project</b> dashboard, then the <b>System</b> panel, then the <b>Overview</b>
        link.</li>
<li>Select <b>Instances</b> in the <b>Manage Compute</b> section of the <b>Project</b> tab to open
        the <b>Instances</b> page.<p>Since no instances are currently running, an empty list is
          displayed.</p></li>
<li>Configure the virtual machine details by clicking <b>Launch Instance</b> to display the Launch
        Instance window. Fill in the information in the Details tab, as illustrated below:<p>
          <image href="../../media/CGH-deploy-bridge-launch.png"/>
        </p><p>In this example you are configuring an instance named tenant1-vm, with the flavor
          example-guest.small, booting from the volume named volexample- guest.</p><p>For more
          information on creating VMs, see <xref
            href="../../CarrierGrade/AdminGuideNew/Instances/carrier-grade.dashboard.instances.create.dita"
            >Creating a New Compute Instance</xref>.</p></li>
<li>Configure the virtual machine authentication credentials.<p>In the <b>Launch Instance</b>
          window, select the Access &amp; Security tab and associate the available tenant's keypair
          with this instance. Use a suitable password ( tenant1 in this example) for
          administration.</p></li>
<li>Connect the VM to the required tenant networks.<p>All tenant networks accessible to the tenant
          are available for use by the virtual machine. You can use the Networking tab of the Launch
          Instance dialog box to connect the VM to a tenant network, by moving the network from the
          Available Networks list to the Selected Networks list . This connects the tenant network
          to a virtual ethernet interface ethn on the VM, where <codeph>n</codeph> is the next
          available integer starting from zero.</p><p>a. List the available tenant
          networks.</p><p>In the <b>Launch Instance</b> window, select the <b>Networking</b> tab.
          This displays the available networks at the bottom, and the currently selected networks at
          the top.</p><p>b. Connect the required tenant networks.</p><p>Click the blue + buttons on
          the Available Networks list to move the tenant networks to the Selected Networks list, as
          shown:</p><p>
          <image href="../../media/CGH-deploy-bridge-launch-after.png"/>
        </p><p>
          <b>Note:</b> The order in which the networks are moved determines the order in which the
          virtual ethernet interfaces <codeph>eth0</codeph>, <codeph>eth1</codeph>,
            <codeph>eth2</codeph>, and so on are assigned. In the scenarios, the example guest image
          is configured to bridge or route between <codeph>eth1</codeph> and <codeph>eth2</codeph>.
          The networks to be attached to the bridge or router must be moved in the proper order for
          compatibility with this configuration.</p><p>First, move the tenant1-mgmt-net network.
          This connects it to interface <codeph>eth0</codeph> on the virtual machine. Then move
          tenant1-net and internal-net, in that order, to assign them to eth1 and eth2 on the
          virtual machine.</p><p>For each interface, you can specify the driver type from a
          drop-down menu. In this example, eth0 (NIC-1) is configured as a virtio interface,
          suitable for low-level management traffic. The eth1 (NIC-2) and eth2 (NIC-3) interfaces
          are configured as accelerated AVP ports for highthroughput traffic. You can select any
          other combination, as required by your application.</p><p>Once the three network
          interfaces have been selected, the Networking tab appears as follows:</p><p>
          <image href="../../media/CGH-deploy-bridge-launch-nic.png"/>
        </p><p>
          <b>Note:</b> The interface type and allocated NIC order cannot be changed after the
          instance is launched. To use different port assignments, you must shut down and delete the
          instance, and then launch a new instance.</p></li>
<li>Implement a function on the guest image.<p>You can implement a function on a guest image by
          applying user data.</p><p>In the Launch Instance window, select the Post-Creation tab and
          populate the Customization Script text box with the appropriate user data.</p><p>
          <b>Caution:</b> The first line in the user data is a mandatory comment. Without it, the
          user data is ignored, and all network interfaces are initialized using DHCP.</p><ul>
          <li>
            <p>To implement a Linux bridge on the guest image, add the following user data for both
              tenant1 and tenant2:</p>
            <codeblock><codeph>#wrs-config
FUNCTIONS="bridge"
BRIDGE_PORTS="eth1,eth2.5"
</codeph></codeblock>
          </li>
        </ul><p>These key-value pairs implement a Linux-kernel bridge attached to interfaces
            <codeph>eth1</codeph> and <codeph>eth2.5</codeph>, where the notation eth2.5 indicates
          traffic on eth2 tagged with VLAN ID 5.</p><ul>
          <li>
            <p>To implement a DPDK-accelerated bridge on the guest image, add the following user
              data for both tenant1 and tenant2.</p>
            <codeblock>
<codeph>#wrs-config
FUNCTIONS="hugepages,vswitch"
BRIDGE_PORTS="eth0,eth1.5"
</codeph>
</codeblock>
          </li>
        </ul><p>These key-value pairs implement a DPDK-accelerated bridge attached to two network
          interfaces, identified as <codeph>eth0</codeph> and <codeph>eth1.5</codeph>. The notation
            <codeph>eth1.5</codeph> indicates traffic on <codeph>eth1</codeph> tagged with
            <codeph>VLAN ID 5</codeph>. For this type of VNF, the interfaces are identified with
          respect to the bridge rather than the Linux kernel. They map to the Linux kernel
          interfaces as follows:</p><table>
          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1"/>
            <colspec colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1"/>
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Linux Kernel</entry>
                <entry>DPDK-Accelerated Bridge</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>eth0 (tenant1-mgmt-net)</entry>
                <entry>--</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>eth1 (tenant1-net)</entry>
                <entry>eth0</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>eth2 (internal-net)</entry>
                <entry>eth1</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></li>
<li>
<p>Launch the instance.</p>

<p>In the <b>Launch Instance</b> window, click <b>Launch</b> to create the instance.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>The Bridging Scenario is now running.</p>
<p>The updated Network Topology page for user1 appears as shown:</p>
<p>
  <image href="../../media/CGH-deploy-bridge-user1.png"/>
</p>
<p>The updated Network Topology page for user2 appears as shown:</p>
<p>
  <image href="../../media/CGH-deploy-bridge-user2.png"/>
</p>
<p>
<b>Note:</b> To complete the deployment scenarios, this task must be repeated as user2, substituting appropriate names. Once the virtual machines for both tenant users are running, you can run test traffic through the test path. For more information, see <xref href="../../CarrierGrade/DeploymentScenarios/carrier-grade-deployment-running-traffic.dita" >Running Traffic Through the Test Paths</xref>.</p>
<p>
  <xref type="section" href="#topic6719"> Return to Top </xref>
</p>
<!-- ===================== horizontal rule ===================== -->
</body>
</topic>
