<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333480544" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <!-- Modification History

 -->
    <title ixia_locid="1">Overview</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is a high-performance,
        high-availability, cloud operating system that enables telecommunications operators to use
        off-the-shelf (COTS) hardware to manage Virtualized Network Functions (VNF) within a carrier
        grade Network Function Virtualization (NFV) architecture.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
        <author ixia_locid="4">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="72">Installing the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade involves loading and configuring the
            software on the controller nodes, and then using the controller nodes to initialize
            compute and storage nodes. For details, see <xref href="jow1404333484592.xml" ixia_locid="73"/>.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="77">Before installation, ensure that you are familiar with the HP Helion
            OpenStack Carrier Grade  architecture, and that your hardware meets the minimum
            requirements. For architecture details, refer to the <cite ixia_locid="15">HP Helion
                OpenStack Carrier Grade Administration Guide</cite>. For minimum hardware
            requirements, see <xref href="jow1419267663457.xml" ixia_locid="92"/>.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="85">Review the <cite ixia_locid="86">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Release
                Notes</cite> for any additional information pertaining to installation.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="78">During installation, have ready the following items:</p>
        <ul id="ul_bgn_frw_g4">
            <li ixia_locid="8">
                <p ixia_locid="9">the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade ISO image on bootable media.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="12">
                <p ixia_locid="13">a configuration plan for use during the installation process</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="90">
                <p ixia_locid="91">a license file</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="93">
                <p ixia_locid="94">(optional) a CA-signed certificate, if  secure HTTPS access is required for REST
                    API applications</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p ixia_locid="80"> For help creating a bootable USB drive, see <xref href="jow1404840003558.xml" ixia_locid="81"/>.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="56">You should be familiar with the following terms used in this guide: </p>
        <dl>
            <dlentry ixia_locid="57">
                <dt ixia_locid="58"><term ixia_locid="87">host</term></dt>
                <dd ixia_locid="59">
                    <p ixia_locid="60">A unit of computing hardware in the rack. Hosts can be
                        assigned or <term ixia_locid="75">commissioned</term> as controller,
                        compute, or storage nodes. </p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry ixia_locid="61">
                <dt ixia_locid="62"><term ixia_locid="88">personality</term></dt>
                <dd ixia_locid="63">
                    <p ixia_locid="64">The role assigned to a host when it is commissioned.
                        Available personalities include <term ixia_locid="82">controller</term>,
                            <term ixia_locid="83">compute</term>, and <term ixia_locid="84">storage</term>.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
            <dlentry ixia_locid="68">
                <dt ixia_locid="69"><term ixia_locid="89">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Cluster</term></dt>
                <dd ixia_locid="70">
                    <p ixia_locid="71">An ensemble of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade hosts. A HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
                        cluster consists of compute nodes and optionally two storage nodes managed
                        by a pair of controller nodes.</p>
                </dd>
            </dlentry>
        </dl>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>