<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="topic_vsf_hnh_ts">
  <title>Install the Database Service</title>
  <body>
<section id="install-database">
<p>This section provides details on installing the Database Service from the Development Platform.</p>
</section>

<section id="availability-zones"> <title>Availability Zones</title>
<p>To configure the Database Service in a highly available manner, it is necessary to create separate availability zones. As a best practice, HP recommends creating three availability zones. All compute hosts should be placed within one of these availability zones. If a compute host is not associated with an availability zone, the Database Service will not be able to provision a database instance to it. As a result, the Database Service may run out of capacity even though there are compute hosts with free capacity.</p>
<p>The following steps show how to create three availability zones and assign a compute host to the zone.</p>
<ol>
<li> Connect to an overcloud controller node and execute the following commands to create three
          availability zones named: "AZ-1", "AZ-2" and
          "AZ-3".<codeblock>nova aggregate-create aggregate-AZ-1 AZ-1
nova aggregate-create aggregate-AZ-2 AZ-2
nova aggregate-create aggregate-AZ-3 AZ-3</codeblock></li>
<li> Validate that the availability zones were correctly created by issuing the following
          command.<codeblock>nova aggregate-list</codeblock></li>
<li> The following commands will add a compute host to your newly created availability zones. Issue
          this command for every compute host that you wish to associate with an availability
          zone.<codeblock>nova aggregate-add-host &lt;id&gt; &lt;hostname&gt;</codeblock></li>
<li> The following command can be used to list all availability zones and the compute hosts
          associated with them.<codeblock>nova availability-zone-list</codeblock></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="quotas"> <title>Quotas</title>
<p>The <b>Database Service</b> will be installed into the admin tenant of the Helion OpenStack overcloud and the admin tenant must have sufficient quota available and unused resources for the service to use. To check existing quota availability, log-in to Horizon as the <b>admin</b> user and open the <b>Overview</b> panel under the <b>Compute</b> tab.</p>
<p>If you are not configuring the Database Service to be highly available you must have the following quota available:</p>
<table>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="col1"/>
<colspec colname="col2"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry>Resource</entry>
  <entry align="right">Usage</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>Floating IPs</entry>
  <entry align="right">6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Instances</entry>
  <entry align="right">6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Networks</entry>
  <entry align="right">2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>RAM (GB)</entry>
  <entry align="right">24</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Routers</entry>
  <entry align="right">2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Security Groups</entry>
  <entry align="right">6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Volumes</entry>
  <entry align="right">4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Volume Storage (GB)</entry>
  <entry align="right">160</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<p>If you have set up Availability Zones and plan to install the Database Service in a highly-available configuration you must have the following quota available:</p>
<table>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="col1"/>
<colspec colname="col2"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry>Resource</entry>
  <entry align="right">Usage</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>Floating IPs</entry>
  <entry align="right">16</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Instances</entry>
  <entry align="right">16</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Networks</entry>
  <entry align="right">2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>RAM (GB)</entry>
  <entry align="right">64</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Routers</entry>
  <entry align="right">2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Security Groups</entry>
  <entry align="right">6</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Volumes</entry>
  <entry align="right">4</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Volume Storage (GB)</entry>
  <entry align="right">160</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<p>In addition to the quota mentioned above, for every database instance that is created by a user, the necessary resources to create that instance will be deducted from the admin tenant quota. The users database service quota will also be affected.</p>
</section>
<section id="db-connect-to-the-download-service"> <title>Connect to the Download Service</title>
<ol>
<li>Open Horizon and login as the "admin" user. You must run the entire install logged in as "admin". </li>
<li> Click on the Admin panel in Horizon and select the <b>Development Platform</b> panel under
          Admin. Then click on the <b>Configure Services</b> sub-panel.</li>
<li> Click the <b>Connect</b> button on the <b>Configure Services</b> panel and enter your username
          and password for the HP Download Network (HDN). Select the Sign-up button if you do not
          have an account.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="download-the-database-service"> <title>Download the Database Service</title>
<ol>
<li> In the <b>Configure Services</b> panel locate the Database Service item in the Configure
          Services table and select <b>Download Service</b> and wait for the download to complete.<p>
            <image href="../../media/HDP_1.2_install_database.png"/>
          </p><p>
            <note> Downloading multiple services simultaneously is not supported, and will leave the
              server in an error state.</note>
          </p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="configuring-the-database-service">
      <title>Configuring the Database Service</title>
      <ol>
        <li> Once the download is complete, click the <b>Configure Service</b> button to begin
          configuration of the service. In the configuration dialog, specify the following
          configuration options:<ul>
            <li>
              <b>Service User Password</b> (Required) - The password for the Admin user that is
              currently logged in. This password MUST match the password used to log in to
              Horizon.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Key Pair</b> (Required) - Key Pair to install on all instances created as part of
              the database service. The public key can be used by an admin to get SSH access to all
              instances.</li>
            <li>
              <b>External Network</b> (Required) - Network Name for the network that has external
              network access. For HP Helion OpenStack Commercial Edition this network is named
                <b>ext-net</b> .</li>
            <li>
              <b>Provider Network</b> (Required) - Network Name for the network that has network
              access to cloud infrastructure services. For HP Helion OpenStack Commercial Edition
              this network is named <b>SVC</b>.</li>
            <li>
              <b>NTP Server IP</b> - IP Address to an NTP server to use if instances will not have
              outbound access to the internet.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Logstash RabbitMQ IP Address</b> (Required) - Specify the IP address of the
              RabbitMQ Server publishing to the central Logstash server.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Logstash RabbitMQ Password</b> (Required) - Specify the password for the RabbitMQ
              Server publishing to the central Logstash server.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Ephemeral CA Password</b> (Required) - Specify the password for the Ephemeral CA
              server. </li>
            <li>
              <b>Ephemeral CA IP Address</b> (Required) - Specify the IP address of Ephemeral CA
              server.</li>
            <li>
              <b>Volume Type</b> (Required) - The volume type to use when creating database
              instances.</li>
            <li>
              <p>
                <b>Enable HA</b> - Specify if the database service is to be set up in a
                high-availability (HA) configuration. If selected, each component of the service
                will have three instances created and active at all times. </p>
              <p>
                <image href="../../media/dev_install_database_new.png" placement="break"/>
              </p>
            </li>
          </ul></li>
        <li> After all configuration options have been provided, select the <b>Configure</b> button
          to complete the configuration step. Wait for the configuration step to complete and the
          status to change to <b>Configured</b>.</li>
      </ol><sectiondiv><p><b>Configure HAProxy</b></p>The following steps will configure HAProxy to
        receive and forward HTTP requests to the VM that hosts the REST API endpoint for the
        Database Service.<!--A BR tag was used here in the original source.--><b>Note</b>: To
        perform these steps you must be connected to the overcloud. <ol>
          <li> Identify the API server IPs on the SVC network. You should have as many API servers
            (and IPs) as you have Availability Zones in your Helion OpenStack installation.<codeblock>nova list | awk '/trove[0-9]*_api/{ print $4,"\t", substr($12,5) }' </codeblock></li>
          <li> Identify the Virtual IP used by the controller nodes to be able to load balance the
              Helion OpenStack
            services:<codeblock>keystone endpoint-list | awk '/8779/{ print $6 }' | egrep -o "[0-9]+.[0-9]+.[0-9]+.[0-9]+"</codeblock></li>
          <li> Update configuration on each of the Helion OpenStack controller nodes by connecting
            to the controller and doing the following: <ol>
              <li>Edit the <i>/etc/haproxy/manual/paas.cfg</i> file and add the following lines. The
                last line should be repeated once for each API server identified in step
                1.<codeblock>listen trove_api
bind &lt;Virtual IP from step 2&gt;:8779
option httpchk GET /
server trove-trove&lt;n&gt;_api-&lt;uniqueid&gt; &lt;API server n's IP Address&gt; check inter 2000 rise 2 fall 5 check-ssl ca-file /etc/ssl/certs/ca-certificates.crt</codeblock></li>
              <li> Edit the /etc/iptables/rules.v4 file and add to
                it:<codeblock>-I INPUT -p tcp --dport 8779 -j ACCEPT</codeblock></li>
              <li>Run the following command as
                root:<codeblock>sudo iptables -I INPUT -p tcp --dport 8779 -j ACCEPT</codeblock></li>
              <li>Reload the haproxy service
                configuration<codeblock>sudo service haproxy reload</codeblock></li>
            </ol></li>
          <li> The installation is complete. Return to the Horizon dashboard (you may log out and
            log in with a non-Admin account if desired), and click on the <b>Database</b> panel
            under the current Project to being using Database Service. </li>
        </ol></sectiondiv></section>

 
  </body>
</topic>
