<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1411482049845" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="183">VM Network Interface Options</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="184">The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade supports both virtio and performance-optimized AVP network interface
  drivers.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="185">Michael B</author>
  <author ixia_locid="187">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <dl>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="44">
    <dt ixia_locid="45">virtio</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="46">
     <p ixia_locid="47">The standard interface type for I/O virtualization in Linux. This type can
      be used with the Linux bridge application or the router application described in these
      scenarios. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="48">
    <dt ixia_locid="49">Accelerated Virtual Port (AVP)</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="50">
     <p ixia_locid="51">A high-performance virtual network interface available exclusively on the
      HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. This type can be used with the Linux bridge application, the DPDK-accelerated
      bridge application, or the router application described in these scenarios.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
  <p ixia_locid="54">The deployment scenarios demonstrate the use of AVP interfaces with three types
   of virtualized network functions (VNFs): a Linux bridge, a DPDK-accelerated bridge, and a router.
   This illustrates the flexibility provided by the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade to adapt to different deployment
   scenarios.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="186">The port assignments for the interfaces are based on the order in which the
   interfaces are arranged in the web administration interface, or defined in the command-line
   interface, when the instance is launched. The type of virtual network interface for each port is
   selected from a list in the web administration interface, or encoded in a <parmname ixia_locid="169">vif-model</parmname> attribute on the command line.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>