<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic4010">
<title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Carrier Grade 1.1: Overview</title>
<prolog>
  <metadata>
    <othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
    <othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
    <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Administrator"/>
    <othermeta name="role" content="Storage Architect"/>
    <othermeta name="role" content="Michael B"/>
    <othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack Carreir Grade 1.1"/>
  </metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
    <section>
      <!-- From QuickSpec Asawa, Manjari <manjari.asawa@hp.com> -->
      <p><b>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade </b> is a carrier grade OpenStack solution plus
        compute and network functions virtualization (NFV) offering that enables CSPs to deploy
        applications on open source software platforms.  </p>
      <p>Some key examples include the host operating system (for example, Linux), server
        virtualization (KVM), network virtualization (vSwitch and SDN controllers), an installer and
        cloud lifecycle management framework, fault and performance management, and
        high-availability framework for the OpenStack control plane and the NFVI layer.</p>
      <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is based on HP Helion Openstack 1.1 but
        with significantly enhanced and optimized functionality, availability, scale and performance
        to meet the needs of NFV cloud deployments.</p>
      <p>Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade includes following key components:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>OpenStack—core services including Horizon, Nova, Neutron, Cinder, Glance, Swift,
          Keystone, Ceilometer, and Heat. Other services will be added as needed in the future.</li>
        <li>Compute node software package that includes: <ul>
            <li>Carrier-grade Linux (host operating system [OS] running on the compute nodes)</li>
            <li>Carrier-grade KVM (for virtualization of the compute node)</li>
            <li>Carrier-grade accelerated virtual switch (AVS), data plane development kit
              (DPDK)-enabled high-performance virtual switch</li>
          </ul></li>
        <li>Management and middleware—composed of high-availability (HA) management; operations,
          administration, and maintenance (OAM); software image management; and fault and
          performance management</li>
        <li>Guest software development kit (SDK) for inclusion in the guest OS of the VNF for
          performance acceleration and improving the HA framework above and beyond standard
          VIMs</li>
        <li>HP Helion Lifecycle Manager (HLM)—cloud installer and lifecycle manager</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="focus-areas-for-hp-helion-openstack-carrier-grade">
      <title>Standard Features</title>
      <!-- From QuickSpec Asawa, Manjari <manjari.asawa@hp.com> -->
      <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colname="col1"/>
          <colspec colname="col2"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry> Feature </entry>
              <entry> Description </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry> Availability and reliability </entry>
              <entry>
                <ul>
                  <li>Advanced self-healing</li>
                  <li>No single point of failure</li>
                </ul>
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry> Platform for high performance VNFs </entry>
              <entry>
                <ul>
                  <li>Near-line rate networking throughout for VNFs like vEPC, vBRAS, vIMS, vFW,
                    vRouter etc.</li>
                  <li>Bare metal compute performance</li>
                </ul>
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry> Manageability </entry>
              <entry>
                <ul>
                  <li>In-service upgrade capabilities</li>
                  <li>Enhanced security</li>
                  <li>Inventory management</li>
                  <li>Advanced resource scheduling and orchestration capabilities</li>
                </ul>
              </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>High Availability/ Disaster Recovery </entry>
              <entry>
                <ul>
                  <li>NIC Bonding at the server level </li>
                  <li>HA for KVM instance</li>
                  <li>Compute Node failure detection and Auto-evacuation in kvm region</li>
                  <li>Live Migration in kvm region</li>
                </ul>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
 
    <section>
      <title>Service Overview</title>
      <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is comprised of a number of services, including several
        OpenStack and HP Helion OpenStack services.</p>
      <p>For more information, see <xref href="carrier-grade.services-overview.dita">Services
          Overview</xref>.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Installation Options</title>HP Helion OpenStack Carreir Grade has two baremetal
      installation options depending on your system configuration. It allows you to manage the KVM
      and VMware ESX<tm tmtype="reg"/> hypervisors and provision virtual machines.<p>You can find
        more information on the hypervisor options in the <xref
          href="../Installation/carrier-grade-technical-overview.dita#topic3485">Technical
          Overview</xref>.</p></section>
  <section id="kvm-Hypervisor">
    <title>KVM Topology</title>
    <p>If you install the KVM deployment, you can integrate either HP Storevirtual (VSA) or HP
      StoreServ (3PAR) storage in the KVM region.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>With HP StoreVirtual VSA storage <p>HP StoreVirtual VSA software is a Virtual Storage
        Appliance that provides the complete array functionality on top of a Linux KVM
        environment without external hardware. VSA eliminates the need for external shared
        storage required to implement Block Storage features.</p></li>
      
      <li>With HP StoreServ (3PAR) storage <p>HP 3PAR StoreServ is a storage array that supports
        Fibre Channel (FC) as well as iSCSI protocol.</p></li>
    </ul>
    <p>You must install 3PAR or VSA before starting the HP Helion OpenStack installation and are
        independent of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. </p>
  </section>
  <section id="esx-hypervisor"><title>KVM + ESX Topology</title>The ESXi/DCN integration enables
      data-center-to-data-center communications through DCN, which connects to the KVM region
      through a gateway (VRS-G). <p>HP Helion OpenStack supports VMWare ESX hypervisor. With our ESX
        integration, you can provision and manage an overcloud ESX cluster. VMWare vCenter Compute
        driver is used as a part of ESX integration. The VMware vCenter driver connects to ESX
        clusters in a vCenter through Compute proxy nodes.</p><p>Virtual networking between HP
        Helion Carrier Grade and the ESX servers is handled by HP Distributed Cloud Networking (DCN)
        is a software-defined networking (SDN) solution that enhances data center (DC) network
        virtualization by automatically establishing connectivity between compute resources upon
        their creation. </p><p>The ESX integration uses the OVSvApp application to connect the
        vCenter networking to the Network Operations controller to manage workload networks.
        </p><p>You can also integrate HP Storevirtual (VSA) or HP StoreServ (3PAR) storage in the
        KVM region. </p><p>You must install ESX, 3PAR or VSA before starting the HP Helion OpenStack
        installation and are independent of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. </p></section>
  
  <section id="nic"><title>Unbonded or Bonded NIC configuration</title>
    <p>The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade installation allows for network interface card bonding
        (bonded NIC). </p>
  </section>
  
    <!-- 
  <section id="distributed-cloud-networking-dcn"> <title>Distributed Cloud Networking (DCN)</title>
<p>Distributed Cloud Networking (DCN) is a Software-Defined Networking (SDN) solution that provides data center (DC) network virtualization and automatically establishes connectivity between compute resources upon their creation.</p>
<p>For more information, see <xref href="../../CarrierGrade/Overview/carrier-grade-overview-dcn.dita" >Distributed Cloud Networking Overview</xref>.</p>
<p>HP Helion OpenStack offers many services based on the different OpenStack projects to provide the functionality you need. Visit the <xref href="../../CarrierGrade/Overview/carrier-grade.services-overview.dita" >HP Helion OpenStack Services Overview page</xref> for a complete list of services.</p>
<p>
  <xref type="section" href="#topic4010"> Return to Top </xref>
</p>
</section> -->
    <!-- ===================== horizontal rule ===================== -->
  </body>
</topic>
