<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic1495">
<title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Carrier Grade 2.0 Alpha: Non-KVM Region Overview</title>
<titlealts>
<searchtitle>HP Helion Openstack Carrier Grade: HP Helion Openstack Overview</searchtitle>
</titlealts>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="All"/>
<othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
    <p>For installation and maintenance, HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade consists of two logical
      or conceptual <i>regions</i>: Non-KVM and KVM. The Non-KVM region contains the HP Helion
      Lifecycle Management (HLM), to deploy and maintain HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade; and HP
      Helion OpenStack, a commercial-grade distribution of OpenStack.</p>
    <p><b>Note:</b> These regions do not function as OpenStack regions. </p>

<section><title>HP Helion Lifecycle Management</title>
  <p>The Non-KVM environment includes a full installation of HP Helion Lifecycle Management (HLM).
    HLM is an application that is used to deploy HP Helion OpenStack Carrier
    Grade and can be used for ongoing operations and maintenance of the system.</p>
  <ul id="ul_bhj_clv_ls">
    <li>
      <p>
            <b>Physical Node Preparation.</b> HLM can configure nodes prior to installation of a
            base operating system, including node discovery/inventory, BIOS configuration,
            (specifically setting PXE boot on primary interface), GRUB settings, RAID setup for
            local disks, iLO/IPMI set up and firmware upgrades.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
            <b>OS Install.</b> HLM can take a PXE bootable node and installs a base operating
            system.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
            <b>Cloud Configuration.</b> HLM can provide detailed information about the cloud
            topology, such as the structure of control plane, assignment of services to nodes, and
            service configuration. You can also specify environment-specific configurations.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <b>OS Configuration.</b> HLM can automatically execute operating system configuration
        values, such as NIC assignments, NTP settings, DNS settings, NIC bonding, sysctl settings,
        VLAN creation etc. HLM uses the Ansible data model output and HLM server playbooks to
        automatically apply the per-node configurations.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
            <b>Helion Operation &amp; Maintenance.</b> HLM is responsible for the deploy, upgrade
            and maintenance lifecycle of the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade system.</p>
    </li>
  </ul>
  
</section>
 
  <section><b>ESX Integration</b><p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade supports VMWare ESX<tm
          tmtype="reg"/> hypervisor using HP Distributed Cloud Networking (aka DCN). With our ESX
        integration, the cloud can provision and manage an ESX cluster. VMWare Compute Proxy is used
        as a part of ESX integration. The VMware vCenter driver connects to ESX clusters through
        Nova Compute proxy nodes. A Compute node scheduler sees each cluster as compute and uses the
        same for scheduling new instances.</p><p>The ESX integration uses the VRSvAPP application to
        connect the V&lt;ware vCenter™ networking to the Network Operations controller to manage
        workload networks.</p><p>The HP DCN is a software-Defined Networking (SDN) solution that
        enhances data center (DC) network virtualization by automatically establishing connectivity
        between compute resources upon their creation. </p><p>ESX region uses mixture of best
        features from OpenStack, ESX and DCN:</p><ul id="ul_p44_snk_ws">
        <li>OpenStack features with rich services such as Keystone, Glance, Nova, Neutron, Cinder,
          Horizon</li>
        <li>ESX providing foundation for building and managing a virtualized IT infrastructure</li>
        <li>ESX providing reliability and performance</li>
        <li>ESX hypervisor abstracting processor, memory and storage</li>
        <li>DCN providing programmable business logic and a powerful policy engine</li>
        <li>DCN providing open and highly responsive solution that scales and span across
          multi-tenant DCs</li>
        <li>Inter-region and Inter-cloud communication between different data centers</li>
        <li>ESX region uses VMDK driver using multi-backend storage support from Cinder </li>
      </ul><p>In the KVM + ESX deployment, the non-KVM region also includes integration into your
        VMware vServer storage environment using HP Distributed Cloud Networking
      (DCN).</p></section>
  
  
  <section><title>HP Helion OpenStack</title>
  <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is a carrier-grade distribution of OpenStack the leading open source cloud computing platform. This
      distribution, backed by HP, enables customers to more easily build, manage, and use
      open-source based hybrid cloud in a resilient, maintainable platform. HP Helion OpenStack enables cost-effective scalability of IT services and business
      agility and, as part of the HP Helion portfolio, it is backed by a wide range of related cloud
      products, services, and professional support.</p>
<p>HP Helion OpenStack offers many services based on the different OpenStack projects to provide the functionality you need. Visit the <xref href="../../CarrierGrade/Overview/carrier-grade.services-overview.dita" >HP Helion OpenStack Services Overview page</xref> for a complete list of services.</p>
    <!-- From http://wiki.hpcloud.net/display/core/Helion+Lifecycle+Management+Root -->
  </section>
  
  <section>
<p><xref type="section" href="#topic1495"> Return to Top </xref></p>
<!-- ===================== horizontal rule ===================== -->
  </section>
</body>
</topic>
