<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic4010">
<title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Carrier Grade 1.1 GA: Overview</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
  <section>
    <p><!--UNDER REVISION--><!--./CarrierGrade/Overview/carrier-grade-overview.md--><!--permalink: /helion/openstack/carrier/overview/--></p>
    <!-- From Helion-CSP-Edition.pptx  https://wiki.hpcloud.net/download/attachments/32052622/Helion-CSP-Edition.pptx?version=1&modificationDate=1426628637000&api=v2 -->
    <p><b>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade (HCG)</b> is a carrier grade OpenStack plus compute and
      network virtualization offering for NFV that enable CSPs to deploy network functions
      virtualization (NFV) applications on open source software platforms. </p>
    <p>Some key examples include the host operating system (for example, Linux), server
      virtualization (KVM), network virtualization (vSwitch and SDN controllers), an installer and
      cloud lifecycle management framework, fault and performance management, and high-availability
      framework for the OpenStack control plane and the NFVI layer.</p>
    <p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is based on <xref
        href="../../commercial/GA1/1.1commercial.index.dita">HP Helion Openstack 1.1</xref> but with
      significantly enhanced and optimized functionality, availability, scale and performance to
      meet the needs of NFV cloud deployments.</p>
  
  <p>Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade includes following  key components:</p>
  <ul><li>OpenStack—core services including Horizon, Nova, Neutron, Cinder, Glance, Swift, Keystone, Ceilometer, and Heat. Other services will be added as needed in the future.</li>
  <li>Compute node software package that  includes:
    <ul>
      <li>Carrier-grade Linux (host operating system [OS] running on the compute nodes)</li>
      <li>Carrier-grade KVM (for virtualization of the compute node)</li>
      <li>Carrier-grade accelerated virtual switch (AVS), data plane development kit (DPDK)-enabled high-performance virtual switch</li></ul></li>
  <li>Management and middleware—composed of high-availability (HA) management; operations, administration, and
    maintenance (OAM); software image management; and fault and performance management</li>
    <li>Guest software development kit (SDK) for inclusion in the guest OS of the VNF for performance acceleration and
      improving the HA framework above and beyond standard VIMs</li>
    <li>HP Helion Lifecycle Manager (HLM)—cloud installer and lifecycle manager</li>
  </ul>
  </section>
    <section id="focus-areas-for-hp-helion-openstack-carrier-grade">
      <title>Focus areas for HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade</title>
      <!-- From Helion-CSP-Edition.pptx  https://wiki.hpcloud.net/download/attachments/32052622/Helion-CSP-Edition.pptx?version=1&modificationDate=1426628637000&api=v2 -->
      <ul>
        <li>Central control plane but resources are distributed across geography interconnected by
          WAN</li>
        <li>VNF resource requirement definition, policy based resource scheduling &amp;
          placement</li>
        <li>VNF Orchestration - Policy based Auto-scaling</li>
        <li>Integrated Physical and Virtual resource monitoring and self-healing</li>
        <li>Highly Resilient and hit-less upgrades</li>
        <li>High performance data plane </li>
        <li>Integration with Open Source SDN controllers and service chaining</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="major-components-in-hp-helion-openstack-carrier-grade">
      <title>Major Components in HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade</title>
      <p>For installation and maintenance, HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade consists of two logical
        or conceptual <i>regions</i>: Non-KVM and KVM. See the <xref
          href="../Installation/carrier-grade-technical-overview.dita#topic3485/deploy-arch"
          >Deployment Architecture diagram</xref> in the Technical Overview for an illustration of
        these two zones.  </p>
    </section>
    <section><b>Non-KVM</b>
      <p>The Non-KVM region contains the HP Helion Lifecycle Management (HLM), to deploy and
        maintain HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade; and HP Helion OpenStack, a commercial-grade
        distribution of OpenStack. The Non-KVM region consists of a host system for HLM and three HP
        Helion OpenStack controllers.</p><p>For more information, see <xref
          href="carrier-grade-overview-non-kvm.dita">Non-KVM Environment
      Overview</xref>.</p></section>
    <section><b>KVM</b><p>The KVM region is the heart of HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. The KVM
        region consists of a software platform, providing ultra-reliability and exceptional
        performance efficiencies for telecommunications networks. </p><p>For more information, see
          <xref href="carrier-grade-overview-kvm.dita">KVM Environment
      Overview</xref>.</p></section>
  <section><title>Service Overview</title><p>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is comprised
        of a number of services, including several OpenStack and HP Helion OpenStack
        services.</p><p>For more information, see <xref href="carrier-grade.services-overview.dita"
          >Services Overview</xref>.</p></section>
    <section/>
    <!-- 
  <section id="distributed-cloud-networking-dcn"> <title>Distributed Cloud Networking (DCN)</title>
<p>Distributed Cloud Networking (DCN) is a Software-Defined Networking (SDN) solution that provides data center (DC) network virtualization and automatically establishes connectivity between compute resources upon their creation.</p>
<p>For more information, see <xref href="../../CarrierGrade/Overview/carrier-grade-overview-dcn.dita" >Distributed Cloud Networking Overview</xref>.</p>
<p>HP Helion OpenStack offers many services based on the different OpenStack projects to provide the functionality you need. Visit the <xref href="../../CarrierGrade/Overview/carrier-grade.services-overview.dita" >HP Helion OpenStack Services Overview page</xref> for a complete list of services.</p>
<p>
  <xref type="section" href="#topic4010"> Return to Top </xref>
</p>
</section> -->
    <!-- ===================== horizontal rule ===================== -->
  </body>
</topic>
