<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/topic.dtd" ><topic xml:lang="en-us" id="topic1743">
<title>HP Helion <tm tmtype="reg">OpenStack</tm> Carrier Grade 1.1: KVM Environment
    Overview</title>
<prolog>
<metadata>
<othermeta name="layout" content="default"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
<othermeta name="role" content="All"/>
<othermeta name="product-version1" content="HP Helion Openstack"/>
<othermeta name="product-version2" content="HP Helion Openstack 1.1"/>
</metadata>
</prolog>
<body>
<p>
<!--UNDER REVISION-->
 <!--./CarrierGrade/Overview/carrier-grade-overview-wr.md-->
 <!--permalink: /helion/openstack/carrier/wr/overview/--></p>
<!-- Taken from http://www.windriver.com/products/titanium-server/ -->
<p>The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade KVM environment is based on Wind River Linux.  The KVM
      environment is a high-performance, high-availability, cloud operating system that enables
      telecommunications operators to use Commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) hardware to manage
      Virtualized Network Functions (VNF) within a carrier grade Network Function Virtualization
      (NFV) architecture.</p>
<p>THe KVM environment includes the critical run-time components and lifecycle development tools,
      services, and developer support needed to successfully build and deploy a virtualized network
      running multiple VMs.</p>
<ul>
<li>TL 9000 design methodology to guarantee six nines reliability</li>
<li>Full 10 G line rate accelerated virtual switching running unmodified guest applications</li>
<li>10 microsecond deterministic interrupt latency to support virtualization in the most stringent customer-provided equipment (CPE) and access sections of the network</li>
<li>Accelerated live VM migration, including the share nothing model, which is faster than enterprise software</li>
<li>500 km geographical redundancy over a standard IP network; more over dedicated fiber</li>
<li>Detection of failed controllers, hosts, or VMs 60x faster than enterprise Linux; automatic recovery, with no single point of failure</li>
<li>Fully integrated telecom-grade security, including complete AAA access control</li>
<li>Involvement in trials with the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI) and other standards bodies</li>
</ul>
<p>
  <xref type="section" href="#topic1743"> Return to Top </xref>
</p>
<!-- ===================== horizontal rule ===================== -->
</body>
</topic>
