<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333737339" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">The Infrastructure Network</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The infrastructure network is a private network visible only to the
        hosts in the cluster. It is optional unless storage nodes are part of the
        cluster.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="25">Jim Owens</author>
        <author></author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="26"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="27">86214 updated</draft-comment>For the most
            part, the infrastructure network shares the design considerations applicable to the
            internal management network. It can be implemented using either a 1 Gb or 10 Gb Ethernet
            interface. It can be VLAN-tagged, enabling it to share an interface with the management
            or OAM network. It can own the entire IP address range on the subnet, or a specified
            range.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="28">The infrastructure network supports dynamic or static IP address
            assignment. The setting is determined by the setting for the management network. If
            static assignment is used, you must manually assign IP addresses on the infrastructure
            network for the other hosts in the cluster, using the <cmdname ixia_locid="29">system
                host-addr-add</cmdname> command.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="5">The decision whether to implement an infrastructure network depends on the
            infrastructure traffic levels expected. The following table provides general guidelines
            on when to implement the infrastructure network, using the number of compute nodes in
            the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade cluster as an indication of expected traffic levels.</p>
        <simpletable id="simpletable_lgh_vms_14" relcolwidth="1.0* 3.0*">
            <sthead>
                <stentry ixia_locid="6">
                    <p ixia_locid="7">Number of Compute Nodes</p>
                </stentry>
                <stentry ixia_locid="8">
                    <p ixia_locid="9">Infrastructure Network Implementation</p>
                </stentry>
            </sthead>
            <strow>
                <stentry ixia_locid="10">
                    <p ixia_locid="11">2 to 4</p>
                </stentry>
                <stentry ixia_locid="12">
                    <p ixia_locid="13">No infrastructure network required. All infrastructure
                        traffic is carried over the internal management network.</p>
                </stentry>
            </strow>
            <strow>
                <stentry ixia_locid="14">
                    <p ixia_locid="15">5 to 8</p>
                </stentry>
                <stentry ixia_locid="16">
                    <p ixia_locid="17">Use 1 Gb Ethernet</p>
                </stentry>
            </strow>
            <strow>
                <stentry ixia_locid="18">
                    <p ixia_locid="19">9 or more</p>
                </stentry>
                <stentry ixia_locid="20">
                    <p ixia_locid="30">Use 10 Gb Ethernet</p>
                </stentry>
            </strow>
        </simpletable>
        <p ixia_locid="22">In addition to the number of compute nodes, other factors must be taken into account when
            deciding the type of infrastructure network to use. For example, live migration of
            large, memory-intensive, guest applications is likely to require additional network
            resources that might not be available in the current configuration. It is always safe to
            implement the fastest infrastructure network possible.</p>
        <note id="note_N10095_N1001D_N10001" ixia_locid="23">
            <p conref="jow1419267499106.xml#jow1419267499106/multicast_in_use" ixia_locid="24"/>
        </note>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>