<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="jow1429546712705" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Enabling the Guest Heartbeat API for a VM</title>
    <shortdesc>You can accommodate the use of guest heartbeats on a VM using an extra specification. </shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <taskbody>
        <context id="context_N1001E_N1001B_N10001">
            <p>Select this option when you expect one or more of the guest
                applications running on the virtual machine to make use of the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Guest
                Heartbeat API.  If no extra spec is added, then by default the API is disabled.</p>
            <p> If this option is selected, the controller node starts heartbeat
                application-level polling cycles on virtual machines launched using the flavor. For
                more information about the Guest Heartbeat API, refer to the <cite>HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Software Development Kit</cite>.</p>
            <p>A guest application modified to use the Titanium Guest Server
                Heartbeat API can be more accurately monitored by internal messaging within the
                virtual machine. For more about application monitoring, see <xref href="jow1404333802962.xml"/>.</p>
            <p>To add this extra spec to a flavor using the web administration
                interface, use the <uicontrol>Guest Heartbeat</uicontrol> selection
                in the <uicontrol>Create Flavor Extra Spec</uicontrol> drop-down
                menu.  To access this menu, see <xref href="jow1429538642910.xml"/>. </p>
            <note id="note_N1004E_N10021_N1001E_N10001">
                <p>The non-default value <nameliteral>True</nameliteral> is offered when the extra spec is added using the web
                    administration interface.</p>
            </note>
            <p>To enable the Guest Heartbeat API using the CLI, use the following
                command:</p>
            <codeblock><systemoutput>~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput>nova flavor-key <varname>flavor_name</varname> set sw:wrs:guest:heartbeat=<varname>value</varname></userinput></codeblock>
            <p>where <varname>value</varname> is either
                    <nameliteral>True</nameliteral> or <nameliteral>False</nameliteral>. If any other value is supplied, it is
                ignored and the default value <nameliteral>False</nameliteral> is used.</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task-wr>