<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="jow1426181040008" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title>Specifying Local Storage for VM Ephemeral Resources</title>
    <shortdesc>To use local storage for ephemeral resources, you must specify
        instantiation on a host with local storage. You can do this by using a flavor with the
        appropriate extra specification.</shortdesc>
    <prolog><author/>
        <author/>
    </prolog>
    <taskbody>
        <context id="context_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
            <p>Each new flavor is automatically assigned a <nameliteral>Storage Type</nameliteral> extra spec that specifies, as the
                default, instantiation on hosts without local storage. You can change this extra
                spec so that hosts with local storage are used. Ephemeral storage resources
                    (<nameliteral>Ephemeral Disk</nameliteral> and <nameliteral>Swap Disk</nameliteral> space) defined for the flavor use this
                local storage, which is allocated from the Local Volume Group on the host.</p>
            <p>If the extra spec is set for local storage and instance is booted
                from an image, then the root disk is ephemeral and also uses local storage. If the
                instance is booted from a volume, the root disk uses Cinder-based storage allocated
                from the controller (for a system using LVM) or from storage hosts (for a system
                using 3PAR).</p>
            <note id="note_N10036_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
                <p>For faster VM booting, use a prepared Cinder volume. For more information, see
                        <xref href="jow1439393204460.xml"/>.</p>
            </note>
        </context>
        <prereq id="prereq_N10022_N1001F_N10001">
            <p>Before you can use local storage for a VM, you must configure at least
                one compute node to provide local storage. For more information, see <xref href="jow1426183480976.xml"/>.</p>
        </prereq>
        <context id="context_N1002F_N1001F_N10001">
            <note conref="jow1426942555025.xml#jow1426942555025/note_local_storage_ephemeral" id="note_N10037_N10032_N1001F_N10001"/>
            <p>To change the extra specification using the web administration
                interface, click <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> for the existing
                    <nameliteral>Storage Type</nameliteral> extra specification,
                and then select the <uicontrol>Local Storage</uicontrol> check box.
                To access the extra specification, see <xref href="jow1429538642910.xml"/>. </p>
            <note id="note_N10064_N10042_N1001F_N10001" type="caution">
                <p>If the <nameliteral>Storage Type</nameliteral>
                    extra spec is not specified, instantiated VMs may use hosts with or without
                    local storage. To ensure that instantiated VMs use storage of a known type, do
                    not delete this extra spec.</p>
            </note>
            <p>You can also specify the extra spec from the CLI by setting the
                following parameter for a flavor:</p>
            <codeblock><userinput>aggregate_instance_extra_specs:localstorage=<varname>loc_storage</varname></userinput></codeblock>
            <p>where <varname>loc_storage</varname> is one of the
                following:</p>
            <dl>
                <dlentry>
                    <dt>true</dt>
                    <dd>
                        <p>Specifies hosts with local storage for use by the VM.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
                <dlentry>
                    <dt>false</dt>
                    <dd>
                        <p>Specifies hosts without local storage for use by the
                            VM.</p>
                    </dd>
                </dlentry>
            </dl>
            <p>For example:</p>
            <codeblock><systemoutput>~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput>nova flavor-key <varname>flavor_name</varname> \
set aggregate_instance_extra_specs:localstorage=false</userinput></codeblock>
            <p>The local storage key is added by default on flavor creation and set
                to false (hosts with no local storage).</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task-wr>