<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1429628777191" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title>Virtual Routers</title>
 <shortdesc>Virtual routers provide internal and external network connectivity for
  tenants.</shortdesc>
 <prolog><author/>
  
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p> The user associated with a tenant can add a designated number of virtual
   routers (Neutron routers) to the tenant. The maximum number is specified in the quotas for the
   tenant. </p>
  <p>The virtual router automatically provides a connection to system services
   required by the tenant, such as the metadata service that supplies instances with user data. You
   can configure the virtual routers with interfaces to tenant networks to provide internal and
   external connectivity.</p>
  <p>A virtual router can be implemented as a centralized router, or a distributed
   virtual router (DVR).</p>
  <note id="note_N10031_N1001F_N10001">
   <p>Only the <nameliteral>admin</nameliteral> user can specify a distributed
    router. For other tenants, this choice is not available, and a centralized router is implemented
    by default. The <nameliteral>admin</nameliteral> user can change a centralized router to a
    distributed router on behalf of other tenants (see <xref href="jow1429637676342.xml"/>).</p>
   <p>A distributed router cannot be converted to a centralized router.</p>
  </note>
  <dl>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>Centralized</dt>
    <dd>
     <p>A centralized virtual router is instantiated on a single compute node. All traffic using the
      router must pass through the compute node.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt>Distributed</dt>
    <dd>
     <p>A distributed virtual router is instantiated in a distributed manner across
      multiple hosts. Distributed virtual routers provide more efficient routing than standard
      virtual routers for east-west (tenant-to-tenant) or floating IP address traffic. Local traffic
      is routed within the local host, while external L3 traffic is routed directly between the
      local host and the gateway router.</p>
     <p>To implement the distributed model, a centralized-portion of the router is
      still deployed on one host. The centralized portion manages north-south (external network)
      traffic and source network address translation (SNAT) traffic, as well as agents deployed on
      other hosts. The agents offload the centralized router for east-west (tenant-to-tenant)
      routing and floating IP network address translation.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
  <p>You can enable SNAT on a virtual router. For more information, see <xref href="jow1438192116883.xml"/></p>
  <p>To add a virtual router, see <xref href="jow1429629394435.xml"/>. To create interfaces, see <xref href="jow1429631834947.xml"/>.</p>
  <!-- "I wouldn't talk about Accelerated DVR until we do it" - Greg -->
  <!--  <p>An Accelerated DVR (to be made available in a later release) is implemented adjacent to the AVS
   switch on each host to provide DPDK-accelerated east-west andL3 forwarding. North-South L3
   Forwarding and SNAT may also be accelerated by implementing the centralized-portion of the router
   as a VM configured to use multiple dedicated cores, instead of sharing the single platform core
   with TiS and OpenStack Agents.</p> -->
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>
