<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333486758" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <!-- Modification History
   -->
    <title ixia_locid="1">Boot Sequence Considerations</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">During HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software installation, each host must boot from
        different devices at different times. In some cases, you may need to adjust the boot
        order.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
        <author ixia_locid="4">Pedro Sanchez</author>
        <author ixia_locid="5">Tom Towle</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="32">The first controller node must be booted initially from a removable
            storage device to install an operating system. The host then reboots from the hard
            drive.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="33">Each remaining host must be booted initially from the network using PXE
            to install an operating system. The host then reboots from the hard drive.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="6">To facilitate this process, ensure that the hard drive does not already
            contain a bootable operating system, and set the following boot order in the BIOS.</p>
        <ol id="ol_htt_5qg_fn">
            <li ixia_locid="19">
                <p ixia_locid="20">removable storage device (USB flash drive or DVD drive)</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="21">
                <p ixia_locid="22">hard drive</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="36" product="tis_standard">
                <p ixia_locid="38">network (PXE), over an interface connected to the internal
                    management network</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="37" product="tis_region">
                <p ixia_locid="39">network (PXE), over an interface connected
                    to the PXE boot network</p>
            </li>
        </ol>
        <p ixia_locid="31">For BIOS configuration details, refer to the OEM documentation supplied
            with the computing node.</p>
        <note id="note_N10061_N10029_N10001" ixia_locid="34">
            <p ixia_locid="35">If a host contains a bootable hard drive, either erase the drive
                beforehand, or ensure that the host is set to boot from the correct source for
                initial configuration. If necessary, you can change the boot device at boot time by
                pressing a dedicated key. For more information, refer to the OEM documentation for
                the compute node.</p>
        </note>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>