<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333745550" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">DiffServ-Based Priority Queuing and Scheduling</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Differentiated Services, or DiffServ, is a packet-based traffic
        management mechanism that allows end devices to specify an expected per-hop behavior (PHB)
        from upstream switches and routers when handling their traffic during overload conditions. </shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author></author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="8">DiffServ marking and architecture are IEEE specifications, IEEE RFC 2474 and RFC
            2475.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="4">Support for DiffServ is implemented on the AVS for all input and output
            ports, on all attached tenant networks. On each port, it uses eight queues associated
            with the CS0 to CS7 DiffServ class selectors, which are processed by a round-robin
            scheduler with weights of 1, 1, 2, 2, 4, 8, 16, and 32. Overflow traffic is tail-drop
            discarded on each queue. Guest applications in the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade cluster can set a
            Differentiated Services Code Point (DSCP) value in the Differentiated Service (DS) field
            of the IP header to mark the desired upstream PHB.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="7">On ingress, a packet being processed to be sent to the VM is directed to
            the appropriate DiffServ output queue. On overflow, that is, if the virtual machine
            cannot keep up with the incoming traffic rate, lower priority packets are discarded
            first.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="5">On egress, a packet sent from the VM to the AVS is first enqueued into the appropriate DiffServ
   input queue according to the specified DSCP value, the CS0 queue being the default. On overload,
   that is, if the AVS cannot keep up with the incoming traffic, lower priority packets are
   discarded first; in this case, you should consider re-engineering the AVS, possibly assigning it
   more processing cores. Once serviced by the DiffServ class scheduler, the packet is processed
   according to the QoS policy in place for the tenant network, as described in <xref href="jow1404333744498.xml" ixia_locid="6"/>. </p>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>
