<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333736207" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">Address Filtering on Virtual Interfaces</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The AVS on compute nodes can be configured to filter out packets based
        on source MAC address.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author></author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="4">MAC addresses for virtual network interfaces on virtual machines are dynamically allocated by
   the system. For most scenarios, the assigned MAC addresses are expected to be used on all
   outgoing packets from the virtual machine instances. However, there are scenarios where the
   source MAC address is not expected to match the original assignment, such as when a L2 switch is
   implemented internally on the virtual machine.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="5">By default, the AVS on compute nodes accepts any source MAC address on the attached virtual
   network interfaces. However, it can be configured to filter out all incoming packets with
   non-system-generated source MAC address, if required. When evaluating the use of the filtering
   capability, you must consider the following:</p>
        <ul id="ul_rzm_jtt_m4">
            <li ixia_locid="6">
                <p ixia_locid="7">Source MAC address filtering can be enabled and disabled by the administrator user only, not
     by tenants.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="8">
                <p ixia_locid="9">Filtering is enabled on a per-tenant basis only. Higher granularity, such as per-instance
     filtering, is not supported.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="10">
                <p ixia_locid="11">When enabled, source MAC address filtering applies to all new virtual interfaces created by
     the Neutron service. Address filtering is not active on virtual interfaces created before
     filtering is enabled.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p ixia_locid="12">Use the following command to enable source MAC address filtering:</p>
        <codeblock ixia_locid="13"><systemoutput ixia_locid="29">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput ixia_locid="15">neutron setting-update --tenant-id=&lt;TENANTID&gt; \
--mac-filtering={True|False}</userinput></codeblock>
        <p ixia_locid="16">Filtering can be enabled or disabled from the web management interface.
            As the administrator, select <uicontrol ixia_locid="17">Projects</uicontrol> from the
                <uicontrol ixia_locid="18">Identity</uicontrol> menu to display the <wintitle ixia_locid="19">Projects</wintitle> window. Then select the option <option ixia_locid="20">Edit Project</option> from the <option ixia_locid="21">More</option>
            drop-down menu of the desired tenant, as illustrated below.</p>
        <fig id="fig_N10067_N1001A_N10001" ixia_locid="22">
            <image href="jow1404333733225.image" id="image_urc_nzt_m4" ixia_locid="23" placement="inline" width="6in"/>
        </fig>
        <p ixia_locid="24">The <wintitle ixia_locid="25">Edit Project</wintitle> window is
            displayed. The filtering option is available from the tab <uicontrol ixia_locid="26">Settings</uicontrol>, as illustrated below.</p>
        <fig id="fig_N1007F_N1001A_N10001" ixia_locid="27">
            <image href="jow1404333734792.image" id="image_q2j_pzt_m4" ixia_locid="28" placement="inline" width="6in"/>
        </fig>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>