<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1429538642910" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title>Flavor Extra Specifications</title>
 <shortdesc>You can edit an existing flavor to include additional attributes using
   <term>extra specifications</term>.</shortdesc>
 <prolog><author/>
  <author/>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p>Extra specifications are key-value pairs you can add to an existing flavor to
   be included when the flavor is used with a new virtual machine. The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade <uicontrol>Extra Specs</uicontrol> tab for a flavor includes extensions specific to
   HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade.</p>
  <p>To access the extra specifications settings for a flavor, open the <wintitle>Flavors</wintitle> window and click the flavor name. For help accessing the
   Flavors window, see <xref href="jow1404333663095.xml"/>.</p>
  <fig id="fig_z2v_2lw_5p">
   <title>Flavor extra specs</title>
   <image href="jow1434398362447.image" id="image_yjr_prs_js">
    <alt>TiS Extra Specs localstorage default</alt>
   </image>
  </fig>
  <p>The <uicontrol>Extra Specs</uicontrol> tab lists extra
   specifications that have been added for the flavor. </p>
  <note id="note_N10060_N10024_N10001">
   <p>A <nameliteral>Storage Type</nameliteral> extra spec is added by default for all new flavors.
    To ensure that instantiated VMs use storage of a known type, do not delete this extra spec. For
    more information, see <xref href="jow1426181040008.xml"/>.</p>
  </note>
  <p>To modify an existing entry, use the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button. To remove a single entry, open the drop-down menu associated with the
   extra spec, and select <uicontrol>Delete extra spec</uicontrol> from the menu.
   You can also remove all extra specs at once using the <uicontrol>Delete extra
    specs</uicontrol> button.</p>
  <p>To add a new extra specification, click <uicontrol>Create</uicontrol>. This opens the <wintitle>Create Flavor Extra
    Spec</wintitle> window, as illustrated below:</p>
  <fig id="fig_wyg_ylw_5p">
   <title>Creating a flavor extra specification</title>
   <image href="psa1413822561872.image" id="image_a2g_h2x_5p" placement="inline">
    <alt>Create VM Flavor Extra Spec</alt>
   </image>
  </fig>
  <p>Use the <uicontrol>Extra Spec</uicontrol> drop-down list to
   add specifications. The following options are available:</p>
  <dl>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Custom Extra Spec</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Available for internal use only.
      <!-- Pedro nodes that you could use this to add documented extra specsd that are not supported from the GUI (specifically, Configuring the NUMA Node Allocations for a VM, for which you would add an extra spec with whatever name and supply as its value hw:numa_nodes=n). --></p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>VCPU Model</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>The CPU model to use with the virtual machine. If this extra spec is not
      added, then by default the QEMU processor is used. For more information, see <xref href="jow1429544114897.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Minimum Number of CPUs</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Sets the minimum number of virtual CPUs for the flavor. If this extra spec
      is not added, then by default the minimum is one. For more information, see <xref href="jow1417817540528.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Shared VCPU ID</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>The ID of a virtual CPU scheduled to run on a shared physical CPU in the
      compute host. If this extra spec is not added, then by default the VM does not use a shared
      CPU. For more information, see <xref href="jow1426618822854.xml"/> and <xref href="jow1426625051841.xml"/>.</p>
     <note id="note_N102CA_N102BE_N102B5_N101CC_N10154_N1001F_N10001">
      <p>To use this extra specification, you must also set the <nameliteral>CPU Policy</nameliteral> extra specification for the flavor to <option>Dedicated</option>. This enables the VM to run a single house-keeping
       virtual CPU on a shared physical core, while keeping all its high-performance virtual CPUs on
       dedicated physical cores.</p>
     </note>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>CPU Policy</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>The policy for assigning dedicated physical or logical CPU resources to the
      VM. If this extra spec is not added, then by default resources are drawn from a shared pool of
      cores. For more information, see <xref href="jow1429544935360.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry><dt><option>VCPU Scheduler Policy</option></dt><dd><p>Sets the scheduling priority for non-boot virtual CPUs. If this extra spec is not added, then by default <i>nice</i> priority 0 is assigned. For more information, see <xref href="jow1429547742880.xml"/>.</p>
     <note id="note_N1017D_N1016B_N10161_N100BC_N10024_N10001">
      <p>This extra spec is shown only for flavors with more than one CPU.</p>
     </note></dd></dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Number of NUMA Nodes</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Sets the number of virtual NUMA Nodes. If this extra spec is not added,
      then by default the memory and CPU resources for a flavor are assigned to a single virtual
      NUMA Node.  For more information, see <xref href="jow1425236666266.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>NUMA Node</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>The NUMA node to use when launching a virtual machine. If this extra spec
      is not added, then by default any available NUMA node is used, subject to other NUMA node
      settings. For more information, see <xref href="jow1425236723556.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Vswitch NUMA Affinity</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Specifies that a NUMA node with a vSwitch core is required or preferred
      when instantiating the VM. If this extra spec is not added, then by default any available NUMA
      node is used, subject to other NUMA node settings. For more information, see <xref href="jow1436210207074.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>PCI NUMA Affinity</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>For a VM configured to use an SR-IOV or PCI passthrough interface,
      specifies that a NUMA node with direct access to the physical interface is either required or
      preferred for instantiation. If this extra spec is not added, then by default a NUMA node with
      direct access is used. For more information, see <xref href="jow1436197980621.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Memory Page Size</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Sets the page size for VM memory. If this extra spec is not added, then by
      default small pages are used. For more information, see <xref href="jow1424723681500.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Storage Type</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Specifies whether to use local or remote ephemeral storage resources. This
      extra spec is added automatically, and is set for remote storage by default. For more
      information, see <xref href="jow1426181040008.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Guest Heartbeat</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Enables the Heartbeat API for use by guests on the VM. If this extra spec is
      not added, then by default this API is disabled. For more information, see <xref href="jow1429546712705.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Server Group Messaging</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p>Enables the VM to communicate with other VMs in the same server group using
      a messaging API. If this extra spec is not added, then by default this API is disabled. For
      more information, see <xref href="jow1432240580490.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Instance Auto Recovery</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <draft-comment author="rstone">US61157 adds</draft-comment>
     <p>Disables auto recovery of failed virtual machine instances. If this extra
      spec is not added, then the system will automatically recover failed virtual machine
      instances. For more information, see <xref href="rst1441899910150.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Live Migration Timeout</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <draft-comment author="rstone">US60539 adds</draft-comment>
     <p>Specifies the number of seconds to wait for a live migration to complete.
      If this extra spec is not added, then it defaults to 800 seconds.  For more information, see
       <xref href="jow1404333655771.xml"/> and <xref href="rst1441822551049.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>Live Migration Max Downtime</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p><draft-comment author="rstone">US60539
              added</draft-comment>Specifies the number of milliseconds of downtime to accept during
            live migrations. If this extra spec is not set, then it defaults to 500 milliseconds.
            For more information, see <xref href="rst1441988597710.xml"/>.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry>
    <dt><option>NIC Isolation</option></dt>
    <dd>
     <p><draft-comment author="rstone">US60525
       adds</draft-comment>Enables isolating a virtual machine instance's network interface cards
      from all other interfaces running on the host. If this extra spec is not set, then the
      instance's interfaces are not isolated. For more information see <xref href="rst1441912501217.xml"/>. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>
