<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="psa1428328539397" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Guest VLANs</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Use guest VLANs to segregate IP traffic from a single virtual Ethernet interface on a
  virtual machine into dedicated VLANs. Together with the capability to define multiple IP subnets
  on a single tenant network, guest VLANs facilitate the transitioning of existing guest
  applications to run on the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade virtualized network environment.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="33">Jim Owens</author>
  <author></author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="4">Guest VLANs are useful when guest applications rely on the capability to
   configure a single virtual Ethernet interface with multiple, probably overlapping, IP addresses.
   From the point of view of the guest, this is done by defining VLAN Ethernet interfaces, and
   associating one or more IP addresses to them. If implementing overlapping IP addresses, typically
   in support of VPN applications, the guest must use different VLAN IDs to separate traffic from
   different VPNs.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="5">For example. on a Linux guest, the virtual interfaces eth0.10:1, eth0.10:2, and
   eth0.20 refer to the same eth0 physical interface with two virtual interfaces on VLAN ID 10, and
   a single virtual interface on VLAN ID 20.  A common scenario in a VLAN application is to allocate
   distinct IP addresses from the same IP subnet to virtual interfaces on the same VLAN. In this
   example, eth0.10:1 and eth0.10:2 could be assigned distinct IP addresses from the subnet
   192.168.1.0/24, and eth0.20 an address from the subnet 192.168.2.0/24. In the case of a VPN
   application, overlapping IP addresses are allowed to exist on eth0.20 and either eth0.10:1 or
   eth0.10:2.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="6">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade supports these deployment scenarios with the help of guest VLANs
   which enable the transport of IP subnets traffic over VLAN-tagged Ethernet frames. To support the
   example above, a tenant user would define the following two IP subnets, both on the same tenant
   network, using guest VLAN IDs as follows:</p>
  <ul id="ul_jn2_rdw_pr">
   <li ixia_locid="7">
    <p ixia_locid="8">Subnet 192.168.1.0/24 with guest VLAN ID set to 10</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="9">
    <p ixia_locid="10">Subnet 192.168.2.0/24 with guest VLAN ID set to 20</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="11">The subnet-to-VLAN_ID mapping can be one-to-one, as in this example, or
   many-to-one. This means that tenant users can use a single VLAN ID of their choice to encapsulate
   traffic from one or more IP subnets.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="47">Alternately, tenant networks can be configured to use VLAN Transparent mode, in
   which VLAN tagged guest packets are encapsulated within a provider network segment without
   removing or modifying the guest VLAN tag. For more information, see <xref href="rst1442341292102.xml" ixia_locid="48"/>. </p>
  <section id="section_N10044_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="12">
   <title ixia_locid="13">Creating Guest VLANs</title>
   <p ixia_locid="14">Tenant users can define a guest VLAN when they add a new IP subnet to a tenant
    network they are creating, or to an existing one. See the <cite ixia_locid="15">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade
     Reference Deployment Scenarios</cite> for examples of how to create tenant networks.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="16">From the web management interface you add the VLAN ID of the guest VLAN to the
     <uicontrol ixia_locid="17">Subnet Detail</uicontrol> tab of the <wintitle ixia_locid="18">Create Subnet</wintitle> window. In the following example a guest VLAN with ID of 10 will be
    created when the subnet is added.</p>
   <fig id="fig_yts_jrw_pr" ixia_locid="19">
    <title ixia_locid="20">Creating a guest VLAN</title>
    <image href="psa1428335880496.image" id="image_upj_qrw_pr" ixia_locid="21">
     <alt ixia_locid="22">Creating a guest VLAN</alt>
    </image>
   </fig>
   <p ixia_locid="23">From the command line interface, a guest VLAN can be defined using the <option ixia_locid="24">--vlan-id</option> option when creating a new subnet, as illustrated below:</p>
   <codeblock ixia_locid="25"><systemoutput ixia_locid="26">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput ixia_locid="27">neutron subnet-create --tenant-id ${tenant_UUID} \
--name my-new-subnet --vlan-id 10</userinput></codeblock>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N10086_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="28">
   <title ixia_locid="29">Guest VLAN Implementation</title>
   <p ixia_locid="30">Guest VLANs are implemented using available segmentation ranges from suitable provider
    networks, just as it is done when new tenant networks are created. Therefore all network design
    considerations regarding the configuration of L2 switches and the Neutron allocation strategy,
    described in <xref href="jow1404333739174.xml" ixia_locid="31"/>, must be taken into consideration.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="32">Additionally, note that the AVS will silently discard incoming VLAN-tagged VM traffic with
    unknown VLAN IDs, that is, with VLAN IDs not defined as guest VLANs on the particular tenant
    network.</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>