<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="psa1420762251633" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title id="Preface_TiS_Admin_Guide" ixia_locid="1"/> 
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2"/>
 <prolog>
  <author></author>
  <author ixia_locid="4">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="5">The HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade Administration Guide is one of several documents released with the Wind
   River HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade product line. They include:</p>
  <ul id="ul_fsm_fgj_rq">
   <li ixia_locid="6">
    <p ixia_locid="7">Quick Start Guide</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="8">
    <p ixia_locid="9">Software Installation Guide</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="10">
    <p ixia_locid="11">Reference Deployment Scenarios</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="12">
    <p ixia_locid="13">System Engineering Guidelines</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="14">
    <p ixia_locid="15">Release Notes</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="16">The Administration Guide is addressed to HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade administrators responsible for the
   following areas:</p>
  <ul id="ul_t5s_jgj_rq">
   <li ixia_locid="17">
    <p ixia_locid="18">Creating and maintaining resources used by end users (tenants), such as virtual machines,
     storage pools, network objects, and access credentials.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="19">
    <p ixia_locid="20">Operating and maintaining components of the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade product, such as clusters, nodes,
     system software, licensing files, and backup and restore facilities.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="21">Familiarity with these technologies is assumed:</p>
  <ul id="ul_ysy_mgj_rq">
   <li ixia_locid="22">
    <p ixia_locid="23">The OpenStack cloud computing service on which HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade is built. This guide provides
     information specific to HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade. Detailed discussion of OpenStack components is outside
     its scope. The OpenStack documentation at http://docs.openstack.org can be used as a
     complement.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="24">
    <p ixia_locid="25">Networking communication standards and protocols, required to manage the
     physical and virtual networks deployed within OpenStack and the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade product.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="26">
    <p ixia_locid="27">Basic computing technology, including familiarity with BIOS settings, network interfaces, and
     drive configurations, required to manage the physical nodes in the cluster.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="28">
    <p ixia_locid="29">The Linux operating system, including its file system, environment, and associated command
     line operations.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="30"><b ixia_locid="31">Before installing the software, you are strongly encouraged to read and understand the
    Overview and Planning chapters in this guide.</b> These chapters provide a mandatory
   introduction to the concepts and considerations required for a smooth and successful
   installation.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="32">For the most part, the Administration Guide assumes that the HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade software is
   already installed, and that you can log in to the web administration interface and the node
   consoles.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>